<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>technology, security, watch and book reviews</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 15:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 15:56:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>TCP/IP - Internet Protocol Suite</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-internet-protocol-suite-is-commonly-known-as-tcpip-because-of-the-central-protocols-in-the-suite-transmission-control-protocol-tcp-and-internet-protocol-ip&quot;&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite is commonly known as TCP/IP because of the central protocols in the suite: Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and Internet Protocol (IP).&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;tcpip-is-the-foundation-of-all-global-internet-communication-and-dominates-networks-around-the-world-the-technical-standards-are-maintained-by-the-internet-engineering-task-force-ietf&quot;&gt;TCP/IP is the foundation of all global internet communication and dominates networks around the world. The technical standards are maintained by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF).&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite predates the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/osi-model/&quot;&gt;OSI Reference Model&lt;/a&gt; which is a more comprehensive framework for general networking systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP originates from research conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DARPA&quot;&gt;DARPA&lt;/a&gt; in the 1960s. The design included a fundamental change to existing protocols as the network would only provide functions to efficiently transmitting and routing traffic between end nodes and that all other intelligence would be located at the edge of the network. This design is known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/End-to-end_principle&quot;&gt;end-to-end principle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;computer racks&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the US Department of Defense declared TCP/IP as the standard for all computer networking and Universities followed in the same year. The promotion of the protocol by large corporations like IBM and DEC led to increasing commercial use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dominance of TCP/IP as the standard for network communication was cemented when the University of California, Berkeley placed the TCP/IP code developed for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSD_UNIX&quot;&gt;BSD UNIX&lt;/a&gt; into the public domain in 1989. More and more vendors included the code in commercial software releases and more people joined Internet protocol suite based networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layers-of-tcpip&quot;&gt;Layers of TCP/IP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defining specification of the suite is found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1122&quot;&gt;RFC 1122&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1123&quot;&gt;RFC 1123&lt;/a&gt;. A four-layer model is outlined as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this layer applications or processes, create user data and communicate this data to other applications on the same host or a remote one. The applications make use of the services provided by the underlying lower layers, especially the transport layer which provides reliable or unreliable communication protocols to other processes. Application architecture is characterized by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Client%E2%80%93server_model&quot;&gt;client-server model&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer computing&lt;/a&gt;. This is the layer in which all application protocols, such as SMTP, FTP, SSH, HTTPS, operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transport layer performs host-to-host communication on local or remote networks. The two primary protocols in this layer are the simplex connectionless UDP or User Datagram Protocol and the full-duplex connection-oriented TCP or Transmission Control Protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data exchange between two systems on this layer is performed via ports. Both TCP and UDP support 65536 ports which are just an address number that both ends of the communication link agree to use when transferring data on the transport layer. A single IP address can support multiple simultaneous communications by utilizing multiple ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at TCP which is connection-oriented and performs a handshake process to establish a communication session. The three-way-handshake is a prerequisite for data transmission between server and client and goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client sends a &lt;strong&gt;SYN&lt;/strong&gt; (synchronize) flagged packet to the server. The server responds with a &lt;strong&gt;SYN/ACK&lt;/strong&gt; (synchronize and acknowledge) flagged packet back to the client. The client sends an &lt;strong&gt;ACK&lt;/strong&gt; (acknowledge) flagged packet back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two methods to disconnect a TCP session once a communication session is complete. The most common one is to use a &lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; (finish) flagged packet which both sides of the communication have to send once all data is transmitted. The other side has to reply with an &lt;strong&gt;ACK&lt;/strong&gt; flagged packet. It takes 4 packets to gracefully shut down a TCP session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative disconnect method is to send a &lt;strong&gt;RST&lt;/strong&gt; (reset) flagged packet, this causes an abrupt and immediate termination of the session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UDP, the other player in the transport layer, is a connectionless best-effort protocol and offers no error detection and correction. It also doesn’t require a pre-established session and is therefore considered unreliable. With its low overhead, it can transmit data quickly but should only be used for non-essential data delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a city by night&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol or IP operates on the Network layer of the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/osi-model/&quot;&gt;OSI Model&lt;/a&gt;. IP provides route addressing for data packets and it is this route addressing that makes TCP/IP the foundation of global internet communications because it provides a way to identify and prescribe transmission paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol is connectionless and acts as an unreliable datagram service. It doesn’t guarantee that packets are delivered in the right order or tht they are delivered at all. Only when TCP and IP work together a reliable and controlled communication session is established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv4&quot;&gt;IPv4&lt;/a&gt; is the most widely used version of the Internet Protocol. A new version known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6_address&quot;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; is being adopted for private and public network use and offers new features and new challenges for Administrators and Security Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICMP or Internet Control Message Protocol is also working on the Internet layer and provides a way to determine the health of a network or a specific link. Commands like ping, traceroute and other network management tools utilize ICMP to send echo packets to remote hosts. With ICMP it is possible to determine whether a remote system is online, how fast it responds and if intermediary systems support the communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many attacks exploited the features of ICMP in forms of denial-of-service (DoS) attacks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ping_flood&quot;&gt;ping floods&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smurf_attack&quot;&gt;smurf attacks&lt;/a&gt;. This has affected the way how networks handle ICMP today, resulting in many limiting the use of ICMP or the throughput rate of this protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Group Management Protocol or IGMP allows systems to support multicasting in an IPv4 network. Multicast management on IPv6 networks is handled by Multicast Listener Discovery (MLD). Both protocols support the transmission of data to multiple specific recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link layer defines the networking methods within the scope of the local network link on which hosts communicate. This layer includes the protocols used to describe the local network topology and the interfaces needed for the transmission of Internet layer datagrams to next-neighbor hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARP or Address Resolution Protocol is enabling the interoperability of logical and physical addressing of interfaces. It resolves IP addresses into Medica Access Control (MAC) addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic on a network is directed from its source to its destination using MAC addresses. ARP uses broadcasting and caching to perform the intended purpose. If the cache doesn’t contain the necessary information, an ARP request is broadcasted into the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP follows principles that helped the model to adapt to new requirements and stay meaningful. Robustness, Adaptability and Continuous Evolution are core values mentioned in the defining RFCs of the Internet Protocol Suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But TCP/IP vulnerabilities are numerous and range from improperly implemented stacks in operating systems to buffer overflows, denial-of-service or spoofing attacks. It is also subject to passive attacks via monitoring traffic patterns or sniffing the content of communication by man-in-the-middle attacks. Deep knowledge of TCP/IP is a must for any security professional to mitigate the risk of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite is the underlying fabric of the internet and I could only provide a quick overview in this posting. Understanding the basics of networking should be in the interests of any Internet user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/tcp-ip-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/tcp-ip-model/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OSI Model - Open Systems Interconnection</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-properly-implement-secure-design-principles-in-network-architectures-it-is-important-to-fully-understand-all-of-the-technologies-involved-in-computer-communications-from-software-and-hardware-to-encryption-and-beyond-there-are-many-standards-to-know-and-procedures-to-follow-the-osi-model-has-become-a-common-reference-against-which-all-protocols-can-be-compared&quot;&gt;To properly implement secure design principles in network architectures, it is important to fully understand all of the technologies involved in computer communications. From software and hardware to encryption and beyond, there are many standards to know and procedures to follow. The OSI model has become a common reference against which all protocols can be compared.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual OSI protocol was developed to establish a common communication structure for all computer systems but was never widely adopted. Instead, the theory behind the protocol serves nowadays as a theoretical model for how protocols should function in an ideal world on ideal hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) model is a guiding principle in networking and related protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication between computers and over networks is made possible by protocols which are simply a set of rules and restrictions that define how data is transmitted over a network medium (whether that connection is electrons over copper, photons over fiber, or radio signals through the air).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;light shining from fiber cables&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-layers-of-the-model&quot;&gt;The Layers of the Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model partitions a communication system into seven abstraction layers. A layer serves the layer above it and is served by the layer below it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the functions and responsibilities of each layer of the OSI Model is essential to understand how network communications function, how attacks work, and how to security can be implemented to protect network communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_table_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-7-application&quot;&gt;Layer 7: Application&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Application layer allows applications to communicate with the protocol stack. It ensures that sufficient resources are available to support the requested communication and is responsible for interfacing user applications, network services, or the operating system with the protocol stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is not located in this layer but rather the protocols and services required for it to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-6-presentation&quot;&gt;Layer 6: Presentation&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 6 imposes common or standardized structure and formatting rules onto the data from the application layer. It acts as an interface between applications and the network and therefore allows various applications to interact over a network. It does so by ensuring that the data formats are supported by both systems. Most data and file formats operate within this layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formats include support for images, video, sound, digital rights, documents, emails, or text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-5-session&quot;&gt;Layer 5: Session&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Session layer is establishing, maintaining, and terminating communication sessions between two computers. It manages dialogue discipline and control (simplex (one-way), half-duplex (two-way one-directional), full-duplex (two-way bi-directional)), establishes checkpoints for recovery, and can retransmit PDUs that have failed to the Transport layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-4-transport&quot;&gt;Layer 4: Transport&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This layer is responsible for managing the integrity of a connection and controlling the session. It accepts a PDU (Protocol Data Unit) from the Session layer and converts into segments. The Transport layer defines the rules of a session, how much data a segment can contain, how to verify the segment integrity, and how to determine if data has been lost. Rules are established through a handshake process (SYNC/ACK three-way handshake for TCP/IP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 4 establishes a logical connection between two devices and provides end-to-end transport services for data delivery. Mechanisms in this layer include sequencing, segmentation, error checking, controlling the data flow, error correction, multiplexing, and optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-3-network&quot;&gt;Layer 3: Network&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network layer is responsible for adding routing and addressing information to the data. It accepts the segments from the Transport layer and adds information to it to create a packet. The packer includes the source and destination IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 3 is responsible for providing routing and delivery information, but it’s not responsible for verifying guaranteed delivery. It also manages error detection and traffic control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routers are an example of network hardware devices functioning on this layer. Routers can determine the best logical path for transmission of packets based on speed, hops, preferences or priority. They use the destination IP address to guide the transmission of packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Non-IP Protocols are protocols that serve as an alternative to IP at the OSI Network layer. With the dominance of TCP/IP, non-IP protocols have become limited to special-purpose networks. Recognizable non-IP protocols are AppleTalk, NetBEUI or IPX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-2-data-link&quot;&gt;Layer 2: Data Link&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Link layer is formatting the packet from the Network layer into the proper format for transmission. The proper format is determined by the hardware and network technology. Ethernet remains a common Data Link layer technology in modern networks. Within the Data Link layer resides the protocol that converts the packet into a properly formated frame. Once the frame is formatted, it’s sent to the Physical layer for transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the processing performed on this layer includes adding the hardware source and destination address to the frame. This address is the Media Access Control (MAC) address. Network hardware functioning on layer 2 are switches and bridges. Switches support MAC-based traffic routing and receive a frame on one port and sent it out to another port based on the destination MAC address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-1-physical&quot;&gt;Layer 1: Physical&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Physical layer is responsible for receiving bits from the physical connection medium and converting them into a frame to be used by the Data Link layer. It also works the other way around by converting the frame into bits for transmission over the physical medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This layer contains the device drivers that tell the protocol how to employ the hardware for transmission and reception of bits. Located in this layer are electrical specifications, interface standards, and protocols. Layer 1 controls throughput rates, manages line noise and medium access, handles synchronization and also determines whether to use digital or analog signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware devices that function at this layer are network interface cards (NIC), hubs or repeaters. These devices perform hardware-based signal operations. One example is a network hub that is sending a signal from one connection port to all other ports. A network repeater is amplifying a signal to support greater transmission distances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;layers of pancakes&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encapsulation-and-de-encapsulation&quot;&gt;Encapsulation and De-encapsulation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protocols based on the OSI Model utilize a mechanism called encapsulation. It is the addition of a header, and possibly a footer, to the data received by each layer from the layer above before it is handed over to the layer below. As a message traverses the layers, it is enriched with additional data. The previous layers header and payload becomes the payload of the current layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encapsulation occurs as data moves down through the OSI Model layers from Application to Physical. When data moves up through the layers from Physical to Application the action occurring is known as de-encapsulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; The Application layer creates the message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; The Application layer passes the message to the Presentation layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; The Presentation layer encapsulates the message by adding layer-specific information to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; The process continues as the original message travels down the layers. Each layer adds additional information to the message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; The message reaches the Physical layer and is converted into electrical impulses that represent bits and is transmitted over the physical connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; The receiving computer captures the bits from the physical medium and re-creates the message in the Physical layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; The Physical layer converts the message from bits into a Data Link frame and sends the message up to the Data Link layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; The Data Link layer strips the layer-specific information from the message and sends it up to the Network layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; The process of de-encapsulation is performed on each layer until the message reaches the Application layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; On the Application layer, the data is extracted from the message and is sent to the intended software recipient&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information added and removed by each layer contains instructions, checksums, and  can only be understood by the peer layer that added or created the information. This creates the logical channel that enables the peer layer on different computers to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tcpip-and-osi-comparison&quot;&gt;TCP/IP and OSI comparison&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TCP/IP or DARPA Model was developed before the OSI Model. The designers of the OSI Reference Model made sure that both fit together because TCP/IP was already an established deployment in networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_table_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP is the most widely used protocol stack with dozens of individual protocols. It is platform-independent and based on open standards and can be found in every available modern operating system. The drawbacks of TCP/IP are its significant consumption of resources and the lack of security by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory behind the OSI model is abstract at first but it serves as a model to understand and compare protocols. It also helps vendors and developers to create digital communication products that interoperate. Lastly, the structure of the OSI model helps to frame discussions of protocols and contrast various technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/osi-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/osi-model/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Holiday Gift Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-started-this-blog-in-2019-and-the-positive-feedback-from-you-readers-is-amazing-and-motivates-me-to-continue-writing-thank-you-i-promise-that-2020-will-bring-more-articles-about-security-books-watches-and-other-topics-that-spark-my-interest&quot;&gt;I started this blog in 2019 and the positive feedback from you readers is amazing and motivates me to continue writing. Thank you! I promise that 2020 will bring more articles about security, books, watches and other topics that spark my interest.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compiling this list of gift ideas was fun to do and the items are either things I already own or things I want. Let’s jump right in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gift_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a gift&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whiskey&quot;&gt;Whiskey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first item from my list is a good bottle of Japanese Whiskey. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37zKvqr&quot;&gt;Nikka From The Barrel&lt;/a&gt; is a blended whiskey created to deliver full flavors and the iconic bottle is designed to reflect “a small block of whiskey” – embodying the rich, strong taste of the whiskey within. Masataka Taketsuru the founder of Nikka is also the ancestor of Japanese whiskey. The Nikka distillery won many prestigious international awards and has earned a reputation for quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nikka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a bottle of nikka&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer a traditional Single Malt Scotch, then I’d recommend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2pXgFve&quot;&gt;Laphroaig 10 y/o&lt;/a&gt;. Made in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine Whiskey requires consumption from nice glasses. Probably the most famous one is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OERDZX&quot;&gt;Glencairn Whiskey Glass&lt;/a&gt;. It is built so your hands won’t warm the Whiskey. A classic &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/35r5KsO&quot;&gt;Whiskey Tumbler&lt;/a&gt; is a solid alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey connoisseurs won’t allow ice cubes to water down their favorite drink. A nice set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/34gGuVV&quot;&gt;Whiskey Stones&lt;/a&gt; will make any aficionado happy and is my third item on this gift list. It’s by the way a centuries’ old Scandinavian tradition to use cold stones to cool liquids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smoking-section&quot;&gt;Smoking Section&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next item in the gift guide is something I tend to enjoy myself after a hard day of security work. A good cigar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/montecristo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a box of Montecristo Cigars&quot; style=&quot;float: left;width:60%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation to people getting into the hobby is to try different brands and find their favorite taste. But a box of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cigarworld.de/en/zigarren/cuba/regulares/montecristo-01007&quot;&gt;Montecristo Cigars&lt;/a&gt; will satisfy the regular as much as the occasional smoker of fine Cubans. Their  strength is medium; in fact, it has become the standard by which all other Havanas are now judged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize to my readers from the United States but I think there is still a problem with importing Cuban goods to the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fine crystal &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KSg19x&quot;&gt;ashtray&lt;/a&gt; and a nice cigar &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DkcNHv&quot;&gt;cutter&lt;/a&gt; go well with a box of cigars as a present and round off the list in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;library&quot;&gt;Library&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter is something more universal and will also benefit people with a more healthy lifestyle. The holiday season is in the end also a good time to pick up a book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thewilliambrownproject.com/&quot;&gt;“WM Brown Magazine”&lt;/a&gt;, founded by style editor, explorer, filmmaker, and New Yorker Matt Hranek starts my recommendations in this category. WM Brown magazine is curated for the gentleman who seeks an off-the-beaten-track experience, in all aspects of life. The well-written articles are accompanied by amazing photography. The stories are about such things as food, fashion, watches, and yes.. even vintage whiskey flasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wmbrown.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a box of Montecristo Cigars&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width:50%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt also wrote a fantastic book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33iHGXA&quot;&gt;“A Man &amp;amp; His Watch”&lt;/a&gt;. While the watches in the book are interesting for sure, it’s the stories of people that make this a must-have for any watch collector. It’s a wonderful collection of stories and images representing a diverse and fascinating group of horological devotees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great book about watches is &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/35BENTn&quot;&gt;“The Watch – Thoroughly Revisited”&lt;/a&gt;. It is not only a feast for the eyes but both a comprehensive and holistic resources in terms of horology that will appeal to any aficionado. It goes into great detail about a microcosm that has never been more popular than in the age of instagraming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough of watches, the next book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Db1KAF&quot;&gt;“How to Measure Anything in Cybersecurity Risk”&lt;/a&gt; is about security or better about risk management and governance and reads like an education in quantitative modeling and how to apply the methodology to cybersecurity. It truly challenges the current common practices of opinion-based risk frameworks. This is a must-have for anyone who has to manage and communicate risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense in depth is not only a military strategy but also helps in building a robust security posture. The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OpYo30&quot;&gt;“Zero Trust Networks: Building Secure Systems in Untrusted Networks”&lt;/a&gt; explains that perimeter defenses guarding your network aren’t as secure as you might think. The book introduces you to the zero trust model, a method that treats all hosts as if they’re internet-facing, and considers the entire network to be compromised and hostile. Strong authentication, authorization, and encryption throughout, while providing compartmentalized access and better operational agility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last book recommendation is a classic science-fiction book. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XN91Qz&quot;&gt;“Neuromancer”&lt;/a&gt; surely sets the stage for many ideas, books, video games, and movies that followed. If your loved one is into tech-noire, corporate dominance, virtual reality, you might just as well have found the perfect present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creation&quot;&gt;Creation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great way to spend the holidays is to build something. And LEGO has something amazing in-store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/landi.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the lego landrover&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 70%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have heard that Land Rover will launch a new version of their vintage cult Defender model in 2020. During the holiday season, you can already start building your Defender with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/34kKTqL&quot;&gt;LEGO Technic Land Rover Defender&lt;/a&gt;. The set has over 2500 pieces and includes a 4-speed sequential gearbox, All Wheel Drive with 3 differentials, independent suspension on both axles, a detailed in-line 6-cylinder engine and a working winch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next item on my list is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DdeXJ5&quot;&gt;Canon EOS M50&lt;/a&gt;. It is an entry-level mirrorless camera that features an electronic viewfinder, fully articulating touchscreen and a 24MP APS-C sensor. It has Canon’s DIGIC 8 processor and offers 4K/24p video capture as well as Wi-Fi, Bluetooth and, NFC. The Camera also features Canons Dual Pixel Auto Focus, which is considered the best in the industry. As a perfect first lense, I recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OiVNrC&quot;&gt;Canon EF-M 22m F2 Pancake Lens&lt;/a&gt; which gives that nice background blur and does great in portraits, landscapes, low-light, and macro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/22m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a JLC Reverso showing some nice background blur&quot; style=&quot;margin: 15px 15px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to finish my holiday gift guide with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2QNTi2e&quot;&gt;Yubikey&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the perfect present for anyone who enjoys a secure authentication method. The keys support OTP and U2F and come in different sizes and with all major connectors. I recently wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/universal-2nd-factor/&quot;&gt;article about U2F&lt;/a&gt; and its advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my guide and all that’s left for me is to wish my readers a relaxed end of the year and a good time with your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/holiday-gift-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/holiday-gift-guide/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>book</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>U2F - Universal 2nd Factor Authentication</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-universal-2nd-factor-is-one-of-the-most-secure-authentication-methods-currently-available-its-advantages-are-based-on-hardware-isolation-and-modern-cryptography&quot;&gt;The “Universal 2nd Factor” is one of the most secure authentication methods currently available. Its advantages are based on hardware isolation and modern cryptography.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F is an open standard that improves and simplifies traditional two-factor authentication. It is utilizing a Universal Serial Bus (USB) or near-field communication (NFC) device to achieve secure authentication and was initially developed by Google and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/&quot;&gt;Yubico&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/yubikey_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;otp&quot;&gt;OTP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_password&quot;&gt;One-time passwords&lt;/a&gt; (OTP) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_algorithm&quot;&gt;time-based one-time passwords&lt;/a&gt; (TOTP) provide a relatively secure second factor to millions of users. The popularity and good propagation are related to the simplicity of the concept. But there are shortcomings to this method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is 2FA OTP? In addition to a static user name/password credential, a user adds another authentication factor - one that is dynamically generated. By definition, this OTP credential is only valid for one login before it becomes obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP technology is compatible with all major platforms (desktop, laptop, mobile) and even legacy environments. It is the most popular choice among second-factor protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-time credentials are delivered in different ways, usually via a physical object, such as a mobile phone (using SMS or an app), a token with an LCD-display, or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2qrTNEa&quot;&gt;YubiKey&lt;/a&gt;. Concrete OTP algorithms vary greatly but they have one thing in common: a shared secret between client and server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TOTP implementations, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Authenticator&quot;&gt;Google Authenticator&lt;/a&gt;, require time-synchronization and a shared secret between the authentication server and the device providing the password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second-factor one-time passwords offer protection against password replay but it’s not designed to counter a &lt;em&gt;man-in-the-middle&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt; attack. The shared secret between client and server is the main weakness of OTP and TOTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A theoretical attack is quite simple: token codes or shared secrets can get intercepted during authentication or stolen during the initialization of OTP. This is significant since it is the principal threat most users believe they are solving with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/totp.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a totp login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;u2f&quot;&gt;U2F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F improves on OTP vulnerabilities such as &lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;man-in-the-middle attacks&lt;/em&gt; by implementing a real-time challenge-response scheme with &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key/&quot;&gt;public-key encryption&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/&quot;&gt;digital signatures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a user registers a U2F device with an online service, a public/private key pair is generated on the client and the public key is shared with the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After registration, when the user attempts to log in, the service provider sends a challenge to the client. The client compiles at least the information about the source of the challenge into the response and signs it with the private key before sending it back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/u2f.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a u2f login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server can detect an abnormality in the response (since it is issuing the challenge) and deny the transaction if a rogue site or middle-man manipulates the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F is resistant to phishing by design too. For instance, the user cannot be tricked into pressing the key and authenticate with a “fake” web page since the authentication origin is part of the process and the communication between the device and the web browser. A malicious person cannot ask for your “U2F codes” because there are no codes in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays most people use biometrics-based methods for authentication on personal mobile devices to unlock them. Fingerprint and facial recognition have been around for a while now but they’re not exactly foolproof. It’s possible to trick fingerprint sensors and basic facial recognition systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/yubikey_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a totp login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most consumer OTP solutions are depending on mobile phones as the second factor, it opens up the question of future dependability of this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F devices, on the other hand, will become cheaper and more common to be accepted by service providers. I predict a future of adaptive security with many potential factors for authentication. Shared secret knowledge, physical ownership of a secure device, location, and behavior are all factors, that if combined, will convince machines that we are who we say we are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/universal-2nd-factor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/universal-2nd-factor/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight - Ref. 79030N</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-black-bay-fifty-eight-was-introduced-at-baselworld-2018-it-is-an-anniversary-model-to-commemorate-60-years-of-the-tudor-submariner-which-was-released-in-1958&quot;&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight was introduced at Baselworld 2018. It is an anniversary-model to commemorate 60 years of the Tudor Submariner which was released in 1958.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this watch is to go back to the original Big Crown models and create a vintage-inspired modern take on the Submariner-like dive watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tudor-submariner-heritage&quot;&gt;Tudor Submariner Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tudor Oyster Prince Submariner ‘Big Crown’ reference 7924 used many parts from Rolex Submariners in those days. The crown and bracelet carried for exampled Rolex markings. The watch was water-resistant up to 200m (600 feet) and featured a large screw-down crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same year, the reference 7925 was released with a depth rating of 100m (300 feet) and the distinctive red triangle at the zero point of the diving bezel. The Marine nationale francaise (MN), the US Navy (USN) and other military organizations throughout the world equipped their elite personnel with the Tudor Sub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watches delivered to these military entities were neither custom-designed nor specially developed. They were just references listed in the Tudor cataloge. Their only distinction was an engraving on the screw-down case back. The Marine nationale francaise watches, for example, bear the initials M.N. accompanied by the last two digits of the year in which they were delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples surviving to this day are rarely in perfect condition since they were used in extremely harsh conditions. The relative rarity of these watches and their respective stories make them a highly prized collectors item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downsizing-the-original-black-bay&quot;&gt;Downsizing the original Black Bay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the new Tudor Black Bay 58 looks just like another Black Bay, a Submariner-like dive watch with vintage inspiration. But the watch is an evolution and at the same time a return to the original dimensions of the Tudor Submariner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A modern Tudor Black Bay 58 vs. a vintage Tudor Submariner&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alignment with the original Big Crown models – mainly the Tudor Submariner 7924 and 7925 means the 58 is a smaller and slimmer version of the bulky Black Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 58 is 39mm in diameter. While the original ref. 7924 was even smaller at 37mm, the effort taken by Tudor to reduce the case size from the original Black Bay is a nod to watch enthusiasts who have been asking for smaller watches for years. The lug width has also been reduced to 20mm, to keep the proportions balanced. The case was condensed in height to now only 11.9mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the 58 ist a well-proportioned watch and sits nicely on the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowflakes-on-a-guilt-dial&quot;&gt;Snowflakes on a guilt dial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a modern interpretation of a classic, the Fifty-Eight has golden writing and minuteries. Also, a one-directional rotating bezel with gold lettering, classic with aluminum inlay and a red triangular marking at 12 adorns the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tudor went with golden snowflake hands which is a deviation from the original Submariner but it works surprisingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BB58 comes with the Tudor in-house MT5402 movement which is COSC certified. It has a power reserve of a whopping 70 hours.
This means one can easily leave the watch on the nightstand over the weekend and pick it up on Monday without having to adjust the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;specifications&quot;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight Ref. 79030N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Calibre MT5402 (COSC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Stainless Steel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Crystal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lug Width:&lt;/strong&gt; 20mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diameter/Height:&lt;/strong&gt; 39 mm/11.9 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six years after the first Black Bay and 60 years after the first Big Crown Submariner, Tudor impressively shows how to use past models to create an equally modern and historically true watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight is a good looking dive watch and comes at a fair price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>tudor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Social Credit Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;nosedive-is-a-episode-in-the-british-science-fiction-series-black-mirror-it-examines-the-idea-of-a-fictional-society-where-people-can-rate-each-other-from-one-to-five-stars-for-every-interaction-they-have-with-each-other-the-resulting-score-has-an-impact-on-the-social-and-economic-status-of-the-individual&quot;&gt;“Nosedive” is a episode in the British science fiction series &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Mirror&quot;&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/a&gt;. It examines the idea of a fictional society where people can rate each other from one to five stars for every interaction they have with each other. The resulting score has an impact on the social and economic status of the individual.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story follows Lacie, who is a young woman overly obsessed with her ratings; she finds an opportunity to improve her ratings greatly and move into a more luxurious residence after being chosen by her popular childhood friend as the maid of honour for her wedding. Her obsession leads to several mishaps on her journey to the wedding that culminate in a rapid reduction in her ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many critics noted the similarity of the episode to real-world Social Credit Systems. Indeed we already live in a world where the judgment of people is being replaced by numbers. Algorithms calculate the value of a human being and create digitally transparent people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a wall of CCTV&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nudge-theory&quot;&gt;Nudge Theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Credit Systems belong to a behavioral science concept called Nudge Theory. It proposes positive reinforcement and indirect suggestions as a way to influence the behavior and decision making of groups or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nudging contrasts with other ways to achieve compliance, such as education, legislation or enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utilization of “nudging” has been widely criticized for diminishing autonomy, threatening dignity, and violating liberties. Some call it psychological manipulative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese system uses a combination of mass surveillance and big data to score citizens. It is currently voluntary but will be made mandatory by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final stage, every citizen and company will be ranked whether they like it or not. The system will manage the punishments and rewards of citizens based on their economic and personal behavior.
The exact methodology for the rating is a secret but examples of infrations include bad driving, smoking in non-smoking areas, or posting fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punishments include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flight ban&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exclusion from schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slow internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;public display of blacklisted individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inside of a chinese airport&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2018, 5.5 million high-speed rail trips and 17.5 million flights had been denied to prospective travelers who were on a Chinese social scoring blacklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;western-world&quot;&gt;Western World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germany has its own social scoring system. The universal credit rating system known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schufa&quot;&gt;Schufa&lt;/a&gt; is a private company that assesses the creditworthiness of the majority of the German citizens and that of over 5 million companies in the country. Factors like living in a low-income neighborhood (geo-scoring) can lower the Schufa score. There is mounting criticism in Germany of what some view as a lack of transparency in establishing Schufa scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schufa has also been criticized for being a privately controlled central database that provides personality profiles for individuals. Having a bad score in the credit rating system will prevent people from getting a loan or renting an apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparable credit systems are common in most western democracies. The US counterpart to Schufa is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FICO&quot;&gt;FICO&lt;/a&gt; and the UK has &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experian&quot;&gt;Experian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of societal “privileges” related to transportation, accommodations, communications, and the rates we pay for services (like insurance) are controlled by algorithms and our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a critical phase of technological development and we need to discuss our values. Private companies will keep scoring people in areas like finance, criminality, rental housing, or mail-order businesses. It works like a charm and some citizens are even welcoming the ideal of “digitally transparent” people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you have something that you don’t want anyone to know, maybe you shouldn’t be doing it in the first place -Eric Schmidt, Google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s only a question of time until government institutions will pull all the information from different databases together and come up with a social score for each citizen. Arguments will be made for it improving the security of people and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we want to live in a world as predicted in the Black Mirror episode? Our societies have to be made aware of what algorithms really can, and cannot, do. Education is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-open-web-application-security-project-owasp-was-founded-in-2001-and-is-a-community-that-produces-freely-available-documentation-tools-articles-and-methodologies-in-the-field-of-security-and-risk-the-owasp-top-10-application-security-risk-list-was-first-published-in-2003-and-is-probably-the-closest-that-the-development-community-has-ever-come-to-a-set-of-rules-on-how-to-keep-products-secure&quot;&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;OWASP&lt;/a&gt;) was founded in 2001 and is a community that produces freely-available documentation, tools, articles, and methodologies in the field of security and risk. The “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_Application_Security_Risks&quot;&gt;OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risk&lt;/a&gt;” list was first published in 2003 and is probably the closest that the development community has ever come to a set of rules on how to keep products secure.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Top 10 list focuses on identifying the most serious web application security risks for a broad array of organizations. For each of these risks, generic information about the likelihood and technical impact is provided which is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Risk_Rating_Methodology&quot;&gt;OWASP Risk Rating Methodology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a wasp&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many standards and organizations reference the Top 10 project, including but not limited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payment_Card_Industry_Data_Security_Standard&quot;&gt;PCI DSS&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Trade_Commission&quot;&gt;FTC&lt;/a&gt;. The latest version of the list was released in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-goal-of-the-top-10&quot;&gt;The Goal of the Top 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the list is to raise awareness for security issues in application development. It’s a guideline for avoiding common mistakes people make when they’re inexperienced, or don’t know any better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL injection and cross-site scripting vulnerabilities are regularly exploited and there is no sign of that changing anytime soon. The Top 10 makes people aware of those threats when writing code or auditing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWASP’s Top 10 shouldn’t be used as a tick box exercise after the code is written and ready to be rolled out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach of discrediting developers who fail to follow the teachings of OWASP is counterproductive and misses the goal of encouraging people to be more knowledgable about security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-culture-and-composition&quot;&gt;Team Culture and Composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good security culture is about educating people. Giving them the knowledge and processes to stay secure. While it is always important to run QA and security checks before going live with a release, security is best baked into the product instead of built on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One increasingly trendy approach for bringing security into the heart of product development is in embedding security folks into cross-functional teams. This enables people to learn from each other and address security best practices in a less confrontational way. The OWASP Top 10 list will naturally be part of discussions in the team and awareness for common vulnerabilities will increase. The list is a great start for conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-technologies&quot;&gt;Improving the Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing tools along the deployment pipelines will help to amplify developers’ capabilities in addressing the OWASP Top 10 list.
Some examples are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Composition Analysis to address the Security of the  &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/software-supply-chain-security/&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Static Code Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamic Code Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuously applied tests and analysis provide quick feedback and is helping teams to build better and more secure products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-2017-list&quot;&gt;The 2017 List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the latest list and the meaning of the risks. The list is created from gathering the data from hundreds of organizations and over 100,000 real-world applications and APIs. The Top 10 items are selected and prioritized according to this prevalence data, in combination with consensus estimates of exploitability, detectability, and impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;owasp logo&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection&quot;&gt;A1:2017-Injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Injection flaws, such as SQL, NoSQL, OS, and LDAP injection, occur when untrusted data is sent to an interpreter as part of a command or query. The attacker’s hostile data can trick the interpreter into executing unintended commands or accessing data without proper authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A2-Broken_Authentication&quot;&gt;A2:2017-Broken Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Application functions related to authentication and session management are often implemented incorrectly, allowing attackers to compromise passwords, keys, or session tokens, or to exploit other implementation flaws to assume other users’ identities temporarily or permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure&quot;&gt;A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Many web applications and APIs do not properly protect sensitive data, such as financial, healthcare, and PII. Attackers may steal or modify such weakly protected data to conduct credit card fraud, identity theft, or other crimes. Sensitive data may be compromised without extra protection, such as encryption at rest or in transit, and requires special precautions when exchanged with the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A4-XML_External_Entities_(XXE)&quot;&gt;A4:2017-XML External Entities (XXE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Many older or poorly configured XML processors evaluate external entity references within XML documents. External entities can be used to disclose internal files using the file URI handler, internal file shares, internal port scanning, remote code execution, and denial of service attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A5-Broken_Access_Control&quot;&gt;A5:2017-Broken Access Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Restrictions on what authenticated users are allowed to do are often not properly enforced. Attackers can exploit these flaws to access unauthorized functionality and/or data, such as access other users’ accounts, view sensitive files, modify other users’ data, change access rights, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A6-Security_Misconfiguration&quot;&gt;A6:2017-Security Misconfiguration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Security misconfiguration is the most commonly seen issue. This is commonly a result of insecure default configurations, incomplete or ad hoc configurations, open cloud storage, misconfigured HTTP headers, and verbose error messages containing sensitive information. Not only must all operating systems, frameworks, libraries, and applications be securely configured, but they must be patched/upgraded in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A7-Cross-Site_Scripting_(XSS)&quot;&gt;A7:2017-Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - XSS flaws occur whenever an application includes untrusted data in a new web page without proper validation or escaping, or updates an existing web page with user-supplied data using a browser API that can create HTML or JavaScript. XSS allows attackers to execute scripts in the victim’s browser which can hijack user sessions, deface web sites, or redirect the user to malicious sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A8-Insecure_Deserialization&quot;&gt;A8:2017-Insecure Deserialization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Insecure deserialization often leads to remote code execution. Even if deserialization flaws do not result in remote code execution, they can be used to perform attacks, including replay attacks, injection attacks, and privilege escalation attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A9-Using_Components_with_Known_Vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;A9:2017-Using Components with Known Vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Components, such as libraries, frameworks, and other software modules, run with the same privileges as the application. If a vulnerable component is exploited, such an attack can facilitate serious data loss or server takeover. Applications and APIs using components with known vulnerabilities may undermine application defenses and enable various attacks and impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A10-Insufficient_Logging%26Monitoring&quot;&gt;A10:2017-Insufficient Logging&amp;amp;Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Insufficient logging and monitoring, coupled with missing or ineffective integration with incident response, allows attackers to further attack systems, maintain persistence, pivot to more systems, and tamper, extract, or destroy data. Most breach studies show time to detect a breach is over 200 days, typically detected by external parties rather than internal processes or monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/owasp-top-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/owasp-top-10/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptographic Deletion</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;recent-advances-in-privacy-laws-and-regulations-like-the-right-to-be-forgotten-or-gdpr-show-that-secure-deletion-is-becoming-a-requirement-for-organizations&quot;&gt;Recent advances in privacy laws and regulations like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Right_to_be_forgotten&quot;&gt;right to be forgotten&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; show that secure deletion is becoming a requirement for organizations.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;most-companies-dont-consider-this-when-using-todays-cloud-storage-services-established-processes-for-the-secure-deletion-of-on-site-storage-do-not-apply-to-the-cloud-storage-service-of-choice&quot;&gt;Most companies don’t consider this when using today’s cloud storage services. Established processes for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simsrecycling.com/reuse/data-destruction/&quot;&gt;secure deletion of on-site storage&lt;/a&gt; do not apply to the cloud storage service of choice.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/deletion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a person burning a paper&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deletion-of-data&quot;&gt;Deletion of Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a unix-style filesystem, every file or directory (technically there is no difference between them) has an inode. This inode contains all of the metadata like the owner or the creation date. The inode also contains a list of all the blocks in which a file is stored. Those blocks are called data blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.die.net/man/1/rm&quot;&gt;default linux delete command&lt;/a&gt; removes just the inode information. The data blocks remain - no inode is pointing to them and the filesystem will overwrite them eventually. This means that the actual data is recoverable until the data blocks are used again by a new file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-sanitization&quot;&gt;Data Sanitization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data sanitization is the process of deliberately, permanently and irreversibly removing or destroying the data stored on a device and make it unrecoverable. A device that has been sanitized has no usable data. Even advanced forensic tools will not be able to recover any data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three methods to achieve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datasanitization.org/data-sanitization-terminology/#data-sanitization&quot;&gt;data sanitization&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;physical destruction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cryptographic erasure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data erasure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deletion-in-the-cloud&quot;&gt;Deletion in the cloud&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud providers use abstraction to map physical resources to logical endpoints. The resulting pool of virtual resources is used for servers, storage systems, or networks. This enables customers to scale their workload easily across multiple physical devices but makes it very difficult to verify the location and absolute state of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a operation centre&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based storage solutions are a popular service today. But the adoption of such storage services challenges organizations in regards to secure data deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a cloud storage scenario, the data sanitization methods of physical destruction and data erasure are no longer applicable. Physical devices are shared amongst different applications or even customers and cloud providers use complex tiered-storage setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.dropbox.com/files-folders/restore-delete/delete-files&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/security/deletion/&quot;&gt;google cloud storage&lt;/a&gt; inform about their secure deletion and hardware decommission concepts. None are deleting immediate or verifiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cryptographic-deletion&quot;&gt;Cryptographic Deletion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptographic deletion or crypto-shredding is the practice of deliberately deleting or overwriting the decryption key for encrypted data. Effectively making the data unreadable until the deployed encryption protocol is broken or being brute-forced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crypto-shredding is an effective technique for the cloud since it ensures that any data in storage that’s outside of an organization’s physical control is unreadable once the keys are unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following for cryptographic deletion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a strong &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-symmetric/&quot;&gt;symmetric encryption algorithm&lt;/a&gt; like AES-256-CBC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;only store the sensitive data that you need (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-5-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Art. 5 GDRP 1c&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consider BYOE (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bring_your_own_encryption&quot;&gt;bring your own encryption&lt;/a&gt;) and avoid vendor lock-in with cloud providers crypto services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;document your approach for the authorities and verify the key deletion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;crypto-shredding is only as good as the deletion of the key (consider key backups)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the unpredictable pace of technological development could render many encryption methods unreliable in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/cryptographic-deletion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/cryptographic-deletion/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PGP - The Web of Trust is Dead</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;pretty-good-privacy-was-committed-to-making-good-encryption-available-to-everyone-the-used-crypto-was-revolutinary-at-the-time-but-one-of-the-big-problems-with-key-encryption-persisted-how-do-i-get-the-right-key-from-the-person-i-dont-know&quot;&gt;Pretty Good Privacy was committed to making good encryption available to everyone. The used crypto was revolutinary at the time. But one of the big problems with key encryption persisted: How do I get the right key from the person I don’t know?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-of-trust&quot;&gt;Web of Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web of Trust was intended for this exact purpose but only ever worked in a small community of PGP fans. The promise of “encryption for the masses” could never be kept. The inflationary signing of keys causes serious problems and is, therefore, removed in GnuPG in version 2.2.17. By default this version is ignoring all signatures coming from a key server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis of the Web of Trust is that “no two people are more than six degrees apart”. Everybody knows everyone. If you authenticate the key of your acquaintances, you’ll eventually reach a state where you can trust the key of person X that came from a central key server. Alter all, the sister of your uncles friend confirmed that the key actually belonged to X and wasn’t placed there by some malicious actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can sign any key and upload the signed version to the keyserver - in theory only after verifying its authenticity. To prevent state actors from forcing key server operators to replace real keys with fake ones, the Synchronizing Key Server (SKS) was designed in such a way that no key or signatures can be deleted. This, however, enabled a range of abuse scenarios. Currently, unknown people load keys onto keyservers again and again, which carry hundreds of thousands of signatures. Read the crisis communication by &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/rjhansen/67ab921ffb4084c865b3618d6955275f&quot;&gt;Robert J. Hansen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoever imports such a key will stall their PGP installation. There is currently no known fix on the side of the SKS servers. Other options to rescue PGP had to be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’ve known for a decade this attack is possible. It’s now here and it’s devastating” rjh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-end-of-key-signatures&quot;&gt;The end of key signatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a direct response, GnuPG from version 2.2.17 added a new option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;self-sign-only&lt;/code&gt;, which is now a default option. It ensures that only the key servers own signatures are retained when a key is imported. The spam signatures and also those of the sister of your uncles friend - are no longer imported into the local keychain. This doesn’t affect manually imported keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solves the signature spam problem for GPG users. But it comes with a hefty price tag. You no longer have any indication as to whether the imported key from a server is real or not. This problem is real because anyone can upload a key for any identity to the key servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenPGP enthusiasts introduced a new keyserver a few weeks ago. It verifies the e-mail address given in the key and only publishes it after successful verification. As things currently stand, there are a lot of arguments for using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;keys.openpgp.org&lt;/code&gt; instead of the SKS servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mailbox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a mailbox&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web of Trust is practically dead and can be considered a failure. The question arises on how the trust in PGP keys can be restored. Some people argue the community should look at messengers like Signal and Threema. They provide a convenient way of key verification and do not require any user actions or signatures. Those services provide basic trust in the genuineness of the delivered keys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/web-of-trust-dead/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/web-of-trust-dead/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Password Entropy</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;entropy-is-a-way-to-express-the-unpredictability-of-a-character-or-string-it-is-based-on-the-number-of-characters-the-set-and-the-length-of-a-given-string&quot;&gt;Entropy is a way to express the unpredictability of a character or string. It is based on the number of characters (the set) and the length of a given string.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can think of entropy as the randomness of a string. A password with high entropy is theoretically harder to brute force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security features should be seen as sequential measures, where one failing safeguard is protected by another one. Weakening one link in the security chain reduces the overall security. I am therefore a strong supporter of password policies with a high entropy potential, rate-limits, multi-factor authentication, and &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/gdpr-passwords-hashing-you/&quot;&gt;strong hashing functions&lt;/a&gt; for password storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/complex.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing chaos&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;random-passwords&quot;&gt;Random Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In computer science, it is common to specify the password strength of a random password in bits of entropy. This approach is derived from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)&quot;&gt;information theory&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of the number of guesses needed to find the password with certainty, the base-2 logarithm of that number is used, which is the number of “entropy bits” in a password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formula to calculate the entropy is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;H = log2(N^L)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt; = entropy, &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; = character set or number of possible symbols, &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt; = string length or number of characters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A password with an entropy of 128 bits calculated in this way would be as strong as a string of 128 bits chosen randomly, for example by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_coin&quot;&gt;fair coin toss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the length, &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;, needed to achieve the desired strength &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;, with a password, created randomly from a set of &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; symbols, one computes (rounded up to the next largest whole number)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;L = H/(log2N)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a table with some character sets and how many digits are required for 128 bit of entropy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;character set&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;symbol count &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;entropy per symbol &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;symbols required for 128 bits of entropy&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;fair coin 0/1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1.000 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;arabic numerals (0-9)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.322 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;hexadecimal numerals (0–9, A–F) (e.g. WEP keys)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.000 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case insensitive Latin alphabet (a–z or A–Z)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.700 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case sensitive Latin alphabet (a–z, A–Z)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.700 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case sensitive alphanumeric (a–z, A–Z, 0–9)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.954 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;all ASCII printable characters&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;95&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6.570 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a short python script to calculate the theoretical entropy of a random password:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/python3
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;argparse&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argparse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ArgumentParser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_argument&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;num_symbols&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;character set or number of symbols&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_argument&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;length&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;password length in characters&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parse_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num_symbols&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-generated-passwords&quot;&gt;Human-generated Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are notoriously poor at achieving sufficient entropy to produce satisfactory passwords. According to one study involving half a million users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/www2007.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, the average password entropy was estimated at 40.54 bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gets worse with the most common number used is “1”, and the most common letters are a, e, o, and r. Users don’t make full use of larger character sets when forming passwords. For example, hacking results obtained from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2006/12/myspace-passwords-arent-so-dumb/?currentPage=all&quot;&gt;MySpace phishing scheme in 2006&lt;/a&gt; revealed 34,000 passwords, of which only 8.3% used mixed case, numbers, and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full strength associated with using a certain character set is only achieved if each possible password is equally likely. The human behavior is a reduction of the theoretical password “strength”. A better requirement would be to require a password &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to contain words from dictionaries or names. If patterned choices are required, humans are likely to use them in predictable ways, such a capitalizing a letter, adding only one or two numbers, and a special character. This predictability means that the increase in password strength is minor when compared to random passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-password-guidelines-in-2019&quot;&gt;Common Password Guidelines in 2019&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a password manager to generate truly random passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a minimum password length of 12 or more characters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use lowercase, uppercase alphabetic characters, numbers and symbols if permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid using the same password twice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid using information that is or could be publicly associated with the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid character repetition, keyboard patterns, dictionary words, letter or number sequences (e.g. dates), usernames, names (ancestors, pets, [ex]partners), biographical information (e.g. ID number)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check passwords against those obtained from previous data breaches (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&quot;&gt;HIBP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/password-entropy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/password-entropy/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
