<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>technology, security, watch and book reviews</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 18:48:30 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 18:48:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptography - Symmetric Key Algorithms</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is the second in a series about cryptography. This time we look at symmetric cryptography, the advantages, disadvantages, and implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-history-basics/&quot;&gt;First Part: Cryptography - History and Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;symmetric-key-algorithms---definition&quot;&gt;Symmetric Key Algorithms - Definition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Symmetric Key Algorithms are based on a shared secret key which is distributed to all members participating in the encrypted communication. The key is used to encrypted and decrypt the message. The sender and receiver are both in the possession of a copy of the shared key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When large keys are used, the symmetric encryption is very difficult to break. The primary use case for it is bulk encryption (eg. hard drives) with a high speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternative terms: &lt;em&gt;private key cryptography&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;shared private key&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/symmetry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing symmetry&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advantage-of-symmetric-key-cryptography&quot;&gt;Advantage of Symmetric Key Cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;/strong&gt; Symmetric Key Cryptography is extremely secure if it is used with a secure algorithm, and a large key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast&lt;/strong&gt; Encrypting and Decrypting symmetric key data is considerably faster than in asymmetric key algorithms&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disadvantages-of-symmetric-key-cryptography&quot;&gt;Disadvantages of Symmetric Key Cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key distribution&lt;/strong&gt; is a major problem since parties must have a secure method of exchanging the secret key before communication can be established. Out-of-band exchange is the method of offline key distribution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonrepudiation&lt;/strong&gt; is not given since each party uses the same key to encrypt and decrypt. There is no way to prove the origin of a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not scalable&lt;/strong&gt; secure communication in a group can only be achieved if each possible combination of users exchanges a shared private key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key regeneration&lt;/strong&gt; all keys must be regenerated if one user leaves the group.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;des---data-encryption-standard&quot;&gt;DES - Data Encryption Standard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Encryption Standard or DES is a symmetric-key algorithm that was developed in the early 1970s. Its short key length of 56-bit (+8 bit parity) was criticized from the beginning. Nowadays this algorithm is no longer recommended for use since intelligence agencies are believed to routinely decrypt DES-encrypted information. This algorithm is nevertheless important to understand because it is highly influential for the more advanced modern cryptography algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DES is the archetypal block cipher - an algorithm that takes a fixed-length string of plaintext bits (DES: 64-bit) and transforms it into a ciphertext string of the same length. In the case of DES, the transformation is accomplished by an exclusive OR (XOR) operation. This process is repeated 16 times for each encryption/decryption operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It supports 5 different modes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic Code Book Mode - ECB&lt;/strong&gt; is the simplest mode and the least secure. Each time the algorithm processes a 64-bit block, it simply encrypts the block using the secret key. Encrypting the same block twice produces the same result. This makes the mode vulnerable to building a “code book”. After a sufficient number of encrypted blocks are gathered, cryptoanalytic techniques could decipher some of the blocks and break the encryption. ECB was only used for the exchange of small amounts of data such as keys or parameters or for encrypting the fields in a database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cipher Block Chaining Mode - CBC&lt;/strong&gt; describes the mode in which each unencrypted block of text is XORed with the block of ciphertext preceding it before it is encrypted. The decryption process simply reverses this behavior. CBC introduces an &lt;em&gt;initialization vector (IV)&lt;/em&gt; and XORs it with the first block of the to be encrypted message. This IV is sent to all recipients either in plaintext or by using ECB. The main problem of CBC is that errors in the message propagate. One corrupted block makes it impossible to decrypt the message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cipher Feedback Mode - CFB&lt;/strong&gt; is simply the streaming version of CBC. It operates against data in real-time. Instead of working with 64-bit blocks of text is uses a memory buffer of the same block size. It encrypts the buffer once it is full and sends it to the recipients. CFB operates in the same fashion as CBC, it uses an IV and is chaining the blocks (buffers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output Feedback Mode - OFB&lt;/strong&gt; operates on streaming data with buffers in the same way as CFB. However, instead of XORing the encrypted version of the previous block (buffer), it uses a seed value as the IV. Future seed values are derived by running the DES algorithm on the previous seed value. The biggest advantage of this mode is that there is no chaining function and therefore errors do not propagate. This makes the mode more robust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counter Mode - CTR&lt;/strong&gt; is similar to OFC but instead of creating the seed value for each encryption/decryption from the results of the previous seed values, it uses a simple counter and increments it for each operation. As with OFB mode, errors do not propagate in CTR mode. CTR also allows to break the operation (encryption/decryption) in multiple steps and is therefore well suited for parallel computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3des---triple-des&quot;&gt;3DES - Triple DES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 56-bit key of DES is no longer considered adequate in the times of modern cryptoanalytic and in the abundance of computational power (cloud). An adapted version of called Triple DES or 3DES uses the same algorithm to produce more secure encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four versions of 3DES:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DES-EEE3&lt;/strong&gt; encrypts the plaintext 3 times using 3 different keys (K1, K2, and K3) and runs 3 encryption operations. It has an effective key length of 168-bit. (P = plaintext, E = encryption)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;E(K1,E(K2,E(K3,P)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DES-EDE3&lt;/strong&gt; uses also 3 keys but replaces the second encryption operation with a decryption operation. The key length is 168-bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;E(K1,D(K2,E(K3,P)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DES-EEE2&lt;/strong&gt; uses only 2 keys as follows and has an effective key length of 112-bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;E(K1,E(K2,E(K1,P)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DES-EDE2&lt;/strong&gt; uses 2 keys and replaces the second encryption operation with a decryption operation. The key length is 112-bit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;E(K1,D(K2,E(K1,P)))
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;idea---international-data-encryption-algorithm&quot;&gt;IDEA - International Data Encryption Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IDEA was developed in response to the criticism of the insufficient key length of DES. Like DES it operates on 64-bit block or buffers of plaintext/ciphertext. It begins the operation with a 128-bit key which is broken up in 56x 16-bit subkeys. The subkeys are then used in a combination of XOR and modulus to produce the encrypted/decrypted version of the input message. IDEA is operating with the same five modes of DES: ECB, CBC, CFB, OFC, and CTR. One well-known implementation of IDEA is Phil Zimmerman’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pretty_Good_Privacy&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Pretty Good Privacy (PGP)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;blowfish&quot;&gt;Blowfish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another alternative to DES and IDEA is Bruce Schneier’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blowfish_(cipher)&quot;&gt;Blowfish&lt;/a&gt; block cipher. It also operates of 64-bit blocks of text but allows to define the key length ranging from a relative insecure 32-bit to an extremely strong 448-bit. With longer key, the encryption/decryption time increases obviously. Blowfish was released for public use and is built in a number of commercial products and open source products (eg. SSH, or Linux).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;skipjack&quot;&gt;Skipjack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This algorithm also works on 64-bit blocks of text and uses an 80-bit key. It supports all modes of operation of DES and was adopted by the U.S. government. It has an added &lt;em&gt;feature&lt;/em&gt; of supporting the escrow of encryption keys. Two government agencies (National Institute of Standards and Technology - NIST and Department of Treasury - DOT), hold a portion of the information required to reconstruct a Skipjack key. Law enforcements can obtain the pieces of keys, and decrypt Skipjack communication. This algorithm was obviously not embraced by the cryptographic community but is in wide use with the U.S. government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rc2rc5---rivest-cipher-rsa&quot;&gt;RC2/RC5 - Rivest Cipher (RSA)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a symmetric key algorithm patented by Rivest-Shamir-Adleman (RSA) Data Security and is found in commercial products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RC2 uses a block size of 64-bit and a key size of 128-bit.
RC5 uses a block size of 32, 64, or 128-bit and a variable key size ranging from 0 - 2040-bit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;aesrijndael---advanced-encryption-standard&quot;&gt;AES/Rijndael - Advanced Encryption Standard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Advanced_Encryption_Standard&quot;&gt;AES&lt;/a&gt; allows three key strengths: 128 bits, 192 bits, and 256 bits and encrypts 128-bit blocks of text. The underlying block-cipher Rijndael exceeds the AES specification and allows to use a block size equal to the key length. The number of encryption rounds in AWS depends on the key length:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;128-bit key -&amp;gt; 10 rounds of encryption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;192-bit key -&amp;gt; 12 rounds of encryption&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;256-bit key -&amp;gt; 14 rounds of encryption&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;twofish&quot;&gt;Twofish&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Twofish was also developed by Bruce Schneier and was a finalist of the AES contest. Twofish is a block cipher and operates on 128-bit blocks of data. It is capable of using key sizes of 1 - 256-bit in length. Twofish introduces two new techniques which are not found in other algorithms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prewhitening&lt;/strong&gt; is the process of XORing the plaintext with a separate subkey before the first round of encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Postwhitening&lt;/strong&gt; uses a similar operation after the 16th round of encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;distribution-of-symmetric-keys&quot;&gt;Distribution of Symmetric Keys&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the major challenges of symmetric encryption algorithms is the secure distribution of the secret keys. There are three general methods used to exchange secret keys securely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offline Distribution&lt;/strong&gt; This is the technically most simple method and requires the physical exchange of the key material in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Real_life#Related_terminology&quot;&gt;meatspace&lt;/a&gt;. One party provides the other with a medium (e.g. sheet of paper, or flash drive) which contains the secret key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Key Encryption&lt;/strong&gt; Here we overcome the hassle of secret key distribution by using public key encryption for the initial setup of the communication (exchange of secret key). Once the secret key has been exchanged, the communication switches to a secret key algorithm to benefit from increased processing speed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diffie-Hellman&lt;/strong&gt; There are use-cases where offline distribution is not feasible (no physical means) and public key encryption is not available (lack of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;public key infrastructure&lt;/a&gt;). In a situation like this so-called key exchange algorithms like Diffie-Hellmann are useful mechanisms to exchange the secret key to enable symmetric key communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; Bob and Alice have to agree on two large numbers. P (prime number) and G (integer) such that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;1 &amp;lt; G &amp;lt; P&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; Bob now chooses a random large integer R and performs the following calculation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;B = G^R mod P&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; Alice chooses a random large integer S and performs the following calculation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;A = G^S mod P&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; Bob sends B to Alice and she sends A to Bob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; Bob performs the following calculation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;K = A^R mod P&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; Alice performs the following calculation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;K = B^S mod P&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point both Bob and Alice have the same value &lt;strong&gt;K&lt;/strong&gt;, and can use this for communication with a symmetric key algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-symmetric/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-symmetric/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptography - History &amp; Basics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is the first in a series about cryptography. In this article, I look at the evolution of crypto and famous historical implementations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;history-of-cryptography&quot;&gt;History of Cryptography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speech and written communication defined the early civilizations and continuously evolved with human societies. In the beginning, humans used &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Petroglyph&quot;&gt;Petroglyphs&lt;/a&gt;, which evolved into &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pictogram&quot;&gt;Pictograms&lt;/a&gt; (Hieroglyphs), and finally &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ideograms&quot;&gt;Ideograms&lt;/a&gt; and today we use flash storage devices stuffed with the information of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Scholastic-Flash-Drive-Encyclopedia-Britannica/dp/B003DKK9KK&quot;&gt;Encyclopedia Britannica&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing encrypted data&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As long as humans have been communicating, they tried to hide the true meaning of the written word from their enemies. Ancient civilizations used complex systems of secret symbols. The evolution of those systems are the codes and ciphers we facilitate to enable private communication in our times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;substitution-cipher-caesar-cipher&quot;&gt;Substitution Cipher: Caesar Cipher&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In crypto, the Caesar cipher is one of the earliest known systems and was used by Julus Caesar to communicate with Cicero in Rome while he was conquering Europe. It is a substitution cipher in which each letter in the plaintext is replaced by a letter some fixed number of positions down the alphabet. For example, with a right shift of 3, A would be replaced by D, B would become E, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is called ROT3 (Rotate 3) cipher and encrypted/decrypted is mathematically implemented by converting each letter to its decimal equivalent. A is 0 and Z is 25. The wrap-around is done by using the modulo function. (C = ciphertext, P = plaintext)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Alphabet to Number relation&quot; style=&quot;middle; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;decrypted message: &lt;strong&gt;WINTER_IS_COMING&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;math to encrypt: C = (P+3) mod 26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_6.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Alphabet to Number relation&quot; style=&quot;middle; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;encrypted message: &lt;strong&gt;ZLQWHU_LV_FRPLQJ&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;math to decrypt: P = (C-3) mod 26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This cipher is easy to use but also easy to crack. The cipher is vulnerable to &lt;em&gt;frequency analysis&lt;/em&gt; since the most common letters in the English language are E, T, A, O, N, R, I, S, and H. Attackers just need to find the common letters in the encrypted text (in my example the letter “I”) and experiment with substitution to break the cipher.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transposition-cipher-rail-fence-cipher-zigzag-cipher&quot;&gt;Transposition cipher: Rail Fence Cipher (ZigZag Cipher)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rail fence cipher was used by the ancient Greeks in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scytale&quot;&gt;scytale&lt;/a&gt;, a mechanical system of producing a transposition cipher. The system consisted of a cylinder and a ribbon that was wrapped around the cylinder. The message to be encrypted was written on the coiled ribbon. The letters of the original message would be rearranged when the ribbon was uncoiled from the cylinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another approach is to write the plain text downwards and diagonally on successive “rails” of an imaginary fence, then moving up when the bottom rail is reached. When the top rail is reached, the message is written downwards again until the whole plaintext is written out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;message: &lt;strong&gt;JON_SNOW_IS_A_TARGARYEN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 rail fence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Rail Fence Cypher&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;encryption with a 3 rail fence:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Rail Fence Cypher&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;encrypted message: &lt;strong&gt;JS_ARYO_NWI__AGRENOSTAN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The message was easily decrypted when the ribbon was recoiled on a cylinder of the same diameter or by trying out multiple fence methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;advanced-substitution-one-time-pads&quot;&gt;Advanced Substitution: One-Time Pads&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A one-time pad is an extremely powerful type of cipher and uses a different substitution alphabet for each letter of the plaintext message. It can be represented by the following function. (C = ciphertext, P = plaintext, K = encryption key)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Alphabet to Number relation&quot; style=&quot;middle; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;decrypted message: &lt;strong&gt;WINTER_IS_COMING&lt;/strong&gt; 22 08 13 19 04 17 08 18 02 14 12 08 13 06&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one-time pad: &lt;strong&gt;ZVFXZVFXZVFXZV&lt;/strong&gt; 25 21 05 23 25 21 05 23 25 21 05 23 25 21&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;math to encrypt: C = (P+K) mod 26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing Alphabet to Number relation&quot; style=&quot;middle; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;encrypted message: &lt;strong&gt;VDSQDM_NP_BJRFNMB&lt;/strong&gt; 21 03 18 16 03 12 13 15 01 09 17 05 12 01&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;math to decrypt: P = (C-K) mod 26&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of one-time pads is that there is no repeating pattern of alphabetic substitution. This cipher is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Information-theoretic_security&quot;&gt;Information-theoretical-secure&lt;/a&gt;. It is an unbreakable encryption scheme if the following requirements are met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The one-time pad must be randomly generated without the use of a reoccurring pattern.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The one-time pad must be protected against disclosure. The message can be easily decrypted if the adversary has a copy of the pad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each pad can only be used once (one-time). Reusing the same pad on multiple messages makes it possible to determine the key value used.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The key must be at least as long as the message so each character of the key is used to encrypt one character of the message.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The advantage of the one-time pad is broken as soon as one of those requirements is not met. One of the major intelligence successes of the United States during the Cold War was when US cryptoanalysts broke the top-secret Soviet cryptosystem that relied on a one-time pad. The project called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Venona_project&quot;&gt;VENONA&lt;/a&gt; discovered a pattern in the key values. The Soviets violated rule number one of one-time pad crypto.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My example does it as well by just repeating the same key (ZVFX).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-time pads have been used throughout history to protect sensitive communication. The major challenge of the system is the generation, distribution and, safeguarding of the key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-breaking&quot;&gt;Code Breaking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Frequency_analysis&quot;&gt;Frequency analysis&lt;/a&gt; is the basic tool for breaking most classical ciphers. It utilizes the fact that in languages, certain letters of the alphabet appear more often than others. With a long enough ciphertext a reasonable representation count of letters can be created and ultimately the code be broken. In the 15th century the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vigen%C3%A8re_cipher&quot;&gt;Vigenère cipher&lt;/a&gt; (polyalphabetic substitution aka series of interwoven Caesar ciphers) was invented and considered to be completely secure (le chiffre indéchiffrable—”the indecipherable cipher”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During World War I and World War II the deciphering of messages played a significant part in the success of a campaign. The US/UK broke the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lorenz_cipher&quot;&gt;Lorenz Cipher&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Enigma_machine&quot;&gt;Enigma Machine&lt;/a&gt; which is said to have played a decisive factor in the Allied victory. The Germans broke the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/German_code_breaking_in_World_War_II&quot;&gt;Naval Code #3 and #5&lt;/a&gt; which enabled the early successes in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Battle_of_the_Atlantic&quot;&gt;Battle of the Atlantic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today the Information or &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/cyber-warfare-domain/&quot;&gt;Cyber Domain&lt;/a&gt; is an official dimension of modern warfare. Intercepting the enemies communication and deciphering the information is a common theme with all major military powers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing encrypted data&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-history-basics/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-history-basics/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Classification</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Data is the oil of the 21st century. Information, knowledge, and data are all closely related concepts, but each has its own role in relation to the other. In this article I will treat them as one. [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-is-the-classification-of-data-important&quot;&gt;Why is the classification of data important?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is inefficient to treat all data the same way when implementing protection for the data assets of an organization. Securing everything with few or no safeguards (controls) means sensitive data might get exposed. Securing everything at a high-security level is expensive and restricts access to noncritical data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classification of data is helpful to determine how much effort, resources, and money is allocated to protect data and control access to it. It is important to classify the protection level of data with the input from legal, regulatory, business, and technical experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Categorization is the process of organizing objects into groups with similarities. The similarities can be value, sensitivity, risk, vulnerability, or damage upon loss. Classification is used to provide mechanisms for processing, storing, or transferring data and also defines how data is removed or destroyed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Declassification is required once an object no longer matches the similarities of other objects in the same category. Without declassification, resources are wasted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The benefits of using data classification schemes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It assists in identifying assets that are most critical and valuable to an organization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It demonstrates an organizations commitment to protecting valuable resources and assets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It helps in the selection of protection mechanisms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is often required for regulatory and legal compliance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It assists in defining access levels for authorized users&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/data.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture representing data&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two commonly used classification schemes are government/military and commercial business/private sector classification levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;government-and-military-classification-scheme&quot;&gt;Government and Military Classification Scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five levels of classification in this scheme. This scheme varies from country to country. [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Top Secret&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Secret&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Confidential&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sensitive but unclassified&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Unclassified&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Secret&lt;/strong&gt; is the highest level of classification. The disclosure of top-secret data will cause &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; damage to national security. This category of data/information is only provided on a need-to-know basis to users. Even users with top-secret clearance will not get access to data until the user has to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secret&lt;/strong&gt; is used for data of a restricted category. Disclosure of secret data will have a &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; effect on national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidential&lt;/strong&gt; classification is used for all data between secret and sensitive but unclassified. The disclosure of confidential data will have a &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; effect on national security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitive But Unclassified&lt;/strong&gt; is used for data that is for internal use or office use only. SBU is often used for data that violates the privacy rights of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unclassified&lt;/strong&gt; is data that is neither sensitive nor classified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revealing the classification label of classified data is already considered a violation of the protection level. Top Secret, Secret and Confidential data are therefore commonly called &lt;em&gt;classified data&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;commercial-business-and-private-sector-classification-levels&quot;&gt;Commercial Business And Private Sector Classification Levels&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are only 3 levels in this classification scheme. The scheme can be adapted to a specific use-case. The University of Berkley is, for example, categorizing data in 4 levels [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;High&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Confidential/Private&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sensitive&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Low&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Public&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Confidential&lt;/strong&gt; is used for data that is extremely sensitive and for internal use only. A &lt;em&gt;significant&lt;/em&gt; negative impact for the organization will occur upon disclosure of data in this category. Another term for this level of classification is &lt;strong&gt;proprietary&lt;/strong&gt;. If proprietary data is lost, it can have an effect on the competitive advantage of a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private&lt;/strong&gt; is used for data that is of a private or personal nature. It is intended for internal use only. The disclosure of private data will have a negative impact on the company or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitive&lt;/strong&gt; is used for data that is not intended for the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public&lt;/strong&gt; is the lowest classification level. It is used for all data that does not match the higher levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ownership-of-data&quot;&gt;Ownership of Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ownership has to be considered in the context of data classification. It can override all other forms of access control. Any operating system or application where files or other types of objects can be assigned to an owner has to be taken into consideration and a security policy has to be enforced to help categorize the content. An owner has full capabilities and privileges over an object they own. The ability to take ownership is often only granted to the most powerful user in an operating system (eg Linux root user or Windows Administrator) or to the creator of an object/file (Goole Docs).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data&quot;&gt;Data - From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classified_information&quot;&gt;Classified information - From Wikipedia, the free encyclopedia&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.berkeley.edu/data-classification-standard&quot;&gt;Berkely Information Security and Policy&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/data-classification/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/data-classification/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Sci-Fi Reality - Cyberwar</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;art-sci-fi-military-doctrine&quot;&gt;Art, Sci-Fi, Military Doctrine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hackers of a terrorist group get bombed just minutes after they start a cyber attack. Sounds like science fiction but the cyber domain just received its first immediate kinetic response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word Cyber became popular when internet, digital communication, and digital identities were all emerging and the term “Cyberspace” was able to describe the new phenomena and ideas. It has been called the largest unregulated and uncontrolled domain in the history of mankind[&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;] and is also unique because it is a domain created by people contrary to the traditional physical domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberwar, Cyberattack, Cyberspace…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term Cyberspace was coined when Danish artist Susanne Ussing (1940-1998) and her partner architect Carsten Hoff (b. 1934) founded Atelier Cyberspace. The two made a series of installations and images entitled “sensory spaces” that were based on the principle of open systems adaptable to various influences, such as human movement and the behavior of new materials[&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Science Fiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first usage of Cyberspace in the context of online computer networks was in the 1980s when science fiction author William Gibson used the term in his cyberpunk books &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Burning_Chrome&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Burning Chrome&lt;/em&gt; (1982)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Neuromancer&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neuromancer&lt;/em&gt; (1984)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cyber.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of hacker&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Cyberspace. A consensual hallucination experienced daily by billions of legitimate operators, in every nation, by children being taught mathematical concepts… A graphic representation of data abstracted from the banks of every computer in the human system. Unthinkable complexity. Lines of light ranged in the nonspace of the mind, clusters, and constellations of data. Like city lights, receding. (Neuromancer)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neuromancer is a cult classic of the science fiction subgenre cyberpunk. The story of Case, Molly, Armitage, the AIs Wintermute and Neuromancer, and the Turing Police are unforgotten and quickly became an underground hit.
Today the book is considered “the archetypal cyberpunk work”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Military Doctrine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1995 General Ronald R. Fogleman, Air Force chief of staff delivered a speech to the Armed Forces Communications-Electronics Association [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:3&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:3&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this speech, he defined a new dimension of Warfare. Information. Later the scope was extended beyond the original information operations background, focusing on “the advanced space-time manipulating capabilities cyberspace offers” and resulting in “Advanced Battlespace and Cybermaneuver Concepts” [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:4&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:4&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today all major military contenders and alliances [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:5&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:5&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;] operate in the 5 dimensions (domains) of warfare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Land&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Air&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cyber&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The domains are not seen as silos of their own but are connected and operations are carried out in multiple dimensions to form the battlefields of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cyberwarfare&quot;&gt;Cyberwarfare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberwarfare consists of both offensive and defensive operations like espionage, sabotage, and cyber attacks. Powers have been developing cyber capabilities and have engaged in offensive and defensive activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard A. Clarke defines it as “actions by a nation-state to penetrate another nation’s computers or networks for the purposes of causing damage or disruption.”[&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:6&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:6&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;] Martin Libicki defines two types of cyberwarfare: Strategic and operational, with strategic being “a campaign of cyberattacks one entity carries out on another”, whilst operational cyberwarfare “involves the use of cyberattacks on the other side’s military in the context of a physical war.”[&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:7&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:7&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other definitions include non-state actors, such as companies, terrorist groups, political or ideological extremist groups, terrorist hacktivists, and transnational organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Espionage&lt;/strong&gt; or Cyber-espionage is generally assumed ongoing between all major powers. One example is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Global_surveillance_disclosures_(2013%E2%80%93present)#Disclosures&quot;&gt;massive spying&lt;/a&gt; of the US in many countries as it was revealed by Edward Snowden. Espionage is not considered an act of war but the word attack is often used in this context.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sabotage&lt;/strong&gt; Cyber attacks with the goal of interruption or interception is a major threat to the functionality of the military and civilian infrastructure. Examples are the attack of US/Israel against Iran with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stuxnet&quot;&gt;Stuxnet worm&lt;/a&gt; or the attack of Russia against the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/December_2015_Ukraine_power_grid_cyberattack&quot;&gt;Ukrainian power grid&lt;/a&gt;. The attack surface of nation-states will increase with a broader adaption of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet_of_things&quot;&gt;IOT&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Industry_4.0&quot;&gt;Industry 4.0&lt;/a&gt;. State player attacks against banks with the purpose of disrupting the economy of adversaries is an option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Propaganda&lt;/strong&gt; Cyber-propaganda is an effort to control or manipulate public opinion. It utilizes social-media, fake websites, and other digital channels to de-legitimize the political system. The internet provides low-cost access to a wide audience and provides a feedback loop regarding the efficiency of propaganda. Countermeasures are affecting the freedom of speech principle of liberal societies and can turn into the perception of censorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;latest-development&quot;&gt;Latest Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There has been controversy over whether cyber operations can be called a declaration of war. The US moved forward in 2011 and made clear that a kinetic response to cyberattacks is a viable option [&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:8&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:8&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015 the US became the first country to respond with military force to a cyberattack. A remote-controlled drone killed a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dod.defense.gov/News/Article/Article/615305/iraq-progresses-in-isil-fight-key-extremist-confirmed-dead/&quot;&gt;British citizen&lt;/a&gt; who was involved in the release of personally identifiable information of about 1,300 U.S. military and government employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An now in 2019 Israel became the first country to respond with &lt;strong&gt;immediate&lt;/strong&gt; military force to a cyberattack. The Hamas cyber-units headquarters in Gaza was destroyed in a so-called “bomb-back” mission[&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:9&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:9&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;]. This is a turning point in modern warfare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-conversation=&quot;none&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;Here is the video released by the IDF showing the air-strike against the building housing Hamas cyber forces. &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/uHm2ZYa4AP&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/uHm2ZYa4AP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;Catalin Cimpanu (@campuscodi) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/campuscodi/status/1125122680267603968?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;May 5, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack was executed by an F-16 fighter airplane. It is currently unknown if the cyberattack was pinpointed to this location or if the IDF used previously acquired knowledge of the location to attack the cyber forces of Hamas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For future development and more details on the topic I want to refer to two of the thought leaders on cyber warfare: &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/thegrugq&quot;&gt;the grugq&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gvS4efEakpY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mikko&quot;&gt;mikko&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/l2rIVdpMToM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cyberpeace&quot;&gt;Cyberpeace&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rise of the cyberspace as a domain of fighting wars has led to multiple efforts to control cyberweapons and surveillance technology. Initiatives include the disclosure of vulnerabilities, decentralization, encryption, and education. Policymakers in Europe are developing rules and norms for modern warfare including cyber. It has to be seen how the results of Cyberpeace efforts will affect the wars on this new battlefield of the 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the topics of Neuromancer have become a reality of our time and we see the beginning of developments that have been anticipated in the book. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Artificial_intelligence&quot;&gt;AI&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cyborg&quot;&gt;Cyborgs&lt;/a&gt; and Genetic Modifications are all on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in interesting times of Sci-Fi reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;1: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/10570319909374648&quot;&gt;The varieties of cyberspace: Problems in definition and delimitation&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;2: &lt;a href=&quot;https://kunstkritikk.com/the-reinvention-of-cyberspace/&quot;&gt;The (Re)invention of Cyberspace&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:3&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;3: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.iwar.org.uk/iwar/resources/5th-dimension/iw.htm&quot;&gt;The Fifth Dimension of Warfare&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:3&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:4&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;4: &lt;a href=&quot;https://worldview.stratfor.com/article/virtual-reality-changing-nature-war#axzz38BcIZKVM&quot;&gt;Is Virtual Reality Changing the Nature of War?&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:4&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:5&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;5: &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.softpedia.com/news/nato-declares-cyber-as-official-battleground-next-to-air-sea-and-land-505388.shtml&quot;&gt;NATO Declares Cyber an Official Warfare Battleground&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:5&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:6&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;6: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.harpercollins.com/9780061962233/cyber-war/&quot;&gt;Cyber War&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:6&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:7&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;7: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Cyberdeterrence-Cyberwar-Martin-C-Libicki/dp/0833047345&quot;&gt;Cyberdeterrence and Cyberwar&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:7&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:8&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;8: &lt;a href=&quot;https://apps.dtic.mil/dtic/tr/fulltext/u2/a600813.pdf&quot;&gt;International Acceptance of Kinetic Operations in Response to a Cyber Attack&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:8&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:9&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;9: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/in-a-first-israel-responds-to-hamas-hackers-with-an-air-strike/&quot;&gt;In a first, Israel responds to Hamas hackers with an air strike&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:9&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/cyber-warfare-domain/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/cyber-warfare-domain/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The CIA Triad - Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Security must start somewhere. This somewhere is a list of security principles. Confidentiality, Integrity, and Availability are considered the primary goals and objectives of a security infrastructure. Security controls are measured on how well they address those core principles. How important each principle is to an organization depends on the security goals and requirements of a company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cia_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Mexican pyramid&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;confidentiality&quot;&gt;Confidentiality&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality protects the secrecy of data, objects, or resources. The goal is to prevent or minimize unauthorized access to data. An authorized user can access or interact with objects while Confidentiality actively prevents unauthorized users from doing so. Many security measures or controls support Confidentiality. Examples are encryption, access control, authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An object is the passive part in a security relationship, such as files, applications, computers, and network connections.
A subject is the active part in a security relationship, such as users, programs or computers.
The management of the relationship between object and subject is access control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For confidentiality to be maintained in a network, data needs to be protected from unauthorized access and disclosure while in transit, in program, and in storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specific controls are required for each of these states of data, resources, and objects to maintain confidentiality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous attacks focus on the violation of confidentiality. Examples are capturing network traffic, stealing passwords, port scanning, privilege escalation, and social engineering. Violation of confidentiality (disclosure) is not limited to intentional attacks. Many times the cause for unauthorized disclosure are the result of human error and oversight. Events leading to disclosure include failing to encrypt a transmission, accessing malicious code, walking away from a computer while sensitive data is displayed on the screen, misconfigured security control, or oversight in a security policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Numerous countermeasures help to ensure confidentiality. These include encryption, network traffic monitoring, strict access control, authentication, data classification, and ownership, or training of personnel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality and Integrity are depending on each other. Without object integrity, confidentiality cannot be maintained. Integrity means the inability of an object to be modified without permission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confidentiality concepts, conditions, and aspects include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitivity&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the damage caused by the disclosure of data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Criticality&lt;/strong&gt; defines how important an object is for the functionality of an organization&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secrecy&lt;/strong&gt; describes the act of preventing disclosure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy&lt;/strong&gt; refers to keeping personally identifiable data confidential&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations need to evaluate the level of confidentiality they wish to enforce on objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;integrity&quot;&gt;Integrity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrity is the concept of protecting the reliability and correctness of data. Integrity protection prevents unauthorized changes to data. It ensures that data remains correct, unaltered, and preserved. Well implemented integrity provides the functionality of authenticated change while it prevents intended and malicious unauthorized activities as well as mistakes by authorized users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Objects must retain their correctness and can only be intentionally changed by authenticated users, in order to maintain integrity. Integrity mechanism and protection provide a high level of assurance that the data, object, and resources are unaltered from their original protected state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unauthorized and unwanted changes should not occur while an object is in storage, in transit, or in process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cia_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;integrity right wrong&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrity is checked from three perspectives:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preventing unauthorized subjects from making modifications&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Preventing authorized subjects from making unauthorized changes (mistakes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maintaining consistency of objects so that their data is correct&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to maintain integrity on a system, controls must be in place to restrict access to data, objects, and resources. Activity logging must be employed to verify that only authorized users are able to access their respective resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some example of attacks against the violation of integrity are viruses, coding errors, malicious modifications, and backdoors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As in confidentiality, the attacks on integrity are not always intentional. Human errors, lack of oversight, or improperness can cause unauthorized alteration of information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many countermeasures to support the integrity approach in security. Access control, authentication, intrusion detection, encryption, hashing, interface restrictions, input verification, training of personnel. Integrity is depending on confidentiality and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integrity concepts, conditions, and aspects&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accuracy&lt;/strong&gt; is correct and precise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Truthfulness&lt;/strong&gt; is a true reflection of reality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authenticity&lt;/strong&gt; refers to genuine and authentic&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability&lt;/strong&gt; means being responsible for actions and results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt; refers to being in charge of having control over a subject or object&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comprehensiveness&lt;/strong&gt; the complete scope of all elements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nonrepudiation&lt;/strong&gt; is not being able to deny having performed an activity or action&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validity&lt;/strong&gt; is factual and logically correct&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;availability&quot;&gt;Availability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last principle of the triad is availability. It refers to authorized subjects have timely and uninterrupted access to objects. Availability implies that infrastructure, like network services or authentication systems, is functional and allows authorized users to gain authorized access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For availability to be maintained, controls need to be in place to ensure an acceptable level of performance, to handle interruption, to be redundant, to maintain functional backups, and to prevent data loss.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example threats to availability are device failure, environmental issues, software and hardware errors, (D)DoS ((Distributed) Denial of Service) attacks, and communication interruptions. As with confidentiality and integrity, violations of availability are not limited to intentional attacks. Examples are overutilizing hardware or software component, mislabeling or incorrectly classifying objects, or accidentally deleting files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cia_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mexicani pyramid&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Countermeasures to support availability are numerous and include monitoring of performance, monitoring of network traffic, monitoring of network bandwidth, redundancy for critical systems, maintaining and testing backup systems, (D)DoS protection systems, designing fault-tolerant systems, testing access control systems, removing single points of failure, and business continuity planning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Availability depends on confidentiality and integrity and cannot be maintained without the two.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Availability concepts and aspects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Usability&lt;/strong&gt; refers to easy to learn, understand, control, and apply&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accessibility&lt;/strong&gt; is the concept of a wide range of subjects can interact with an object&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timeliness&lt;/strong&gt; means to provide low latency response or being within a reasonable timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cia-priority&quot;&gt;CIA Priority&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every organization has unique security requirements and the security needs have to be prioritized. Knowing which assets are more important than others guides the development of a dedicated security stance and the deployment of a security solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prioritizing with the CIA Triad is a good start and can be replicated for design, architecture, deployment, maintenance, and development.
The prioritization focuses the effort of an organization on one aspect over the others. It doesn’t mean that the second or third prioritised items are ignored or improperly addressed. Each individual organization decides its own security priorities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/cia-triad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/cia-triad/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security Risk Assessment</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Risk is a consequence of an action taken and can have a positive or negative outcome. It can be managed in 5 distinct ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accepting&lt;/strong&gt; a risk means there are no actions. This is a valid approach but requires identification and documentation of the risk. The acceptance of a risk has to be done by a qualified person. Real-life example: Smoking, drinking or base jumping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoiding&lt;/strong&gt; is a change of plans and not executing on a strategy, investment or software project because of the risk. Real-life example: Stick to the speed limit, not go bungee jumping&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transfer&lt;/strong&gt; of risk means another party, person or organization is taking the risk instead. Real-life example: insurance industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mitigation&lt;/strong&gt; against a risk is the most common approach. One can mitigate against the impact and or mitigate by reducing the likelihood. Real-life example: audits, backup, redundancy, error-tolerant design&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exploiting&lt;/strong&gt; is an option if the risk has a positive impact. Looking for ways to increase the likelihood and/or impact of a risk. Real-life example: using new technologies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All mentioned risk management approaches rely on a prior assessment. The assessment of the risk for an organization has to follow a structured approach.  Risk assessment and management is an essential part of security management. Security assessment methodologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CRAMM&quot;&gt;CRAMM&lt;/a&gt; contain risk assessment modules. Risk assessment methodologies like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MEHARI&quot;&gt;Mehari&lt;/a&gt; have evolved to be security assessment methodologies. A systematic approach to security risk assessment is necessary to identify security requirements and to create an effective Information Security Management System (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ISO/IEC_27001&quot;&gt;ISMS&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security risk assessments identify, quantify, and prioritize risks against defined criteria for risk management and objectives relevant to the organization.
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;symbolic picture for risk&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;when-to-run-security-risk-assessment&quot;&gt;When to run Security Risk Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a new system, software, process or partner is connected to the organization. It’s essential to understand for example what data is shared and which privileged rights are implemented. A decision has to be made conscious and has to be aligned with the risk profile of a company.
Existing assessments have to be revisited on a regular basis to adapt to the ever-evolving security threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each risk assessment has to be tailored to the subject of the assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;stories-from-the-trenches&quot;&gt;Stories from the trenches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A designer finds this new productivity tool on the internet and installs it on the company notebook. The tool turns out to be malware.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A manager is doing a test run with a new vendor and shares production data that turns out to include privacy protected data. The vendor is in a territory not bound to EU privacy laws and does not comply with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Development teams use third-party modules for a software project. One module has malicious code injected (&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/software-supply-chain-security/&quot;&gt;software supply chain attack&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A company decides to go global without a global security framework. Later a foreign branch is hacked and the HQ is affected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;example-cyber-security-risk-assessment&quot;&gt;Example Cyber Security Risk Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bank is evaluating a new Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system. The new system is a browser-based SaaS (Software as a service) solution. The new CRM software is part of a digitalization project in the bank with the purpose to reduce costs and improve customer relationship. The vendor of the SaaS solution was successfully approved after a vendor risk assessment. The contract with the SaaS provider includes SLA definitions and SLA monitoring metrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We scope this risk assessment to only look at the Data, Network and Client. People and Client hardware availability has to be covered in a disaster recovery plan and according to corporate security requirements. Customer and Support Agent interaction has to follow security approved processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-no-1-identify-assets-and-define-the-scope&quot;&gt;Step No. 1: Identify Assets and define the scope&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The identification of the assets can includes hardware, software, data, and personnel. It’s important to work with business users and management to create a list of all valuable assets. A tech person might not have all the information necessary to identify the assets or potential consequences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;It’s possible to define the scope of the assessment and recommend further assessments.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;asset table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-no-2-identify-potential-consequences&quot;&gt;Step No. 2: Identify potential consequences&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Determine what financial and reputational losses the organization would suffer if a given asset were damaged. This will later be used to determine the impact of loss or unavailability of an asset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer Data&lt;/strong&gt;
As a financial institute the partial or complete loss of customer data has legal implications and has to be reported to the authorities. The reputational consequences are a loss of trust in the organization. A full or partial data breach has legal, reputational and financial implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Client&lt;/strong&gt;
Because of the SaaS solution the agents only require a browser. Browsers have evolved into cloud-based password managers and provide access to extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Network&lt;/strong&gt;
A stable network connection with low latency is required for the SaaS solution to work. Loss of the connection means downtime for the customer support department which implies reputational consequences. Prolonged downtimes will have financial impact on the organiziation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-no-3-identify-threats&quot;&gt;Step No. 3: Identify Threats&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A threat is anything that might exploit a vulnerability to breach your security and cause harm to your assets. Threats are specific to the company and derive from the company threat assessment. A bank of a certain size is considered critical infrastructure and is facing threats from computer criminals and state players. Natural disasters are also considered a threat but out of scope for this assessment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;threat table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-no-4-identify-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;Step No. 4: Identify Vulnerabilities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step is probably one of the most challenging aspects of the security risk assessment. Vulnerability analysis requires technical understanding, up to date knowledge about the security threat landscape and the ability to tie it all together on the use case. I am giving some examples here without claim for completeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;vulnerability table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-no-5-assess-the-risk&quot;&gt;Step No. 5: Assess the risk&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk is the potential that a given threat will exploit the vulnerabilities of the environment and cause harm to one or more assets. 
It is important to document the justification or rationale for each impact assessment and probability of occurrence rating. If the conditions or environment change, the assessment might need to be revisited. The rationale helps to communicate the significance of the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Risk = Threat Likelihood x Magnitude of Impact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The likelihood of an event to occur can be defined by factoring in the capability and motivation of a threat and the existing controls to prevent a threat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Likelihood table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The definition of the impact by the value of the data or service and the impact a loss has for the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_5.png&quot; alt=&quot;Impact table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Risk model&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_6.png&quot; alt=&quot;Risk table&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting risk management plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_table_7.png&quot; alt=&quot;Risk management plan&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this simplified risk assessment we can now decide on how the risk is managed. Most organizations will try to mitigate the risk and quantification helps to justify the costs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/risk-assessment/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/risk-assessment/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GDPR, Passwords, Hashing and You</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a legal expert and this article is my interpretation of the law and personal opinion. GDPR does not contain any specifics about passwords. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-data-protection/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/security/passwords-in-online-services/&quot;&gt;UK Information Commissioner’s Office - ICO&lt;/a&gt; published a useful guide for the development of password protection systems after GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;password-systems-and-the-gdpr&quot;&gt;Password systems and the GDPR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Passwords (low-entropy secrets) play a critical role in keeping information safe. For this reason, ensuring password security is critical. GDPR not only introduces the principles of &lt;strong&gt;privacy by design&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;privacy by default&lt;/strong&gt;, but in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imperva.com/learn/data-security/gdpr-article-32/&quot;&gt;Article 32&lt;/a&gt; it also defines the obligation for data security and data loss prevention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Access to personal data is protected by passwords. In order to protect personal data, passwords have to be protected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any password system developed or deployed has to be protected against &lt;strong&gt;brute force&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;dictionary&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;guessing&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/vulnerability-disclosure-at-signup/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;credential stuffing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; attacks. The password itself is treated as personal data and requires state of the art protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly after the introduction of GDPR a German company reported a data breach in accordance with Article 33 GDRP to the authorities. During the investigation, it was discovered that the passwords have been stored in clear text. This was interpreted as a violation of Article 32 GDRP and the company was fined &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theregister.co.uk/2018/11/23/knuddels_fined_for_plain_text_passwords/&quot;&gt;EUR 20.000&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“By storing the passwords in clear text, the company knowingly violated its duty to ensure data security in the processing of personal data.” the authority said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The company wasn’t fined for the breach but because of the password storage strategy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;state-of-the-art-methods-for-password-storage&quot;&gt;State of the art methods for password storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under GDPR a strong password storage strategy is critical in mitigating data breaches. 
Hashing passwords is no longer just an option and the hashing method should be &lt;em&gt;state of the art&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Requirements for the hashing method:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The honest player needs to be able to compute a single instance of the algorithm on standard hardware for moderate costs.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The adversary should not be able to reduce costs by calculating multiple instances of the algorithm on customized hardware.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The time for calculating the hash should not depend on the length of the password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Identical input has to produce a different output (nondeterministic).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One way function&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is better than clear text but attackers have found ways around this implementation. If a couple of users were to use the same password, their hash would be identical. Multiple accounts mapped to the same hash indicate a commonly used password. With this knowledge, hackers can considerably narrow down the number of passwords used in an attack. Attackers can also utilize databases of pre-computed hashes (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rainbow_table&quot;&gt;rainbow table attacks&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The salt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Salting the input increases the complexity of the output without increasing user requirements. A salt is a fixed-length cryptographically strong value added to the input. But fixed salt strings can get exposed in a data breach and the attacker can neglect the advantage of using a salt. This implementation also produces deterministic outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BCrypt, PBKDF2 or SCrypt - key stretching&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a great improvement over the mentioned above methods but I do not recommend the commonly implemented BCrypt, PBKDF2 or SCrypt methods for newly designed systems anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;BCrypt and PBKDF2&lt;/em&gt; are key stretching or key derivation functions and do not offer memory hardness. This means those methods are CPU bound and prone to password cracking by Application Specific Integrated Circuits (ASICs). Whitepapers have emerged regarding &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usenix.org/system/files/conference/woot14/woot14-malvoni.pdf&quot;&gt;Energy-Efficient Bcrypt Cracking with Low-CostParallel Hardware&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;SCrypt&lt;/em&gt; adds memory-hard functions (MHFs). It is CPU and Memory intensive to calculate. But I see an issue with the usage in &lt;a href=&quot;https://coinpaprika.com/tag/scrypt?all=true&quot;&gt;cryptocurrencies&lt;/a&gt;. Mining solutions for SCrypt are &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptomining-blog.com/10810-new-innosilicon-a6-ltc-master-2-2-ghs-scrypt-asic-miner/&quot;&gt;available&lt;/a&gt; and these could be repurposed for &lt;em&gt;offline cracking&lt;/em&gt;. SCrypt also doesn’t give many options to configure parameters to balance parameters. In my opinion, this is an important feature to tailor the method to your use case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;argon2---appropriate-hashing&quot;&gt;Argon2 - appropriate hashing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation for a newly designed password storage system is argon2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;open source implementations in all commonly used languages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;has been around for a while&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;withstood studies to accelerate the algorithm on dedicated hardware&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;parameters to control execution time, memory requirements and degree of parallelism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;won the &lt;a href=&quot;https://password-hashing.net/&quot;&gt;Password Hashing Competition&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gdpr_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;GDPR symbolic picture&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;preventing-a-data-breach&quot;&gt;Preventing a data breach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hashing will protect passwords after a data breach. Other privacy information is usually stored in clear text.
The risk for a data breach can be reduced by implementing processes, controls, and audits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User rights management - Access control&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Privileged user monitoring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Immutable audit trail for machines and humans&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Secure archiving for forensics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data access auditing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Data discovery and classification&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rate limiting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employee background checks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encryption of private information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;evaluation-process-with-gdpr&quot;&gt;Evaluation process with GDPR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDPR changes the requirements for engineers and we need to put more thought into designing a system.
Evaluation processes and decision making has to be documented along the following criteria:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;State of the Art&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the most advanced approach and measure it against the ever-evolving cybersecurity threat landscape.
Keep on learning, educate yourself, assess risks and anticipate attacks. Be aware of threats relevant for your use case.
A successful security strategy is never “done”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Profile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Know your companies unique risk profile and customize your solutions accordingly. Risk profiles include core requirements for systems.
This profile has to be re-evaluated according to company changes or changes to the threat level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Processing Profile&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluate the nature, scope, context, and purposes of the processing of personal data. It is essential to understand what data is where and for which purpose.
Data might be the oil of the 21st century but minimizing the amount of collected data is required. Collect only data you need for business and legal reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cost&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Evaluate the costs of an implementation according to the risk profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I wanted to show how to satisfy GDRP requirements for password storage and what to take into consideration.
It’s fine to run a legacy system with BCrypt but when designing a new system we need to use technology with a high probability to stand the test of time. Or at least the next decade. It’s on us engineers to stay informed about the continuous evolution of cybersecurity threats and adapt our approach.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/gdpr-passwords-hashing-you/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/gdpr-passwords-hashing-you/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Software Supply Chain Security</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-supply-chain&quot;&gt;The Supply Chain&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software development, platform technology, and delivery pipelines are a mission-critical element in every modern enterprise - and a place for security incidents. Increased velocity in software development, delivery and the removal of manual steps create additional security risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other industries have understood the need to manage risk along the supply chain a long time ago. Documenting the origin of raw materials, testing the quality of supplied materials and ensuring the integrity of their supply chains. Examples are the medical, automotive, aerospace and mechanical engineering industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/supply_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a container harbor&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at the traditional supply chain security of the cargo industry. Threats are terrorism, theft and, piracy.
The activities to protect the supply chain include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Credentialing of participants in the supply chain&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screening and validating of the contents of cargo being shipped&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Advance notification of the contents to the destination country&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensuring the security of cargo while in-transit via the use of locks and tamper-proof seals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Real-time tracking of the cargo while in-transit via GPS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inspecting cargo on entry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing those efforts with the care being taken for the software supply chain in even big companies, illustrates the gap. Attackers have shifted their focus from operating systems and networks directly to applications and they don’t care how the weakness got there in the first place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;excuses-are-plenty---opportunities-are-rare&quot;&gt;Excuses are plenty - Opportunities are rare&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially in the startup industry, there is a lot of pressure for delivery and little for security. Customer growth, agility, automation or product delivery are the key performance indicators. &lt;strong&gt;Ain’t nobody got time for software supply chain security&lt;/strong&gt; attitude has even been seen in the fintech and medtech industry. Nobody would admit this of course. Everybody takes security serious unless it collides with the mentioned above KPIs. It’s important to explain to non-technical decision makers the importance of risk reduction in the supply chain of the software product. Leaking data and industrial espionage are just two of many threats to companies with unchecked or weak software supply chain security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attack-vectors&quot;&gt;Attack vectors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;injecting malicious code in public repositories for common libraries, modules, and images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A software project consists nowadays of up to &lt;a href=&quot;https://finance.yahoo.com/news/sonatype-reduces-licensing-risks-nuget-135123418.html&quot;&gt;90% of open source components&lt;/a&gt; and only 10% of custom code. Modern software development relies on large communities of open source developers to deliver building blocks for the companies own software product. I believe open source being superior to closed source software but companies have to understand that they can’t outsource their own risk to open source development teams and repositories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are no enforced code reviews, commit right reviews or background checks on developers in open source. Companies need to start taking responsibility for the third party software they use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malicious code has been found in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GitHub&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dockerhub&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;maven repository&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;npm&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;outdated libraries, modules, and images&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another vector is the lack of tracking for software component versions. While third-party libraries with weaknesses are disclosed and updated, it’s frightening to know that most utilizing software of the components is not updated. Known CVEs (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures) have been found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.zdnet.com/article/study-more-than-50-of-global-500-use-vulnerable-open-source-components/&quot;&gt;more than 50%&lt;/a&gt; of companies. The microservice architecture is counterproductive. Small specialized services are developed once and then left deserted for months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;third party failure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today IT companies and startups are very specialized on a core business model and outsource to SaaS providers or insource specialized software. This is understandable from an efficiency and financial perspective. One doesn’t need to reinvent the wheel. But this also means that the vendors’ security becomes the security of their own company. Data breaches happen even with the big players. (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theinquirer.net/inquirer/news/3031566/github-bug-exposed-user-passwords-in-plaintext&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://nakedsecurity.sophos.com/2018/07/03/typeform-data-breach-hits-thousands-of-survey-accounts/&quot;&gt;Typeform&lt;/a&gt;). This exposes data and user accounts without having done anything wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a breach companies struggle to determine the impact and the affected data. Remediation actions are delayed or wrongly planned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ok-what-now&quot;&gt;Ok, what now?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Companies have to understand how their respective software supply chain is structured.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pipelines and Systems need to be documented and governed.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code components should be scanned during deployment against common vulnerabilities (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Dependency_Check&quot;&gt;OWASP dependency check&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jfrog.com/xray/&quot;&gt;Jfrog X-Ray&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Access to public repositories has to be restricted and monitored. Local repositories or proxies are preferred.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vetting of components and base images is required.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software and component versions require documentation and automatic checks against CVE databases.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third party software and partners have to be checked and their own software supply security needs to be verified. Due diligence of partners must involve a security assessment. A good name or reference is not enough.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ingress and egress traffic monitoring needs to be performed on a per-host basis.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Documentation of vendors and the data that is shared with them is a must.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Deployments have to be monitored and the code change requires reference to the source code changes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The technical debt of your partner is your technical debt!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strong security controls need to be implemented across the supply chain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Detected vulnerabilities require swift remediation or whitelisting by experts as not applicable for the use case.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strengthen your QA specialists!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most important action is to raise awareness with managers and decision makers. A data leak, prolonged downtime or a company breach can bring an end to all the ambitious growth goals company founders have. IT companies need to step up their game. We owe it to our customers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/software-supply-chain-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/software-supply-chain-security/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nomos Tangente - Ref. 101</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nomos Glashütte is a German watchmaking company based in Glashütte, Saxony. The company was founded in 1990, only two months after the fall of the Berlin Wall. The designs of the collection are influenced by the minimalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bauhaus&quot;&gt;Bauhaus&lt;/a&gt; style. The absence of centuries of watchmaking experience has helped the brand to create modern and minimalist designs that are unlike anything else on the market. In 2005 Nomos started to use only inhouse manufactured movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tangente&quot;&gt;Tangente&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tangente is considered the flagship model of Nomos. The watch was introduced in 1992 and is available in multiple dimensions and special editions. The Ref. 101 is considered the classic version and comes in a 35mm size. The large lugs make up for the small diameter in contemporary standards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/101_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the nomos tangente&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch is very slender and sits very low to the wrist, an refreshing aesthetic in the times of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/rolex-explorer-II-216570/&quot;&gt;bigger contemporary watches&lt;/a&gt;. The case is light very comfortable to wear for an extended period of time. The case is polished all over. This makes the watch stand out on the wrist despite the small size as it reflects light. However, the watch attracts scratches that tarnishes the polishing. The relative softness of 316L steel does not help with this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the lugs extending far out from the case, the Tangente looks much bigger on the wrist than its 35mm diameter would indicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The watch is very versatile when it comes to strap options. Hipster suede, chill nato or business cordovan.. anything goes. The simple design helps the watch to adapt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/101_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;3d picture of the nomos tangente&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dial is made out of galvanized steel plated in silver, which gives it a nice texture when viewed from certain angles. The Tangente reacts to light in different angles. The arabic numerals and stick markers support the well spaced typography. The Nomos own design team in the hipster district of Berlin (Kreuzberg) shows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hands of the watch are all “heat-blued” and add some color to the otherwise monochrome dial. The hands are also perfectly dimensioned and pass over the respective markes without blocking the view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dial design is a distinctly Nomos one and I’m a big fan of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/101_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of myself wearing a nomos tangente&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The movement of the watch is inhouse manufactured and called α by Nomos. The design of the movement is however a manual wind ETA 7001.
The stock strap is a black Horween shell cordovan strap. The buckle is a tang-styled one with a engraved Nomos insignia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;specifications&quot;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Nomos Tangente 35 Ref. 101&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Nomos Alpha&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Material:&lt;/strong&gt; 316L Stainless Steel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Crystal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lug Width:&lt;/strong&gt; 18mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diameter/Height:&lt;/strong&gt; 35 mm/6.6 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This watch has rightly earned many awards but design is also polarizing. The minimalistic Bauhaus style doesn’t sit well with everybody.
I have worn this watch for extended times and like the varity it provides to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://inversegravity.net/tag/watch/&quot;&gt;collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/nomos-tangente-101/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/nomos-tangente-101/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>nomos</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Vulnerability Disclosure at SignUp</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-issue&quot;&gt;The Issue&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limited password portfolios of users are a security threat to all applications. I am suggesting an approach to responsibly disclose breached accounts to users during signup. This can help users to get a better understanding of the situation and hopefully motivates them to use a new password or activate two-factor authentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;e-mail-address&quot;&gt;E-Mail Address&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Services require a customer to provide an E-Mail address and a password during signup. The E-Mail address is essential for login, password recovery and all communication between service provider and customer. &lt;a href=&quot;http://radicati.com/wp/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Email-Statistics-Report-2015-2019-Executive-Summary.pdf&quot;&gt;Consumer research&lt;/a&gt; shows an average of 1.7 to 1.9 E-Mail accounts per user. This means that there is a high probability that a user will use the same address over years and for multiple service signups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;password&quot;&gt;Password&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The password should be distinctive per service but &lt;a href=&quot;https://securingtomorrow.mcafee.com/consumer/consumer-threat-notices/security-world-password-day/&quot;&gt;31% of customers&lt;/a&gt; use only two to three different passwords. The question is also how different those passwords are. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cyclonis.com/report-83-percent-users-surveyed-use-same-password-multiple-sites/&quot;&gt;83% of users&lt;/a&gt; admit to re-using passwords. Password managers are very helpful to provide unique passwords for each account but hardly anybody uses them if not forced by company policy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-breaches&quot;&gt;Data Breaches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies get hacked or information is unintentionally exposed to the public. Data sets with millions of accounts have been seen in the wild. Clear text passwords or hashing without salt are not uncommon in user databases. Attackers use the information of those exposed data sets in attacks against other services. The known E-Mail address and password combinations are used for account takeovers. The method is called &lt;strong&gt;credential stuffing attack&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security aware users counter this with the use of password managers and two-factor authentication, but the majority of users doesn’t. Service providers are afraid to enforce hard requirements in fear of customers not signing up or the usability of a service degrading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/pki_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a keyboard&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;myself&quot;&gt;Myself&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I use the same E-Mail address since 2005. The address has been leaked in the following hacks:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;verifications.io&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In February 2019, the email address validation service verifications.io suffered a data breach. Discovered by Bob Diachenko and Vinny Troia, the breach was due to the data being stored in a MongoDB instance left publicly facing without a password and resulted in 763 million unique email addresses being exposed. Many records within the data also included additional personal attributes such as names, phone numbers, IP addresses, dates of birth and genders. No passwords were included in the data. The Verifications.io website went offline during the disclosure process, although an archived copy remains viewable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Dates of birth, Email addresses, Employers, Genders, Geographic locations, IP addresses, Job titles, Names, Phone numbers, Physical addresses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tumblr&lt;/strong&gt;
In early 2013, Tumblr suffered a data breach which resulted in the exposure of over 65 million accounts. The data was later put up for sale on a dark market website and included email addresses and passwords stored as salted SHA1 hashes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Email addresses, Passwords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MySpace&lt;/strong&gt;
In approximately 2008, MySpace suffered a data breach that exposed almost 360 million accounts. In May 2016 the data was offered up for sale on the “Real Deal” dark market website and included email addresses, usernames and SHA1 hashes of the first 10 characters of the password converted to lowercase and stored without a salt. The exact breach date is unknown, but analysis of the data suggests it was 8 years before being made public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Email addresses, Passwords, Usernames&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/strong&gt; 
In May 2016, LinkedIn had 164 million email addresses and passwords exposed. Originally hacked in 2012, the data remained out of sight until being offered for sale on a dark market site 4 years later. The passwords in the breach were stored as SHA1 hashes without salt, the vast majority of which were quickly cracked in the days following the release of the data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Email addresses, Passwords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dropbox&lt;/strong&gt; 
In mid-2012, Dropbox suffered a data breach which exposed the stored credentials of tens of millions of their customers. In August 2016, they forced password resets for customers they believed may be at risk. A large volume of data totaling over 68 million records was subsequently traded online and included email addresses and salted hashes of passwords (half of them SHA1, half of them bcrypt).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Email addresses, Passwords&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disqus&lt;/strong&gt;
In October 2017, the blog commenting service Disqus announced they’d suffered a data breach. The breach dated back to July 2012 but wasn’t identified until years later when the data finally surfaced. The breach contained over 17.5 million unique email addresses and usernames. Users who created logins on Disqus had salted SHA1 hashes of passwords whilst users who logged in via social providers only had references to those accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compromised data: Email addresses, Passwords, Usernames&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My E-Mail address was also in the Collection #1. This data set contains multiple data breaches and almost 2.7 billion records including 773 million unique email addresses alongside passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not in possession of all breached databases but the service &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/&quot;&gt;’;–have i been pwned?&lt;/a&gt; does a great job of collecting this information. HIBP allows to check E-Mail address via their web interface and with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/API/Consumers&quot;&gt;public API&lt;/a&gt; against those databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclosure-to-the-user&quot;&gt;Disclosure to the user&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At signup, the customer provides his E-Mail address. We can check this address with the API of HIBP (make sure the users agrees to the third party sharing of his data) for prior exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the potential positive results are shared with them we can make suggestions on how to improve the account security (eg. two-factor authentication). Service providers can also require tougher security features on the account. This could be a more complex password policy or a more secure policy regarding changes to the account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need to involve non-technical people to improve security. Disclosing information to users about past breaches is a great way to help them to harden their account and change behavior regarding password recycling. Service providers should not shy away from this and instead make users understand that security is taken seriously in the service they are signing up for. Building trust in a zero trust world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/vulnerability-disclosure-at-signup/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/vulnerability-disclosure-at-signup/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
