<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>blog about technology, security, data-privacy and gear</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 17:59:09 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 17:59:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security Awareness - Security Culture</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;many-organizations-incorrectly-assume-that-a-team-of-security-experts-can-protect-the-other-99-of-the-companys-workforce-from-exposing-critical-information-to-malicious-external-actors&quot;&gt;Many organizations incorrectly assume that a team of security experts can protect the other 99% of the company’s workforce from exposing critical information to malicious external actors.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-dangerous-mindset-persists-in-many-technical-product-and-development-teams-too-and-members-take-it-for-granted-that-the-security-team-will-keep-them-out-of-trouble&quot;&gt;This dangerous mindset persists in many technical product and development teams too, and members take it for granted that the security team will keep them out of trouble.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the robust security posture of an enterprise doesn’t only consist of obvious components like policies, operational controls, work rules, monitoring tools, and a team of security specialists; the most critical factor is the daily informed decision making of employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security awareness as a concept aims at employees knowing about these procedures, rules, and touchpoints with the security experts. Security culture, however, goes beyond that and emphasizes a healthy mix of knowledge and follow-through by all members of an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture of a hackers hiding&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we want to take a look at some examples of how to increase awareness and, more specifically, create an impactful cybersecurity culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership---top-down-approach&quot;&gt;Leadership - Top-Down Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant shifts in an organization start at the highest level; the support of the executive team is, thereforei, essential in building a security culture. The top management has to communicate cybersecurity as an organization-wide priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular reporting regarding the security situation of the organization and clear communication about the benefits of initiatives will help to build trust between the security team and management. Face to face meetings help to clearly explain why security matters to the success of the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Middle managers work directly with employees and are naturally an essential driver of security culture. By properly explaining requirements to their team and leading by example, team leads will get the security mindset transported to all departments. Getting middle management on board with security has a significant effect on cultural change. They are the multipliers of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’ve seen a lot of incidents where the management says that cybersecurity is important, but then they turn around and ask for exceptions—and that is the death knell of any cybersecurity program.”
    —Rob Clyde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An “we are in this together” security mentality is achieved by embedding a vision and mission with leaders. This gives all employees direction on what they need to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-and-awareness&quot;&gt;Training and Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security training is labor-intensive but an essential effort for growing and maintaining a security culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educating the work-force requires different approaches depending on the specific needs of the target group. For example, it makes sense to run all newcomers through a basic security program with information on common social engineering attacks like phishing or malware, introducing them to secure behavior expectations, and how to report an incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tailored training for development teams can be, for example, introducing them to the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/threat-landscape/&quot;&gt;Threat Landscape&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/owasp-top-10/&quot;&gt;OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks&lt;/a&gt;, or maybe refresh some &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-history-basics/&quot;&gt;crypto&lt;/a&gt; knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Departments, like HR, on the other hand, require awareness of the importance of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/personnel-security/&quot;&gt;Personnel Security&lt;/a&gt; and how they can help with keeping the workplace safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transporting knowledge can be done in workshops, via videos or, maybe by introducing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3444488/equifax-data-breach-faq-what-happened-who-was-affected-what-was-the-impact.html&quot;&gt;famous data-leak case&lt;/a&gt; to a broader group in the organization and how it could have prevented by aligning with the policy framework. Showing that threats are close is an excellent way to encourage employees to follow security policies and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security teams should also consider collecting feedback after training to ensure the continuous improvement of the education program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture with data privacy message &quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;secure-development-lifecycle&quot;&gt;Secure Development Lifecycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secure from the start to the end and repeat. SDL is elemental to a sustainable security culture since it enables security to be integrated from the early stages of the development processes, and not as an afterthought at the very end of the delivery pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a product through SDL will build trustworthy solutions that have fewer security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of most industry SDL implementations is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/securityengineering/sdl/practices&quot;&gt;Microsoft program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SDL is sustainable security culture in action and answers the how to embed security culture in development and product teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rewards&quot;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate success and recognize the people that do the right thing for security. Positive reinforcement is an excellent practice to support the effort to build a community of security-aware employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By adding security-related goals to performance reviews, will make reasonable security practices mandatory. A positive message to the entire organization can be sent by giving employees with good risk awareness more freedom when making decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Distributing the responsibility for security and giving more freedom is a significant goal of security culture and therefore has to be embedded in the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture with data privacy message &quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automation&quot;&gt;Automation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations can support employees by adding security automation to software development and daily processes. This will not only make the employee’s job more comfortable but can also significantly improve the security posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of good automation are security scanners, static code analysis, or automatically generated governance documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security culture is an integral part of a broader corporate culture that encourages people to make correct decisions in alignment with the organization’s security policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a long-term and never-ending endeavor to break down silos. A sense of ownership needs to be communicated companywide and not end at the security department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees have to be seen as assets in this approach; they are the first line of defense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/security-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/security-culture/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security Awareness - Threat Landscape</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;information-security-awareness-focuses-on-raising-consciousness-regarding-risks-from-the-continuous-evolving-threats-to-organizations-businesses-and-individuals&quot;&gt;Information security awareness focuses on raising consciousness regarding risks from the continuous evolving threats to organizations, businesses, and individuals.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;attackers-evolve-their-capabilities-and-develop-more-technically-advanced-attack-methods-and-are-acting-on-more-diverse-motives&quot;&gt;Attackers evolve their capabilities and develop more technically advanced attack methods, and are acting on more diverse motives.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goals of security awareness is to raise conscious with everyone that they are vulnerable to the challenges in today’s threat landscape, change human risk behaviors, and implement a security culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hacker_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of ants&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, we take a look at threat actors and attacks to provide an overview of the current threat landscape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;threat-actors&quot;&gt;Threat Actors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A threat actor is a person or entity that is responsible for an event that impacts the safety or security of another entity. The term is used to describe the individuals and groups that perform malicious attacks against organizations of various types and sizes. Actors are categorized as external or internal an can be intentional or unintentional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following categories are a general overview. Threat actors are in reality more complex in their motivation and backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;hacktivists&quot;&gt;Hacktivists&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hacktivism is mainly portrayed as the evolution of meatspace civil disobedience into cyberspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The common motivation is the fight against censorship and the support for the freedom of information but some hacktivists work for personal and or political gains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typically hacktivists see themselves as vigilantes who use hacking to enact social justice and policy change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;industrial-espionage&quot;&gt;Industrial Espionage&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Industrial espionage aims at stealing intellectual property, data, and secrets to use them for a competitive advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actors in this category are usually well-financed and use a mix of cyber and physical actions to achieve their goals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hacker_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a hacker building tool&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;organized-crime&quot;&gt;Organized Crime&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Criminals are motivated by making money. The digital equivalent of kidnapping or robbery offers greater scalability and much lower risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The organized crime has been quick in adapting themselves to the opportunities of making money with online activities. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ransomware&quot;&gt;Ransomeware&lt;/a&gt; and cryptojacking allow criminals to hide their identity and digital currencies make the laundering of money risk free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;insider-threats&quot;&gt;Insider Threats&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The malicious intent of employees can have a devastating impact on the security posture of an organization. Valid accounts and knowledge of applied controls make it difficult to detect harmful actions or distinguish them from regular work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Insider threats can be motivated by revenge, competition, money, or just by opportunity. Negligence or incompetence of employees can cause similar outcomes to the actions of a malicious actor inside the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;nation-states&quot;&gt;Nation States&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;State-backed hackers are not exclusively focused on hacking into military systems. Nation-state attacks have been documented against critical infrastructures like financial institutes or energy providers with the intent to destabilize another country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With almost unlimited financial potential these attackers use sophisticated techniques to disrupt organizations by leaking confidential information or attacking the availability of critical systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-attacks&quot;&gt;Common Attacks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of attack methods that are a threat to organizations and individuals working in both public and private sectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;distributed-denial-of-service-ddos&quot;&gt;Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DDoS attacks target the availability of systems. Its effectiveness is based on the coordinated usage of many computer which act in sync to attack a single endpoint. DDoS attacks try to exhaust the resources of systems by flooding them with requests. As a result, legitimate requests can no longer be answered or at least the service becomes too slow to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attack is executed from many different IP addresses to prevent blacklisting and therefore distributed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;malware&quot;&gt;Malware&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malware or malicious software is intentionally developed to cause damage to a computer, clients, or network. Malware comes in various types including worms, viruses, trojan horses, ransomware, adware, backdoors, and spyware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malware targets the weaknesses of other software systems or relies on users to install them by pretending to be regular software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced malware will try to conceal itself by using polymorphic approaches. This means that the signature of such software will mutate over time, making it difficult to detect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/hacker_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a video game&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;advanced-persistent-threat-apt&quot;&gt;Advanced Persistent Threat (APT)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This term describes a targeted attack against an organization or business with defined goals. Operators executing the attack have a full spectrum of techniques at their disposal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These include open-source or commercial computer intrusion technologies, but can also extend to a state financed intelligence and intrusion program. APTs use continuous monitoring and interaction to achieve defined objectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;APT attacks are coordinated human activities, rather than the execution of automated code. The operators have a specific objective and are organized, motivated, skilled, and potentially well funded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;phishing&quot;&gt;Phishing&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is an attempt to gather sensitive information such as email addresses and passwords by disguising oneself as a entity of trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phishing is a social engineering technique used to deceive users. Users are lured by communications purporting to be from trusted parties such as social web sites, auction sites, banks, online payment processors or IT administrators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While phishing describes a broad and automated attack, the so called spear-phishing is a customized attack on a specific employee or organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gathering-threat-intelligence&quot;&gt;Gathering Threat Intelligence&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security teams need to be proactive and improve their ability to properly defend themselves against current threats to the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developing a detailed threat profile helps organizations with a clear illustration of the threats that they might face and supports an appropriate and tailored security program.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/threat-landscape/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/threat-landscape/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>System Architecture - Shift To The Client</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-network-dependency-of-an-terminal-user-of-the-70s-is-surprisingly-familiar-to-a-mobile-phone-user-in-the-2020s-without-a-connection-to-the-network-and-the-centralized-server-infrastructure-the-applications-are-not-working&quot;&gt;The network dependency of an terminal user of the 70s is surprisingly familiar to a mobile phone user in the 2020s. Without a connection to the network and the centralized server infrastructure, the applications are not working.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;having-its-roots-in-the-thin-clients-of-mainframe-multi-user-systems-the-server-centric-approach-was-challenged-by-the-emergence-of-powerful-personal-computers-in-the-80s-only-to-become-the-de-facto-standard-once-again-with-the-smartphone-revolution&quot;&gt;Having its roots in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Thin_client&quot;&gt;thin clients&lt;/a&gt; of mainframe multi-user systems, the server-centric approach was challenged by the emergence of powerful personal computers in the 80s, only to become the de facto standard once again with the smartphone revolution.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the recent advances in privacy laws and regulations, we might see another shift to the client as the place of data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;client-server-architecture&quot;&gt;Client Server Architecture&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client-server model has two roles: the service user (client) and the service provider (server). The client requests and the server provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the design process of a client-server application, it is decided which parts of the task should be executed on the client, and which on the server. This decision can affect the robustness and security of the application as a whole. This will also have an effect on the cost of future modifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;control room&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mobile-applications&quot;&gt;Mobile Applications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early smartphones had limited storage capacity and processing power. Hence mobile application development focused heavily on degrading the smartphone to a pure front-end experience while scalable backend systems provided computational power and storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Business interests like analyzing usage patterns or digital rights management further pushed the server-centric agenda of mobile application architecture. End-users received device independence and cloud storage in return for giving up data to organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today companies implement server-centric architecture without a second thought and mobile application development is mostly reduced to work fancy UX design and backend API integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/smartphone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;control room&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be time to re-think this approach since privacy laws emphasize user rights over company interests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But enough of the theory and let’s look at a mobile application in the default server-centric setup, the privacy law implications and how it could be transformed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;symptom-checker-app-10&quot;&gt;Symptom Checker App 1.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A symptom checker is the attempt to replace a doctor visit with an algorithm supported self-diagnosis. After providing some base information like the age and answering a couple of questions, the diagnosis is made. I will not go into the reliability of this kind of diagnosis but rather focus on the technical implementation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average symptom checker takes user input and sends it to a backend server where the data is processed in clear text and the results are stored. This means that the correlation between medical and personal data is possible for anyone with access (intended or not) to those systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data cluster of a symptom checker is considered sensitive personal data and is located in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-9-gdpr/&quot;&gt;highest data protection category&lt;/a&gt;. Appropriate technical and organizational measures have to be implemented to satisfy privacy laws like GDPR. This will be challenging for small to medium-sized organizations, especially when utilizing cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shift-to-the-client&quot;&gt;Shift To The Client&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handheld devices are also rapidly catching up to desktop computers in terms of computing power and memory. While the performance gap will never be completely closed, the additional abilities of smartphones open up the possibility for more flexibility in system design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So the question is how a different approach could look like and where to make the trade-offs? For an understanding of the future, I suggest looking to the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 80s the PC revolution set the trend from server-centric to client-centric. The mainframe was forecasted to be replaced by personal computers with locally installed business logic. The only thing a centralized server was required for was the sharing of files and as a backup solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;symptom-checker-app-20&quot;&gt;Symptom Checker App 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The algorithm behind a symptom checker is reflected in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_tree&quot;&gt;decision tree&lt;/a&gt; since it only contains conditional control statements. It is therefore small in size and could easily be executed on a smartphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By creating an application framework for different downloadable decision trees it is possible to run the logic entirely on the client and reduce the server involvement of a symptom checker app to that of a simple file service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No critical data would be centralized processed or stored. The user will stay in control and can make a conscious decision about donating data to improve the app or share the results with others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest, most users don’t care or know whether the application they are using runs locally or remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s the responsibility of architects and engineers to make good decisions. Privacy laws force us to think about the data criticality and consider alternative approaches to the well-known default of server-centric applications.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/privacy-client-shift/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/privacy-client-shift/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>GDPR - The Minimum</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;entrepreneurs-are-busy-people-having-to-distribute-their-precious-time-between-technical-implementation-marketing-and-monetization-data-privacy-is-not-very-high-on-the-list-of-things-that-need-to-get-done-but-the-gdpr-knows-no-mercy-or-the-concept-of-a-test-or-beta-phase&quot;&gt;Entrepreneurs are busy people having to distribute their precious time between technical implementation, marketing, and monetization. Data privacy is not very high on the list of things that need to get done, but the GDPR knows no mercy or the concept of a test or beta phase.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;as-soon-as-the-data-of-real-people-is-processed-the-rules-of-gdpr-apply-looking-into-data-privacy-in-the-early-stages-of-a-venture-prevents-bad-decisions-and-can-ultimately-shape-a-more-sustainable-business-plan&quot;&gt;As soon as the data of real people is processed, the rules of GDPR apply. Looking into data privacy in the early stages of a venture prevents bad decisions and can ultimately shape a more sustainable business plan.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this guide, I want to provide basic requirements and actions for young businesses to avoid privacy debt. Ignoring GDPR responsibilities can result in fines, invalidate the business case, leave organizations open to legal action, and negatively affect the credibility of the startup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-this-is-important&quot;&gt;Why this is important&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; became enforceable on 25 May of 2018 and is a regulation for all member states of the EU. It affects all organizations that collect data from EU residents and has become a model for many national laws outside of the EU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Violators of the GDPR may be fined up to €20 million or up to 4% of the annual turnover of the business. Solid investors will check if the paperwork of a startup includes the necessary documents regarding data privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GDPR compliance is an advantage, adding value to the business and giving customers the security that their rights are taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gdpr.png&quot; alt=&quot;gdpr is here to stay&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lawyer-up&quot;&gt;Lawyer up&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GDPR was written by lawyers and is filled with legal terms. To understand it requires to decipher the language and terms. Here are some basic explanations for common wording in the data privacy regulation law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Subjects&lt;/strong&gt; are individuals. The natural person whose data is being processed. This can be a customer or an employee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Controller&lt;/strong&gt; describes the entity that “determines the purpose, condition, and means” of the processing of personal data. This is the entrepreneurs’ startup or a small company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Processor&lt;/strong&gt; is the entity that processes data on behalf of the Data Controller. Sometimes companies are the Controller and Processor at the same time, but the Processor role can also be outsourced to a third party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Data&lt;/strong&gt; is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person. Examples are email addresses, names, birth dates, financial data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sensitive Personal Data&lt;/strong&gt; is a set of “special categories” that must be treated with extra caution. This category includes racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health data, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/personnel_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;welcome&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-privacy-mindset&quot;&gt;Data Privacy Mindset&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the right approach, and by following a few rules, it is possible for small businesses to implement a robust strategy for data privacy. Collecting data of users is a responsibility that startups and entrepreneurs need to prioritize. The following points are by no means a GDRP compliance guide but a good foundation to build on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data classification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An excellent way to start the process is by performing &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/data-classification/&quot;&gt;data classification&lt;/a&gt;. This must involve the data directly requested from users (e.g. name, email address, day of birth, password) and also data that is collected during the use of a service (e.g. log files, browser information, IP address). Documenting the categories of all data collected is the base for the next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data flow&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data flow of data provides the ability to implement appropriate protective measures. Those can be technical, organizational, or contractual. Documentation of where data is stored and which services are involved is essential. Data classification and data flow documentation underline the purpose of data processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-party screening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can’t outsource risk nor responsibility. Startups need to choose third-party services not only by features but also with regards to their data privacy policy. A list of all service providers of a company has to be compiled, and the data and data categories shared with them have to be documented. The data flow diagram reveals what data is shared with which provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparency and consent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personal data can only be processed and stored with the consent of the user. The purpose of the data collection has to be made clear to the user, and any change to it requires new consent. Being transparent about data processing is a significant goal of the GDPR. Creating a transparent message of how customer data will be used builds company integrity and emphasizes the commitment to GDPR compliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Point of Contact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customers have the right to request information about their data usage (data subject access requests) and can also request the erasure of their data. Every data processor needs to provide, therefore, a point of contact. Please keep in mind to properly authenticate a person before handing out information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-newsletter-example&quot;&gt;The Newsletter Example&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our example startup develops a mobile application and has a promotional website where interested people can signup for a newsletter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Operating a website and a newsletter are potent tools to build and maintain relationships with customers. But it requires a comprehensive &lt;strong&gt;privacy policy&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;user consent&lt;/strong&gt; as personal data is being collected. The involvement of any &lt;strong&gt;third-party&lt;/strong&gt; has to be disclosed to the customer as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s recap. The collection and processing of data from EU residents require the following disclosure of information:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What data is processed? Just the email address, or is the startup collecting more information like IP address, country, and gender?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of the collection? In our case, this is market analysis, sending out newsletters and maybe selecting early adopters for the application. It’s essential to be specific about the purpose, and changes to the purpose require additional consent.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The involvement of third parties has to be disclosed to the user. Which other companies receive the email address? Where is the data stored and processed?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How can the user contact the data processor and request the erasure of the data? Keep in mind that this includes the deletion of the data from third-parties.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applied-data-privacy-for-the-newsletter&quot;&gt;Applied Data Privacy for the Newsletter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Draft a comprehensive yet simple Privacy Policy and make it accessible to your users. With the collection of the above information, it will be easy to meet the obligations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following information has to be included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What personal information you collect&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What you use it for&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whether you use third-party service&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The controls users have and how they can get into contact&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The privacy policy is a passive document that gives information to the interested user, consent, on the other hand, is an explicit affirmative action that signifies agreement to the processing of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implied consent is no longer an option. Consent under GDPR has to be expressed - to ask for consent; the user has to understand the question and implication and then make a genuine choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an appropriate example of newsletter signup. The user is made aware of the purpose, and a link to the privacy policy is provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/consent.png&quot; alt=&quot;good consent&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following example is non-compliant with GDPR. It implies consent to the processing activities, and the user is not made aware of what the signup means, what the data is used for or how to get more information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/consent2.png&quot; alt=&quot;bad consent&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rights and freedoms of the user are violated by providing a non-transparent signup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a good foundation, it is possible to gradually mature the data privacy processes and supporting documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Writing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-30-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Record of processing activities&lt;/a&gt;, performing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-35-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Data protection impact assessment&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-36-gdpr&quot;&gt;consulting with the authorities&lt;/a&gt; are the next steps a company needs to take in accordance with GDPR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data privacy is never done but instead a continuous process and has to be part of the DNA of any successful company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/gdpr-minimum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/gdpr-minimum/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>TCP/IP - Internet Protocol Suite</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;the-internet-protocol-suite-is-commonly-known-as-tcpip-because-of-the-central-protocols-in-the-suite-transmission-control-protocol-tcp-and-internet-protocol-ip&quot;&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite is commonly known as TCP/IP because of the central protocols in the suite: Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and Internet Protocol (IP).&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;tcpip-is-the-foundation-of-all-global-internet-communication-and-dominates-networks-around-the-world-the-technical-standards-are-maintained-by-the-internet-engineering-task-force-ietf&quot;&gt;TCP/IP is the foundation of all global internet communication and dominates networks around the world. The technical standards are maintained by the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF).&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite predates the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/osi-model/&quot;&gt;OSI Reference Model&lt;/a&gt; which is a more comprehensive framework for general networking systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP originates from research conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DARPA&quot;&gt;DARPA&lt;/a&gt; in the 1960s. The design included a fundamental change to existing protocols as the network would only provide functions to efficiently transmitting and routing traffic between end nodes and that all other intelligence would be located at the edge of the network. This design is known as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/End-to-end_principle&quot;&gt;end-to-end principle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;computer racks&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1982 the US Department of Defense declared TCP/IP as the standard for all computer networking and Universities followed in the same year. The promotion of the protocol by large corporations like IBM and DEC led to increasing commercial use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dominance of TCP/IP as the standard for network communication was cemented when the University of California, Berkeley placed the TCP/IP code developed for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BSD_UNIX&quot;&gt;BSD UNIX&lt;/a&gt; into the public domain in 1989. More and more vendors included the code in commercial software releases and more people joined Internet protocol suite based networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;layers-of-tcpip&quot;&gt;Layers of TCP/IP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The defining specification of the suite is found in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1122&quot;&gt;RFC 1122&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc1123&quot;&gt;RFC 1123&lt;/a&gt;. A four-layer model is outlined as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_01.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this layer applications or processes, create user data and communicate this data to other applications on the same host or a remote one. The applications make use of the services provided by the underlying lower layers, especially the transport layer which provides reliable or unreliable communication protocols to other processes. Application architecture is characterized by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Client%E2%80%93server_model&quot;&gt;client-server model&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer computing&lt;/a&gt;. This is the layer in which all application protocols, such as SMTP, FTP, SSH, HTTPS, operate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The transport layer performs host-to-host communication on local or remote networks. The two primary protocols in this layer are the simplex connectionless UDP or User Datagram Protocol and the full-duplex connection-oriented TCP or Transmission Control Protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data exchange between two systems on this layer is performed via ports. Both TCP and UDP support 65536 ports which are just an address number that both ends of the communication link agree to use when transferring data on the transport layer. A single IP address can support multiple simultaneous communications by utilizing multiple ports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at TCP which is connection-oriented and performs a handshake process to establish a communication session. The three-way-handshake is a prerequisite for data transmission between server and client and goes as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The client sends a &lt;strong&gt;SYN&lt;/strong&gt; (synchronize) flagged packet to the server. The server responds with a &lt;strong&gt;SYN/ACK&lt;/strong&gt; (synchronize and acknowledge) flagged packet back to the client. The client sends an &lt;strong&gt;ACK&lt;/strong&gt; (acknowledge) flagged packet back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two methods to disconnect a TCP session once a communication session is complete. The most common one is to use a &lt;strong&gt;FIN&lt;/strong&gt; (finish) flagged packet which both sides of the communication have to send once all data is transmitted. The other side has to reply with an &lt;strong&gt;ACK&lt;/strong&gt; flagged packet. It takes 4 packets to gracefully shut down a TCP session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alternative disconnect method is to send a &lt;strong&gt;RST&lt;/strong&gt; (reset) flagged packet, this causes an abrupt and immediate termination of the session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UDP, the other player in the transport layer, is a connectionless best-effort protocol and offers no error detection and correction. It also doesn’t require a pre-established session and is therefore considered unreliable. With its low overhead, it can transmit data quickly but should only be used for non-essential data delivery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a city by night&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internet&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol or IP operates on the Network layer of the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/osi-model/&quot;&gt;OSI Model&lt;/a&gt;. IP provides route addressing for data packets and it is this route addressing that makes TCP/IP the foundation of global internet communications because it provides a way to identify and prescribe transmission paths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol is connectionless and acts as an unreliable datagram service. It doesn’t guarantee that packets are delivered in the right order or tht they are delivered at all. Only when TCP and IP work together a reliable and controlled communication session is established.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv4&quot;&gt;IPv4&lt;/a&gt; is the most widely used version of the Internet Protocol. A new version known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IPv6_address&quot;&gt;IPv6&lt;/a&gt; is being adopted for private and public network use and offers new features and new challenges for Administrators and Security Engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ICMP or Internet Control Message Protocol is also working on the Internet layer and provides a way to determine the health of a network or a specific link. Commands like ping, traceroute and other network management tools utilize ICMP to send echo packets to remote hosts. With ICMP it is possible to determine whether a remote system is online, how fast it responds and if intermediary systems support the communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many attacks exploited the features of ICMP in forms of denial-of-service (DoS) attacks like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ping_flood&quot;&gt;ping floods&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Smurf_attack&quot;&gt;smurf attacks&lt;/a&gt;. This has affected the way how networks handle ICMP today, resulting in many limiting the use of ICMP or the throughput rate of this protocol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Group Management Protocol or IGMP allows systems to support multicasting in an IPv4 network. Multicast management on IPv6 networks is handled by Multicast Listener Discovery (MLD). Both protocols support the transmission of data to multiple specific recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link layer defines the networking methods within the scope of the local network link on which hosts communicate. This layer includes the protocols used to describe the local network topology and the interfaces needed for the transmission of Internet layer datagrams to next-neighbor hosts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ARP or Address Resolution Protocol is enabling the interoperability of logical and physical addressing of interfaces. It resolves IP addresses into Medica Access Control (MAC) addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traffic on a network is directed from its source to its destination using MAC addresses. ARP uses broadcasting and caching to perform the intended purpose. If the cache doesn’t contain the necessary information, an ARP request is broadcasted into the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP follows principles that helped the model to adapt to new requirements and stay meaningful. Robustness, Adaptability and Continuous Evolution are core values mentioned in the defining RFCs of the Internet Protocol Suite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But TCP/IP vulnerabilities are numerous and range from improperly implemented stacks in operating systems to buffer overflows, denial-of-service or spoofing attacks. It is also subject to passive attacks via monitoring traffic patterns or sniffing the content of communication by man-in-the-middle attacks. Deep knowledge of TCP/IP is a must for any security professional to mitigate the risk of attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet Protocol Suite is the underlying fabric of the internet and I could only provide a quick overview in this posting. Understanding the basics of networking should be in the interests of any Internet user.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/tcp-ip-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/tcp-ip-model/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OSI Model - Open Systems Interconnection</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;to-properly-implement-secure-design-principles-in-network-architectures-it-is-important-to-fully-understand-all-of-the-technologies-involved-in-computer-communications-from-software-and-hardware-to-encryption-and-beyond-there-are-many-standards-to-know-and-procedures-to-follow-the-osi-model-has-become-a-common-reference-against-which-all-protocols-can-be-compared&quot;&gt;To properly implement secure design principles in network architectures, it is important to fully understand all of the technologies involved in computer communications. From software and hardware to encryption and beyond, there are many standards to know and procedures to follow. The OSI model has become a common reference against which all protocols can be compared.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual OSI protocol was developed to establish a common communication structure for all computer systems but was never widely adopted. Instead, the theory behind the protocol serves nowadays as a theoretical model for how protocols should function in an ideal world on ideal hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Systems Interconnection (OSI) model is a guiding principle in networking and related protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Communication between computers and over networks is made possible by protocols which are simply a set of rules and restrictions that define how data is transmitted over a network medium (whether that connection is electrons over copper, photons over fiber, or radio signals through the air).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;light shining from fiber cables&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-layers-of-the-model&quot;&gt;The Layers of the Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The model partitions a communication system into seven abstraction layers. A layer serves the layer above it and is served by the layer below it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understanding the functions and responsibilities of each layer of the OSI Model is essential to understand how network communications function, how attacks work, and how to security can be implemented to protect network communications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_table_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-7-application&quot;&gt;Layer 7: Application&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Application layer allows applications to communicate with the protocol stack. It ensures that sufficient resources are available to support the requested communication and is responsible for interfacing user applications, network services, or the operating system with the protocol stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The application is not located in this layer but rather the protocols and services required for it to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-6-presentation&quot;&gt;Layer 6: Presentation&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 6 imposes common or standardized structure and formatting rules onto the data from the application layer. It acts as an interface between applications and the network and therefore allows various applications to interact over a network. It does so by ensuring that the data formats are supported by both systems. Most data and file formats operate within this layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formats include support for images, video, sound, digital rights, documents, emails, or text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-5-session&quot;&gt;Layer 5: Session&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Session layer is establishing, maintaining, and terminating communication sessions between two computers. It manages dialogue discipline and control (simplex (one-way), half-duplex (two-way one-directional), full-duplex (two-way bi-directional)), establishes checkpoints for recovery, and can retransmit PDUs that have failed to the Transport layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-4-transport&quot;&gt;Layer 4: Transport&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This layer is responsible for managing the integrity of a connection and controlling the session. It accepts a PDU (Protocol Data Unit) from the Session layer and converts into segments. The Transport layer defines the rules of a session, how much data a segment can contain, how to verify the segment integrity, and how to determine if data has been lost. Rules are established through a handshake process (SYNC/ACK three-way handshake for TCP/IP).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 4 establishes a logical connection between two devices and provides end-to-end transport services for data delivery. Mechanisms in this layer include sequencing, segmentation, error checking, controlling the data flow, error correction, multiplexing, and optimization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-3-network&quot;&gt;Layer 3: Network&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Network layer is responsible for adding routing and addressing information to the data. It accepts the segments from the Transport layer and adds information to it to create a packet. The packer includes the source and destination IP address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Layer 3 is responsible for providing routing and delivery information, but it’s not responsible for verifying guaranteed delivery. It also manages error detection and traffic control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Routers are an example of network hardware devices functioning on this layer. Routers can determine the best logical path for transmission of packets based on speed, hops, preferences or priority. They use the destination IP address to guide the transmission of packets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Non-IP Protocols are protocols that serve as an alternative to IP at the OSI Network layer. With the dominance of TCP/IP, non-IP protocols have become limited to special-purpose networks. Recognizable non-IP protocols are AppleTalk, NetBEUI or IPX&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-2-data-link&quot;&gt;Layer 2: Data Link&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Data Link layer is formatting the packet from the Network layer into the proper format for transmission. The proper format is determined by the hardware and network technology. Ethernet remains a common Data Link layer technology in modern networks. Within the Data Link layer resides the protocol that converts the packet into a properly formated frame. Once the frame is formatted, it’s sent to the Physical layer for transmission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the processing performed on this layer includes adding the hardware source and destination address to the frame. This address is the Media Access Control (MAC) address. Network hardware functioning on layer 2 are switches and bridges. Switches support MAC-based traffic routing and receive a frame on one port and sent it out to another port based on the destination MAC address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;layer-1-physical&quot;&gt;Layer 1: Physical&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Physical layer is responsible for receiving bits from the physical connection medium and converting them into a frame to be used by the Data Link layer. It also works the other way around by converting the frame into bits for transmission over the physical medium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This layer contains the device drivers that tell the protocol how to employ the hardware for transmission and reception of bits. Located in this layer are electrical specifications, interface standards, and protocols. Layer 1 controls throughput rates, manages line noise and medium access, handles synchronization and also determines whether to use digital or analog signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hardware devices that function at this layer are network interface cards (NIC), hubs or repeaters. These devices perform hardware-based signal operations. One example is a network hub that is sending a signal from one connection port to all other ports. A network repeater is amplifying a signal to support greater transmission distances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;layers of pancakes&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encapsulation-and-de-encapsulation&quot;&gt;Encapsulation and De-encapsulation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Protocols based on the OSI Model utilize a mechanism called encapsulation. It is the addition of a header, and possibly a footer, to the data received by each layer from the layer above before it is handed over to the layer below. As a message traverses the layers, it is enriched with additional data. The previous layers header and payload becomes the payload of the current layer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encapsulation occurs as data moves down through the OSI Model layers from Application to Physical. When data moves up through the layers from Physical to Application the action occurring is known as de-encapsulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The process is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; The Application layer creates the message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; The Application layer passes the message to the Presentation layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; The Presentation layer encapsulates the message by adding layer-specific information to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; The process continues as the original message travels down the layers. Each layer adds additional information to the message&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; The message reaches the Physical layer and is converted into electrical impulses that represent bits and is transmitted over the physical connection&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; The receiving computer captures the bits from the physical medium and re-creates the message in the Physical layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; The Physical layer converts the message from bits into a Data Link frame and sends the message up to the Data Link layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; The Data Link layer strips the layer-specific information from the message and sends it up to the Network layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; The process of de-encapsulation is performed on each layer until the message reaches the Application layer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10.&lt;/strong&gt; On the Application layer, the data is extracted from the message and is sent to the intended software recipient&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The information added and removed by each layer contains instructions, checksums, and  can only be understood by the peer layer that added or created the information. This creates the logical channel that enables the peer layer on different computers to communicate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tcpip-and-osi-comparison&quot;&gt;TCP/IP and OSI comparison&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TCP/IP or DARPA Model was developed before the OSI Model. The designers of the OSI Reference Model made sure that both fit together because TCP/IP was already an established deployment in networking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/osi_table_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;table presentation of the layers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TCP/IP is the most widely used protocol stack with dozens of individual protocols. It is platform-independent and based on open standards and can be found in every available modern operating system. The drawbacks of TCP/IP are its significant consumption of resources and the lack of security by design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theory behind the OSI model is abstract at first but it serves as a model to understand and compare protocols. It also helps vendors and developers to create digital communication products that interoperate. Lastly, the structure of the OSI model helps to frame discussions of protocols and contrast various technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/osi-model/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/osi-model/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Holiday Gift Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;h6 id=&quot;i-started-this-blog-in-2019-and-the-positive-feedback-from-you-readers-is-amazing-and-motivates-me-to-continue-writing-thank-you-i-promise-that-2020-will-bring-more-articles-about-security-books-watches-and-other-topics-that-spark-my-interest&quot;&gt;I started this blog in 2019 and the positive feedback from you readers is amazing and motivates me to continue writing. Thank you! I promise that 2020 will bring more articles about security, books, watches and other topics that spark my interest.&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compiling this list of gift ideas was fun to do and the items are either things I already own or things I want. Let’s jump right in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/gift_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a gift&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;whiskey&quot;&gt;Whiskey&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first item from my list is a good bottle of Japanese Whiskey. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/37zKvqr&quot;&gt;Nikka From The Barrel&lt;/a&gt; is a blended whiskey created to deliver full flavors and the iconic bottle is designed to reflect “a small block of whiskey” – embodying the rich, strong taste of the whiskey within. Masataka Taketsuru the founder of Nikka is also the ancestor of Japanese whiskey. The Nikka distillery won many prestigious international awards and has earned a reputation for quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/nikka.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a bottle of nikka&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you prefer a traditional Single Malt Scotch, then I’d recommend a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2pXgFve&quot;&gt;Laphroaig 10 y/o&lt;/a&gt;. Made in Scotland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fine Whiskey requires consumption from nice glasses. Probably the most famous one is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OERDZX&quot;&gt;Glencairn Whiskey Glass&lt;/a&gt;. It is built so your hands won’t warm the Whiskey. A classic &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/35r5KsO&quot;&gt;Whiskey Tumbler&lt;/a&gt; is a solid alternative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whiskey connoisseurs won’t allow ice cubes to water down their favorite drink. A nice set of &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/34gGuVV&quot;&gt;Whiskey Stones&lt;/a&gt; will make any aficionado happy and is my third item on this gift list. It’s by the way a centuries’ old Scandinavian tradition to use cold stones to cool liquids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smoking-section&quot;&gt;Smoking Section&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next item in the gift guide is something I tend to enjoy myself after a hard day of security work. A good cigar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/montecristo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a box of Montecristo Cigars&quot; style=&quot;float: left;width:60%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My recommendation to people getting into the hobby is to try different brands and find their favorite taste. But a box of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cigarworld.de/en/zigarren/cuba/regulares/montecristo-01007&quot;&gt;Montecristo Cigars&lt;/a&gt; will satisfy the regular as much as the occasional smoker of fine Cubans. Their  strength is medium; in fact, it has become the standard by which all other Havanas are now judged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I apologize to my readers from the United States but I think there is still a problem with importing Cuban goods to the US.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fine crystal &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2KSg19x&quot;&gt;ashtray&lt;/a&gt; and a nice cigar &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DkcNHv&quot;&gt;cutter&lt;/a&gt; go well with a box of cigars as a present and round off the list in this category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;library&quot;&gt;Library&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chapter is something more universal and will also benefit people with a more healthy lifestyle. The holiday season is in the end also a good time to pick up a book or magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thewilliambrownproject.com/&quot;&gt;“WM Brown Magazine”&lt;/a&gt;, founded by style editor, explorer, filmmaker, and New Yorker Matt Hranek starts my recommendations in this category. WM Brown magazine is curated for the gentleman who seeks an off-the-beaten-track experience, in all aspects of life. The well-written articles are accompanied by amazing photography. The stories cover such things as food, fashion, watches, and yes.. even vintage whiskey flasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wmbrown.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a box of Montecristo Cigars&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width:50%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt also wrote a fantastic book: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/33iHGXA&quot;&gt;“A Man &amp;amp; His Watch”&lt;/a&gt;. While the watches in the book are interesting for sure, it’s the stories of people that make this a must-have for any watch collector. It’s a wonderful collection of stories and images representing a diverse and fascinating group of horological devotees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another recommended book about watches is &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/35BENTn&quot;&gt;“The Watch – Thoroughly Revisited”&lt;/a&gt;. It is not only a feast for the eyes but both a comprehensive and holistic resource in terms of horology that will appeal to any aficionado. It goes into great detail about a microcosm that has never been more popular than in the age of instagraming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough of watches, the next book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2Db1KAF&quot;&gt;“How to Measure Anything in Cybersecurity Risk”&lt;/a&gt; is about security or better about risk management and governance and reads like an education in quantitative modeling and how to apply the methodology to cybersecurity. It truly challenges the current common practices of opinion-based risk frameworks. This is a must-have for anyone who has to manage and communicate risks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Defense in depth is not only a military strategy but also helps in building a robust security posture. The book &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OpYo30&quot;&gt;“Zero Trust Networks: Building Secure Systems in Untrusted Networks”&lt;/a&gt; explains that perimeter defenses guarding your network aren’t as secure as you might think. The book introduces you to the zero trust model, a method that treats all hosts as if they’re internet-facing, and considers the entire network to be compromised and hostile. Strong authentication, authorization, and encryption throughout, while providing compartmentalized access and better operational agility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My last book recommendation is a classic science-fiction book. &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2XN91Qz&quot;&gt;“Neuromancer”&lt;/a&gt; surely sets the stage for many ideas, books, video games, and movies that followed. If your loved one is into tech-noire, corporate dominance, virtual reality, you might just as well have found the perfect present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creation&quot;&gt;Creation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great way to spend the holidays is to build something. And LEGO has something amazing in-store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/landi.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the lego landrover&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width: 70%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might have heard that Land Rover will launch a new version of their vintage cult Defender model in 2020. During the holiday season, you can already start building your Defender with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/34kKTqL&quot;&gt;LEGO Technic Land Rover Defender&lt;/a&gt;. The set has over 2500 pieces and includes a 4-speed sequential gearbox, All Wheel Drive with 3 differentials, independent suspension on both axles, a detailed in-line 6-cylinder engine and a working winch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next item on my list is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2DdeXJ5&quot;&gt;Canon EOS M50&lt;/a&gt;. It is an entry-level mirrorless camera that features an electronic viewfinder, fully articulating touchscreen and a 24MP APS-C sensor. It has Canon’s DIGIC 8 processor and offers 4K/24p video capture as well as Wi-Fi, Bluetooth and, NFC. The Camera also features Canons Dual Pixel Auto Focus, which is considered the best in the industry. As a perfect first lense, I recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2OiVNrC&quot;&gt;Canon EF-M 22m F2 Pancake Lens&lt;/a&gt; which gives that nice background blur and does great in portraits, landscapes, low-light, and macro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/22m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a JLC Reverso showing some nice background blur&quot; style=&quot;margin: 15px 15px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to finish my holiday gift guide with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2QNTi2e&quot;&gt;Yubikey&lt;/a&gt;. It’s the perfect present for anyone who enjoys a secure authentication method. The keys support OTP and U2F and come in different sizes and with all major connectors. I recently wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/universal-2nd-factor/&quot;&gt;article about U2F&lt;/a&gt; and its advantages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was my guide and all that’s left for me is to wish my readers a relaxed end of the year and a good time with your loved ones.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/holiday-gift-guide/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/holiday-gift-guide/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>book</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>U2F - Universal 2nd Factor Authentication</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-universal-2nd-factor-is-one-of-the-most-secure-authentication-methods-currently-available-its-advantages-are-based-on-hardware-isolation-and-modern-cryptography&quot;&gt;The “Universal 2nd Factor” is one of the most secure authentication methods currently available. Its advantages are based on hardware isolation and modern cryptography.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F is an open standard that improves and simplifies traditional two-factor authentication. It is utilizing a Universal Serial Bus (USB) or near-field communication (NFC) device to achieve secure authentication and was initially developed by Google and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.yubico.com/&quot;&gt;Yubico&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/yubikey_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;otp&quot;&gt;OTP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/One-time_password&quot;&gt;One-time passwords&lt;/a&gt; (OTP) or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Time-based_One-time_Password_algorithm&quot;&gt;time-based one-time passwords&lt;/a&gt; (TOTP) provide a relatively secure second factor to millions of users. The popularity and good propagation are related to the simplicity of the concept. But there are shortcomings to this method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is 2FA OTP? In addition to a static user name/password credential, a user adds another authentication factor - one that is dynamically generated. By definition, this OTP credential is only valid for one login before it becomes obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OTP technology is compatible with all major platforms (desktop, laptop, mobile) and even legacy environments. It is the most popular choice among second-factor protocols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One-time credentials are delivered in different ways, usually via a physical object, such as a mobile phone (using SMS or an app), a token with an LCD-display, or a &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2qrTNEa&quot;&gt;YubiKey&lt;/a&gt;. Concrete OTP algorithms vary greatly but they have one thing in common: a shared secret between client and server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TOTP implementations, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Google_Authenticator&quot;&gt;Google Authenticator&lt;/a&gt;, require time-synchronization and a shared secret between the authentication server and the device providing the password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second-factor one-time passwords offer protection against password replay but it’s not designed to counter a &lt;em&gt;man-in-the-middle&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt; attack. The shared secret between client and server is the main weakness of OTP and TOTP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A theoretical attack is quite simple: token codes or shared secrets can get intercepted during authentication or stolen during the initialization of OTP. This is significant since it is the principal threat most users believe they are solving with this technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/totp.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a totp login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;u2f&quot;&gt;U2F&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F improves on OTP vulnerabilities such as &lt;em&gt;phishing&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;man-in-the-middle attacks&lt;/em&gt; by implementing a real-time challenge-response scheme with &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key/&quot;&gt;public-key encryption&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/&quot;&gt;digital signatures&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a user registers a U2F device with an online service, a public/private key pair is generated on the client and the public key is shared with the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After registration, when the user attempts to log in, the service provider sends a challenge to the client. The client compiles at least the information about the source of the challenge into the response and signs it with the private key before sending it back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/u2f.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a u2f login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The server can detect an abnormality in the response (since it is issuing the challenge) and deny the transaction if a rogue site or middle-man manipulates the flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F is resistant to phishing by design too. For instance, the user cannot be tricked into pressing the key and authenticate with a “fake” web page since the authentication origin is part of the process and the communication between the device and the web browser. A malicious person cannot ask for your “U2F codes” because there are no codes in play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future…&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nowadays most people use biometrics-based methods for authentication on personal mobile devices to unlock them. Fingerprint and facial recognition have been around for a while now but they’re not exactly foolproof. It’s possible to trick fingerprint sensors and basic facial recognition systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/yubikey_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a totp login&quot; style=&quot; margin: 10px 0px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most consumer OTP solutions are depending on mobile phones as the second factor, it opens up the question of future dependability of this system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;U2F devices, on the other hand, will become cheaper and more common to be accepted by service providers. I predict a future of adaptive security with many potential factors for authentication. Shared secret knowledge, physical ownership of a secure device, location, and behavior are all factors, that if combined, will convince machines that we are who we say we are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/universal-2nd-factor/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/universal-2nd-factor/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight - Ref. 79030N</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-black-bay-fifty-eight-was-introduced-at-baselworld-2018-it-is-an-anniversary-model-to-commemorate-60-years-of-the-tudor-submariner-which-was-released-in-1958&quot;&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight was introduced at Baselworld 2018. It is an anniversary-model to commemorate 60 years of the Tudor Submariner which was released in 1958.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this watch is to go back to the original Big Crown models and create a vintage-inspired modern take on the Submariner-like dive watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tudor-submariner-heritage&quot;&gt;Tudor Submariner Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tudor Oyster Prince Submariner ‘Big Crown’ reference 7924 used many parts from Rolex Submariners in those days. The crown and bracelet carried for exampled Rolex markings. The watch was water-resistant up to 200m (600 feet) and featured a large screw-down crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same year, the reference 7925 was released with a depth rating of 100m (300 feet) and the distinctive red triangle at the zero point of the diving bezel. The Marine nationale francaise (MN), the US Navy (USN) and other military organizations throughout the world equipped their elite personnel with the Tudor Sub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watches delivered to these military entities were neither custom-designed nor specially developed. They were just references listed in the Tudor cataloge. Their only distinction was an engraving on the screw-down case back. The Marine nationale francaise watches, for example, bear the initials M.N. accompanied by the last two digits of the year in which they were delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples surviving to this day are rarely in perfect condition since they were used in extremely harsh conditions. The relative rarity of these watches and their respective stories make them a highly prized collectors item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downsizing-the-original-black-bay&quot;&gt;Downsizing the original Black Bay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the new Tudor Black Bay 58 looks just like another Black Bay, a Submariner-like dive watch with vintage inspiration. But the watch is an evolution and at the same time a return to the original dimensions of the Tudor Submariner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A modern Tudor Black Bay 58 vs. a vintage Tudor Submariner&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alignment with the original Big Crown models – mainly the Tudor Submariner 7924 and 7925 means the 58 is a smaller and slimmer version of the bulky Black Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 58 is 39mm in diameter. While the original ref. 7924 was even smaller at 37mm, the effort taken by Tudor to reduce the case size from the original Black Bay is a nod to watch enthusiasts who have been asking for smaller watches for years. The lug width has also been reduced to 20mm, to keep the proportions balanced. The case was condensed in height to now only 11.9mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the 58 ist a well-proportioned watch and sits nicely on the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowflakes-on-a-guilt-dial&quot;&gt;Snowflakes on a guilt dial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a modern interpretation of a classic, the Fifty-Eight has golden writing and minuteries. Also, a one-directional rotating bezel with gold lettering, classic with aluminum inlay and a red triangular marking at 12 adorns the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tudor went with golden snowflake hands which is a deviation from the original Submariner but it works surprisingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BB58 comes with the Tudor in-house MT5402 movement which is COSC certified. It has a power reserve of a whopping 70 hours.
This means one can easily leave the watch on the nightstand over the weekend and pick it up on Monday without having to adjust the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;specifications&quot;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight Ref. 79030N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Calibre MT5402 (COSC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Stainless Steel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Crystal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lug Width:&lt;/strong&gt; 20mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diameter/Height:&lt;/strong&gt; 39 mm/11.9 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six years after the first Black Bay and 60 years after the first Big Crown Submariner, Tudor impressively shows how to use past models to create an equally modern and historically true watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight is a good looking dive watch and comes at a fair price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>tudor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Social Credit Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;nosedive-is-a-episode-in-the-british-science-fiction-series-black-mirror-it-examines-the-idea-of-a-fictional-society-where-people-can-rate-each-other-from-one-to-five-stars-for-every-interaction-they-have-with-each-other-the-resulting-score-has-an-impact-on-the-social-and-economic-status-of-the-individual&quot;&gt;“Nosedive” is a episode in the British science fiction series &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Mirror&quot;&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/a&gt;. It examines the idea of a fictional society where people can rate each other from one to five stars for every interaction they have with each other. The resulting score has an impact on the social and economic status of the individual.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story follows Lacie, who is a young woman overly obsessed with her ratings; she finds an opportunity to improve her ratings greatly and move into a more luxurious residence after being chosen by her popular childhood friend as the maid of honour for her wedding. Her obsession leads to several mishaps on her journey to the wedding that culminate in a rapid reduction in her ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many critics noted the similarity of the episode to real-world Social Credit Systems. Indeed we already live in a world where the judgment of people is being replaced by numbers. Algorithms calculate the value of a human being and create digitally transparent people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a wall of CCTV&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nudge-theory&quot;&gt;Nudge Theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Credit Systems belong to a behavioral science concept called Nudge Theory. It proposes positive reinforcement and indirect suggestions as a way to influence the behavior and decision making of groups or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nudging contrasts with other ways to achieve compliance, such as education, legislation or enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utilization of “nudging” has been widely criticized for diminishing autonomy, threatening dignity, and violating liberties. Some call it psychological manipulative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese system uses a combination of mass surveillance and big data to score citizens. It is currently voluntary but will be made mandatory by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final stage, every citizen and company will be ranked whether they like it or not. The system will manage the punishments and rewards of citizens based on their economic and personal behavior.
The exact methodology for the rating is a secret but examples of infrations include bad driving, smoking in non-smoking areas, or posting fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punishments include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flight ban&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exclusion from schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slow internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;public display of blacklisted individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inside of a chinese airport&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2018, 5.5 million high-speed rail trips and 17.5 million flights had been denied to prospective travelers who were on a Chinese social scoring blacklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;western-world&quot;&gt;Western World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germany has its own social scoring system. The universal credit rating system known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schufa&quot;&gt;Schufa&lt;/a&gt; is a private company that assesses the creditworthiness of the majority of the German citizens and that of over 5 million companies in the country. Factors like living in a low-income neighborhood (geo-scoring) can lower the Schufa score. There is mounting criticism in Germany of what some view as a lack of transparency in establishing Schufa scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schufa has also been criticized for being a privately controlled central database that provides personality profiles for individuals. Having a bad score in the credit rating system will prevent people from getting a loan or renting an apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparable credit systems are common in most western democracies. The US counterpart to Schufa is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FICO&quot;&gt;FICO&lt;/a&gt; and the UK has &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experian&quot;&gt;Experian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of societal “privileges” related to transportation, accommodations, communications, and the rates we pay for services (like insurance) are controlled by algorithms and our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a critical phase of technological development and we need to discuss our values. Private companies will keep scoring people in areas like finance, criminality, rental housing, or mail-order businesses. It works like a charm and some citizens are even welcoming the ideal of “digitally transparent” people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you have something that you don’t want anyone to know, maybe you shouldn’t be doing it in the first place -Eric Schmidt, Google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s only a question of time until government institutions will pull all the information from different databases together and come up with a social score for each citizen. Arguments will be made for it improving the security of people and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we want to live in a world as predicted in the Black Mirror episode? Our societies have to be made aware of what algorithms really can, and cannot, do. Education is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
