<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>personal blog</description>
    <link>https://damaex17.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://damaex17.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 07:20:13 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 07:20:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stealth-rolex&quot;&gt;the stealth rolex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally created to honor the adventures of the Mt. Everest conquerors Tenzing Norgay and Sir Edmund Hillary, the 1953 Rolex Explorer was the first of a long line of Rolex tool watches designed to go anywhere.
The Explorer was developed from the original 1930s-50s Oyster Perpetual “bubblebacks,” the first water-resistant and self-winding wristwatches to achieve technical and commercial success. Norgay and Hillary immortalized the Explorer and the continuous incremental refinement by Rolex led to the Explorer 114270 produced from 2002 until 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the general public may not understand the depth of the Rolex tool heritage, even the averrage “man on the street” understands that the brand stands as a synonym for quality. And in this Explorer, Rolex delivers. The Geneva watchmaker ranks among the exclusive club of true manufactures that produce virtually every part of their watches by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 36mm stainless steel case itself is a testament to Rolex’s eye for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all begins with the steel itself; Rolex makes it in its own company foundry. The steel employed on the Explorer is of the 904L type, not the lesser resilient 316L employed by the majority of watchmakers. 904L is more expensive to produce and harder to work with. The payoff is the watch’s lifetime and scratch resistance. The steel preserves the poished and brused finishes and the corrosion resistance is higher than with conventional stainless steel. 
Rolex is building watches that last a life time (or two, or three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the case is the Rolex Cal. 3130 chronometer grade movement which beats at 28.800 vibrations per hour. The movement is COSC certified in a two-week evaluation process. This certification tests the movement in different positions and temperatures. Another testament to the quality requirements of Rolex watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than any other aspect of the watch, the dial is what makes the Explorer unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three Arabic numerals at 3, 6, and 9 o’clock combine with a triangular index at 12 and intermediate stick indexes, no date, smooth bezel. Signature “Mercedes” cathedral hands are, like all indexes, rendered in white gold for enduring resistance to corrosion and tarnish. The rich black lacquer dial provides a radiant gloss backdrop to the white gold elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270 is the last of the 36mm Explorers. It represents a time where Rolex built tools rather than jewellery and investment pieces. But make no mistake… the Explorer can be worn with a suite. If there is one leason learned from history, it’s that a Rolex Explorer is your companion anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
