<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>cyber security and technology blog</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 10:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lightning Network</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;bitcoin-is-the-worlds-first-decentralized-cryptocurrency-that-operates-without-the-need-for-a-central-authority-it-has-gained-immense-popularity-due-to-its-ability-to-facilitate-secure-fast-and-low-cost-transactions-across-borders-however-as-the-popularity-of-bitcoin-has-grown-so-have-the-challenges-it-faces-one-of-the-most-significant-challenges-has-been-scalability-leading-to-the-development-of-the-lightning-network&quot;&gt;Bitcoin is the world’s first decentralized cryptocurrency that operates without the need for a central authority. It has gained immense popularity due to its ability to facilitate secure, fast, and low-cost transactions across borders. However, as the popularity of Bitcoin has grown, so have the &lt;a href=&quot;/2021/bitcoin-scale/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;challenges it faces&lt;/a&gt;. One of the most significant challenges has been scalability, leading to the development of the Lightning Network.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://documentation.zebedee.io/img/v1/btc-ln.png&quot; alt=&quot;lightning network logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bitcoins-scalability-issues&quot;&gt;Bitcoin’s Scalability Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin’s scalability issues arise from the limited number of transactions that can be processed by the network at any given time. Currently, the Bitcoin network can only handle about 7 transactions per second. This limitation has resulted in slow transaction processing times, higher transaction fees, and network congestion during periods of high demand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network is a second-layer protocol that operates on top of the Bitcoin blockchain. It was designed to solve the scalability issues faced by Bitcoin by enabling fast, low-cost transactions between parties without the need for third-party intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network operates by setting up a network of payment channels between users. These payment channels enable users to conduct transactions off-chain, meaning that they are not recorded on the Bitcoin blockchain. Instead, transactions are recorded in a separate layer of the Lightning Network, which is only settled on the Bitcoin blockchain once the payment channel is closed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use the Lightning Network, users first need to set up a payment channel with a counterparty. This is done by opening a channel on the Lightning Network and depositing an amount of Bitcoin into the channel. Once the channel is open, users can conduct transactions between each other instantly and with minimal fees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-benefits-of-the-lightning-network&quot;&gt;The Benefits of the Lightning Network&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network offers several benefits over traditional on-chain Bitcoin transactions. Firstly, it enables instant transactions between parties without the need for third-party intermediaries. This means that transactions are settled within seconds, compared to traditional Bitcoin transactions that can take several minutes to be processed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the Lightning Network significantly reduces transaction fees. Traditional Bitcoin transactions require users to pay a fee to miners to process the transaction, which can be significant during periods of high demand. However, Lightning Network transactions are processed off-chain, meaning that transaction fees are significantly lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, the Lightning Network also provides greater privacy for users. Traditional Bitcoin transactions are publicly visible on the blockchain, meaning that anyone can track the flow of funds between Bitcoin addresses. However, the Lightning Network operates off-chain, meaning that transactions are not publicly visible on the blockchain, providing greater privacy for users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lightning Network is a promising solution to the scalability issues faced by Bitcoin. By enabling fast, low-cost transactions between parties without the need for third-party intermediaries, it has the potential to significantly improve the usability and adoption of Bitcoin. With continued development and adoption, the Lightning Network could become a vital component of the Bitcoin ecosystem, enabling it to scale to meet the demands of a growing user base.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2023/lightning-network/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2023/lightning-network/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>ATT&amp;CK - Threat Intelligence</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-attck-adversarial-techniques-tactics-and-common-knowledge-framework-is-an-open-source-threat-intelligence-knowledge-base-designed-to-equip-organizations-with-the-information-they-need-to-defend-their-networks-against-sophisticated-cyber-threats&quot;&gt;The ATT&amp;amp;CK (Adversarial Techniques, Tactics, and Common Knowledge) framework is an open-source threat intelligence knowledge base designed to equip organizations with the information they need to defend their networks against sophisticated cyber threats.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed by MITRE Corporation and a community of security experts and practitioners, ATT&amp;amp;CK provides a comprehensive view of attack tactics and techniques across all stages of the adversary lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.crowdstrike.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/12/MITRE-Eval-Blog-Image2-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ATT&amp;amp;CK logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;usage&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Companies can use the &lt;a href=&quot;https://attack.mitre.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ATT&amp;amp;CK&lt;/a&gt; framework to gain better visibility into the tactics, techniques, and procedures adversaries use to attack their systems. By understanding the various stages of the attacker lifecycle, organizations can build more effective security defenses and incident response plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ATT&amp;amp;CK framework can also be used to prioritize and validate detection logic. Companies can review techniques and tactics used by adversaries in past attacks and develop rules and use cases based on that information. This can help ensure that detection logic is focused on the most pressing security risks. Additionally, companies can use ATT&amp;amp;CK to better understand the tactics and techniques used by threat actors, which can help inform their security investments and plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;attack-lifecycle&quot;&gt;Attack Lifecycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ATT&amp;amp;CK divides attack tactics into nine stages based on real-world observations of attackers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Access&lt;/strong&gt; covers techniques used to gain access to the target system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execution&lt;/strong&gt; describes how adversaries establish a foothold after gaining access&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Persistence&lt;/strong&gt; relates to how attackers maintain their presence on the system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discovery&lt;/strong&gt; covers the approach used to identify assets and vulnerabilities in the system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lateral Movement&lt;/strong&gt; represents procedures used to move across the network&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Collection&lt;/strong&gt; describes how attackers extract data from systems&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Command and Control&lt;/strong&gt; relate to techniques used to control compromised systems&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exfiltration&lt;/strong&gt; covers techniques used to transport data out of the system&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact&lt;/strong&gt; describes the ultimate objectives of the attack&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relationship between tactics and techniques can be visualized in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://attack.mitre.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ATT&amp;amp;CK Matrix&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, under the tactic &lt;a href=&quot;https://attack.mitre.org/tactics/TA0043/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Reconnaissance&lt;/a&gt;, there are a series of techniques including &lt;a href=&quot;https://attack.mitre.org/techniques/T1595/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Active Scanning&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://attack.mitre.org/techniques/T1591/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Gather Victim Org Information&lt;/a&gt;. Each of these is a single technique that attackers may use to achieve the goal of reconnaissance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://miro.medium.com/max/640/1*DioJj9NQNtDXGBTEO_8-7w.webp&quot; alt=&quot;ATT&amp;amp;CK logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;getting-started&quot;&gt;Getting started&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MITRE has released a great series of getting started &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/mitre-attack/getting-started/home&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. Organizations can use ATT&amp;amp;CK to prioritize and validate detection logic by analyzing techniques used by adversaries in past attacks. With this knowledge, organizations can start developing rules and use cases to better protect their networks against sophisticated threats.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2023/MITRE-att&ck/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2023/MITRE-att&ck/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Semgrep - Security Testing</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;static-application-security-testing-or-sast-is-a-testing-methodology-to-analyse-application-source-code-and-to-identify-security-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;Static Application Security Testing or SAST is a testing methodology to analyse application source code and to identify security vulnerabilities.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many compliance frameworks require organizations to perform security testing prior to pushing code into production environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/returntocorp/semgrep/develop/semgrep.svg&quot; alt=&quot;Semgrep logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;semgrep&quot;&gt;Semgrep&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/returntocorp/semgrep&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Semgrep&lt;/a&gt; is a free open-source static code analysis tool developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://r2c.dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;r2c&lt;/a&gt; and the open-source community. It has stable support for Go, Java, JavaScript, JSON, Python, and Ruby and experimental support for many other languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To complement the native semgrep tool, r2c also provides a continuous integration service (called Semgrep CI) and maintains a rule library (called Semgrep Registry). Basic individual use of these services are offered for free while paid tiers cover team and commercial use-cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be a bit confusing at the beginning but there are three ways of running semgrep:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semgrep CLI&lt;/strong&gt; is the command line interface for semgrep and can be easily installed via &lt;em&gt;brew&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;pip&lt;/em&gt; and executed in a source code directory with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;semgrep --config=auto&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semgrep App&lt;/strong&gt; is esentially Semgrep CLI but can be integrated in GitHub or GiLab and now the scans are configurable in repositories via &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;semgrep.yml&lt;/code&gt;. After &lt;a href=&quot;https://semgrep.dev/docs/semgrep-app/getting-started-with-semgrep-app/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;setting everything up&lt;/a&gt;, Semgrep can be executed daily or weekly or on a PR (pull request) or MR (merge request).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Semgrep CI&lt;/strong&gt; is the approach where Semgrep is integrated in you CI (continuous integration) environment. When connecting it to Semgrep App you can now do things like bulk triage for false positives, notifications via Slack and email and PR/MR review comments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We suggest to start with Semgrep CLI or a plugin for your preferred IDE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rules&quot;&gt;Rules&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rules are at the core of a software like semgrep. These instructions describe patterns in the source code. A code finding is when the mentioned rules detect a match in the code. Semgrep matches the code using rules to report a finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semgrep support developers by catching issues of security, performance, correctness, and enforce best practices. Rules are either created by the community or can be customly defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-noise&quot;&gt;Finding Noise&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static analysis has a reputation for being “noisy”, reporting hundreds or even thousands of rule violations just when you thought you were ready to release. Fortunately, semgrep provides strategies for dealing with those false positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;states&quot;&gt;States&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semgrep CI can track the lifetime of an individual finding in a 4-tuple: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;(rule ID, file path, syntactic context, index)&lt;/code&gt;. These are hashed and returned as the uniqye identifier of a finding aka the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;syntactic_id&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semgrep App provides the most flexibility in managing findings. Here, the finding can move between states according to the unique &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;syntactic_id&lt;/code&gt; from Semgrep CI. The four states are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;OPEN&lt;/code&gt;: the finding exists in the code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;FIXED&lt;/code&gt;: the finding existed in the code but is no longer found&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MUTED&lt;/code&gt;: the finding has been ignored&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;REMOVED&lt;/code&gt;: the finding’s rule isn’t enabled anymore&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shift-left&quot;&gt;Shift Left&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, the application testing is executed before code is compiled into an artifact and pushed into production (testing/staging). If code doesn’t meet the quality gates, the test fails and the deployment is stopped. This gatekeeper approach causes significant bottlenecks in the development lifecycle and isn’t compatible with agile methodologies, which emphasize early feedback and development velocity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shifting the static application security testing to the left enables developers to identify and fix issues much earlier in the development lifecycle. This make the software development more efficient, improves quality, and enables faster deployments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semgrep can be integrated in most editors like &lt;a href=&quot;https://visualstudio.microsoft.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/idea/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IntelliJ&lt;/a&gt;. By doing this developers get direct feedback from semgrep while they write code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2023/semgrep/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2023/semgrep/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup October 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Our selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;toyota-hacked---leaked-credentials&quot;&gt;Toyota Hacked - Leaked Credentials&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Toyota official connectivity app allows owners to link their smartphone with the vehicle’s infotainment system. Toyota discovered recently that a portion of the T-Connect site source code was mistakenly published on GitHub and contained an access key. This made it possible for an unauthorized third party to access the details of 296,019 customers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/toyota-discloses-data-leak-after-access-key-exposed-on-github/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;github-actions-are-being-abused-to-run-mining-operations&quot;&gt;GitHub Actions are being abused to run mining operations&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sysdig Threat Research Team (Sysdig TRT) recently uncovered an extensive and sophisticated active cryptomining operation in which a threat actor is using some of the largest cloud and continuous integration and deployment (CI/CD) service providers. The activity observed is known as “freejacking,” which is the abuse of compute allocated for free trial accounts on SaaS platforms. &lt;a href=&quot;https://sysdig.com/blog/massive-cryptomining-operation-github-actions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://sysdig.com/wp-content/uploads/image2-22-1170x786.png&quot; alt=&quot;High-level overview of PURPLEURCHIN operation&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;High-level overview of PURPLEURCHIN operation / Credit: sysdig.com&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;list-of-common-passwords-accounts-for-nearly-all-cyberattacks&quot;&gt;List of Common Passwords Accounts for Nearly All Cyberattacks&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability management firm Rapid7 recorded every attempt to compromise their honeypot servers over a 12-month period, finding that the attempted credential attacks resulted in 512,000 permutations. Almost all of those passwords (99.997%) are included in a common password list - the RockYou2021 file. It seems like attackers are just taking the easy road. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/endpoint/a-common-password-list-accounts-for-nearly-all-cyberattacks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-102022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-102022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup September 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-month-multiple-hacks-have-show-that-mfa-is-becoming-a-main-target-for-attacks-in-many-organizations-authentication-processes-a-stark-reminder-to-replace-time-based-one-time-passwords-totp-with-man-in-the-middle-resistant-forms-of-mfa-like-u2f&quot;&gt;This month, multiple hacks have show that MFA is becoming a main target for attacks in many organizations’ authentication processes. A stark reminder to replace time-based one-time passwords (TOTP) with man-in-the-middle resistant forms of MFA like &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/universal-2nd-factor/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U2F&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;uber-hacked---mfa-weakness-i&quot;&gt;Uber Hacked - MFA Weakness I&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ride-sharing giant Uber took some of its operations offline after it discovered that its internal systems have been compromised. An attacker was able to social-engineer his way into an employee’s VPN account before moving deeper into the network. “They pretty much have full access to Uber,” Sam Curry, a security engineer at Yuga Labs. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/uber-breach-external-contractor-mfa-bombing-attack&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;rockstar-games-hacked---mfa-weakness-ii&quot;&gt;Rockstar Games Hacked - MFA Weakness II&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The video game publisher Rockstar Games released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/RockstarGames/status/1571849091860029455&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt; revealing a network intrusion and informing fans that details about their new Grand Theft Auto game had been leaked. Reliable details of the hack are not available yet. It is rumored the attack was performed by the same threat actor that is behind the Uber breach. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/rockstar-games-confirms-grand-theft-auto-6-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.bleepstatic.com/content/hl-images/2022/09/18/GTA_headpic.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rockstar Games Hacked&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Grand Theft Auto / Credit: Rockstar Games&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;transitioning-to-multiple-aws-accounts&quot;&gt;Transitioning to multiple AWS accounts&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many companies struggle with applying the least-privilege principle to their existing single-account AWS environment. Justin Plock discusses transitioning from a single-account environment to a multi-account environment, including decisions you need to make about network, user management, security, access control, and architecture. &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/prescriptive-guidance/latest/transitioning-to-multiple-aws-accounts/welcome.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;russian-official-says-civilian-satellites-may-be-a-legitimate-military-target&quot;&gt;Russian official says civilian satellites may be a legitimate military target&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;while SpaceX’s Starlink satellite Internet has proved valuable in Ukraine, new threats are coming from Russia. Without mentioning Starlink by name, Russia’s representative at a United Nations meeting on threats from space and possible countermeasures spoke of an “extremely dangerous trend”. He was referring to the use of civilian or commercial infrastructure in space for military purposes by “the United States and its allies.” Quasi-civilian infrastructure can thus become a legitimate target for retaliation”, he said. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2022/09/russian-diplomat-suggests-attacks-on-satellites-in-possible-reference-to-starlink/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;microsoft-investigates-iranian-attacks-against-the-albanian-government&quot;&gt;Microsoft investigates Iranian attacks against the Albanian government&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Microsoft Detection and Response Team (DART) has released an in-depth analysis after being engaged by the Albanian government to lead an investigation into the attacks. According to the report, Microsoft assumes that “with a high degree of probability” several Iranian actors were involved in the attack, which was carried out in several phases. Tools and a digital certificate that had previously been used by actors from Iran were seen in action against the Albanian government. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/09/08/microsoft-investigates-iranian-attacks-against-the-albanian-government/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;san-franciscos-subway-only-runs-thanks-to-windows-98-and-dos&quot;&gt;San Francisco’s subway only runs thanks to Windows 98 and DOS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The newspaper The Mercury News reports on the 50th anniversary of the Bart (Bay Area Rapid Transport) subway and the numerous technical difficulties in keeping the old trains running. According to the report, some of the problems are due to completely outdated technology. This apparently includes Windows 98. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mercurynews.com/2022/09/17/how-clever-mechanics-keep-50-year-old-bart-trains-running-windows-98-ebay-and-scraps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.mercurynews.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/09/EBT-L-BART-XXXX-03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;BART&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;BART trains / Credit: Jose Carlos Fajardo/Bay Area News Group&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-most-damning-allegation-in-the-twitter-whistleblowers-report&quot;&gt;The Most Damning Allegation in the Twitter Whistleblower’s Report&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The claimed lax security at Twitter is bad news. But one clearly captures the extent of systemic issues. Engineers had extensive access to the social network’s live, deployed software platform with minimal logging and monitoring. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/story/mudge-twitter-whistleblower-security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-092022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-092022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup August 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Our selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consequences-of-inadequate-identity-management-in-github&quot;&gt;Consequences of Inadequate Identity Management in GitHub&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity and Access Management is a major area of concern for security teams, including source control management like GitHub. The blog article raises three major risks people should be aware of. In addition, we suggest taking a good look at the CI/CD system and the service accounts controlling production environments. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cidersecurity.io/blog/research/the-consequences-of-inadequate-identity-management-in-your-github-organization/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;building-a-product-security-program&quot;&gt;Building A Product Security Program&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anshuman Bhartiya writes on his blog about the different aspects of building a product security program from scratch. He writes about the essential topics of risk appetite, prioritization, relationships, and empathy. This article is a great start for anyone who has to implement a secure development approach in an organization. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anshumanbhartiya.com/posts/building-product-security-program&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;get-a-headstart-on-post-quantum-cryptography&quot;&gt;Get A Headstart On Post-Quantum Cryptography&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of post-quantum (PQ) cryptography describes the fact practically all data sent over the Internet today is at risk in the future if a stable quantum computer is created. Cloudflare has released open-source software and experimental services to test post-quantum key agreements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/experiment-with-pq/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/07/18/07/39/quantum-mechanics-1525470_960_720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quantum Mechanics&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Quantum Mechanics / Credit: pixabay.com&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cisco-data-breach&quot;&gt;Cisco Data Breach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco has confirmed a breach of its network, the attacker used voice phishing to convince an employee to accept a malicious multifactor authentication (MFA). With access established, the attacker then moved through the network by escalating privileges and logging into multiple systems. Cisco believes the threat actor is an initial access broker - an adversary that gains unauthorized access to networks and then sells that access on the Dark Web. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/cisco-confirms-data-breach-hacked-files-leaked&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco Talos did a great write-up with all the details related to the cyber attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.talosintelligence.com/2022/08/recent-cyber-attack.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lastpass-data-breach&quot;&gt;LastPass Data Breach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberattackers have compromised the internal systems of the password management company LastPass, stealing source code and intellectual property. LastPass said it detected anomalous activity in its development environment. After a forensic investigation, it was determined that the attacker compromised a developer account to gain access to the network, taking intellectual property from the company. The adversaries weren’t able to access customer data or encrypted password vaults according to LastPass. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/lastpass-developer-systems-hacked-to-steal-source-code/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;record-ddos-layer7-attack&quot;&gt;Record DDoS Layer7 Attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google reports a new record for DDoS on Layer 7: The Mēris botnet is believed to have sent a total of up to 46 million requests for HTTPS connections per second to the Google Cloud from 132 countries. The company compares the flood of data packets with all Wikipedia calls in an entire day, concentrated into ten seconds. According to its information, Google was able to fend off the attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/identity-security/how-google-cloud-blocked-largest-layer-7-ddos-attack-at-46-million-rps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-cloudblog-publish/images/DDoS_Attack_Graphic_-_pretty.max-2200x2200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DDoS attack graph peaking at 46M requests per second&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;DDoS attack graph peaking at 46M requests per second / Credit: Google&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prioritize-vulnerability-management-with-ml&quot;&gt;Prioritize Vulnerability Management With ML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get a little suspicious of marketing fluff whenever we see machine learning and security mentioned in the same sentence, but researchers have now created a model for predicting which vulnerabilities will likely result in a functional exploit, an interesting tool for prioritizing patches and estimating risk. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/security-bugs-exploited-model-machine-learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ssh-commit-verification-on-github&quot;&gt;SSH Commit Verification On GitHub&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest service provider for git repositories is now supporting commit verification with self-generated SSH keys. While GPG keys have been supported for a long time, we are now able to use SSH to give others confidence about the origin of a change. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/changelog/2022-08-23-ssh-commit-verification-now-supported/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cloud-isolation-problem-postgresql&quot;&gt;Cloud Isolation Problem: PostgreSQL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tenant separation is a fundamental premise of the cloud and is at the core of trusting your cloud provider. The team of Wiz Research examined how effectively the environments of customers are isolated from each other across different cloud service providers and discovered multiple vulnerabilities in the PostgreSQL offerings of major cloud providers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wiz.io/blog/the-cloud-has-an-isolation-problem-postgresql-vulnerabilities&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-082022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-082022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup July 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;massive-data-breach-in-china&quot;&gt;Massive Data Breach in China&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personally identifiable information (PII) of one billion people in China has been put up for sale on the darknet. The dataset was reportedly extracted from an unsecured Shanghai police database hosted on Alibaba’s cloud hosting platform. There have been countless instances where organizations have similarly exposed sensitive data by leaving it poorly secured. What makes the Shanghai breach notable is its sheer scale. By most accounts, it is one of the largest ever known compromises of PII. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud/questions-massive-shanghai-police-data-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-modeling-field-guide&quot;&gt;Threat Modeling Field Guide&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid guide to a multitude of threat modeling methodologies has been published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shellsharks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shellsharks&lt;/a&gt;. Each of the methods comes with a solid description and visualizations. The Appendix goes into data flow diagrams and tooling to perform the perfect threat modeling session for your use case. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shellsharks.com/threat-modeling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://shellsharks-images.s3.amazonaws.com/2022/threatmodel/data-flow-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hackers hacking&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Data Flow Diagram&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;binary-vulnerability-toolset-with-ghidra-and-semgrep&quot;&gt;Binary Vulnerability Toolset With Ghidra and Semgrep&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/0xdea&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marco Ivaldi&lt;/a&gt; released a technical article about automated vulnerability discovery via static analysis techniques. The walkthrough covers custom scripts for &lt;a href=&quot;https://semgrep.dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;semgrep&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghidra-sre.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ghidra&lt;/a&gt; to build a toolset for binary bug hunting.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.humanativaspa.it/automating-binary-vulnerability-discovery-with-ghidra-and-semgrep/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hackerone-employee-steals-vulnerability-reports-for-personal-gains&quot;&gt;HackerOne Employee Steals Vulnerability Reports for Personal Gains&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A HackerOne employee has been fired for collecting bug bounties from its customers after alerting them to vulnerabilities that were found by other researchers and shared privately with HackerOne through its vulnerability disclosure program. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/hackerone-employee-fired-for-stealing-and-selling-bug-reports-for-personal-gain&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://inversegravity.net/assets/images/culture_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hackers hacking&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hackers&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nist-announces-first-four-quantum-resistant-cryptographic-algorithms&quot;&gt;NIST Announces First Four Quantum-Resistant Cryptographic Algorithms&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security experts have warned that practical quantum computers could break many of today’s popular encryption algorithms, such as RSA and elliptic curve cryptography. On July 5, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) announced the selection of four candidates to form the basis of future data-protection technologies able to withstand attacks from quantum computers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2022/07/nist-announces-first-four-quantum-resistant-cryptographic-algorithms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;most-of-the-domains-in-australia-have-security-issue-with-their-spf-and-dmarc-configuration&quot;&gt;Most Of The Domains in Australia Have Security Issue With Their SPF And DMARC Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastian-salla/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sebastian Salla&lt;/a&gt; scanned 1.7 million Australian domains and checked for various types of SPF &amp;amp; DMARC-related issues. His interesting writeup describes how he ran 400 concurrent lambda functions for 24 hours and reveals the less than optimal results from his scan. &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniphish.com/phishing-resources/blog/australian-spf-scan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;unlock-honda-cars-remotely&quot;&gt;Unlock Honda cars remotely&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of security researchers found that several modern Honda car models have a vulnerable rolling code mechanism that allows unlocking the cars or even starting the engine remotely. Called Rolling-PWN, the weakness enables replay attacks where a threat actor intercepts the codes from the keyfob to the car and uses them to unlock or start the vehicle. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-can-unlock-honda-cars-remotely-in-rolling-pwn-attacks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-to-patch-before-scan-15-minutes&quot;&gt;Time To Patch Before Scan: 15 Minutes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is less time to patch disclosed security vulnerabilities than previously thought, as a new report from Palo Alto’s Unit 42 shows. Threat actors scan for vulnerable endpoints within 15 minutes of a new CVE being publicly disclosed. The speed at which actors target devices and systems only adds additional pressure on security teams that already struggle to get vulnerabilities managed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-scan-for-vulnerabilities-within-15-minutes-of-disclosure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-072022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-072022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup June 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;steampipe-cli&quot;&gt;Steampipe CLI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steampipe.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steampipe&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source CLI to instantly query cloud APIs using SQL-based queries to explore dynamic data. Mods extend Steampipe’s capabilities with dashboards, reports, and controls. One of our favorite modes is the AWS compliance mode which includes 120+ controls for cloud environments. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.steampipe.io/mods/turbot/aws_compliance/dashboards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/turbot/steampipe-mod-aws-compliance/main/docs/aws_cis_v140_console.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steampipe CIS Dashboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Steampipe CIS Dashboard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;code-execution-vulnerability-in-ms-office---follina&quot;&gt;Code Execution Vulnerability In MS Office - Follina&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Follina 0-day vulnerability &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2022-30190&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(CVE-2022-30190)&lt;/a&gt; was made public when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nao_sec/status/1530196847679401984&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nao_sec&lt;/a&gt; reported a malicious Word document on VirusTotal submitted from an IP Address in Belarus. The document performs command execution on a target even though the document is a .docx and does not contain the usual way of exploitation namely macros. &lt;a href=&quot;https://fourcore.io/blogs/follina-ms-office-msdt-code-execution-zero-day-vulnerability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;atlassian-injection-observed-in-the-wild&quot;&gt;Atlassian Injection Observed In The Wild&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a security advisory published on the 2nd of June, Atlassian addressed a remote code execution vulnerability &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2022-26134&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(CVE-2022-26134)&lt;/a&gt; affecting all supported versions of its Confluence Server and Data Center products. This vulnerability allows an unauthenticated remote attacker to execute code. Greynoise documents the details of how quickly this vulnerability was exploited. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greynoise.io/blog/observed-in-the-wild-atlassian-confluence-server-cve-2022-26134&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;analysis-of-the-wizard-spider-hacking-group&quot;&gt;Analysis Of The Wizard Spider Hacking Group&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizard Spider is a highly profitable cybercrime group that operates a number of sophisticated malware variants in its attacks. This report contains a technical analysis of Wizard Spider’s capabilities and its command structure, which includes a complex set of sub-teams divided into software-specific groups. This information can help organizations prepare for highly coordinated cyberattacks that use distributed command structures to exploit high-value targets. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prodaft.com/m/reports/WizardSpider_TLPWHITE_v.1.4.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-intelligence-conti-logs&quot;&gt;Threat Intelligence: Conti Logs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following blog from Microsoft explains a workflow for deeper data analysis and visualization as well as extraction and analysis of indicators of compromise (IOCs). Data sets from the February 2022 leak of data from the ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) coordinated operation called “Conti” is used as a case study. The slang translation dictionary is hilarious. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/06/01/using-python-to-unearth-a-goldmine-of-threat-intelligence-from-leaked-chat-logs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/uploads/securityprod/2022/05/fig-10-connections-to-user-Stern.png&quot; alt=&quot;Graph Connections&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Graph of the connections of a single user&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consider-attackability-for-vulnerability-management&quot;&gt;Consider “Attackability” for Vulnerability Management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As vulnerability-management workloads surge in the face of heightened software supply chain security risks, a study reports only 3% of flaws can actually be exploited. The study also explores how to find and fix the critical 3%. It is suggested to execute a simplified threat analysis for open-source vulnerabilities resulting in a “attackability” and “reachability” score. While seeking a prioritization model like this is nothing new, the article provides a great perspective. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/open-source-software-bugs--attackability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;7-steps-to-stronger-saas-security&quot;&gt;7 Steps to Stronger SaaS Security&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software-as-a-service (SaaS) application security is often a blind spot, so give your SaaS ecosystem some extra attention with the suggested 7 basic steps. SaaS is ubiquitous, highly configurable, and continuously updated, leaving many organizations vulnerable if they aren’t closely monitoring for security gaps and changes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud/7-steps-to-stronger-saas-security&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-062022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-062022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloud Security Toolkit</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;technologies-such-as-kubernetes-and-terraform-have-revolutionized-the-way-how-scalable-applications-are-deployed-by-using-cloud-native-tools-companies-can-focus-on-implementing-the-business-logic-of-their-applications-rather-than-having-to-maintain-a-dedicated-it-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Technologies such as Kubernetes and Terraform have revolutionized the way how scalable applications are deployed. By using cloud-native tools, companies can focus on implementing the business logic of their applications rather than having to maintain a dedicated IT infrastructure.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such environments, cloud security requires special attention - but it must also keep pace with technological advancements. What are the right priorities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/03/25/01/49/abstract-1278060_960_720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CVSS logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Picture: insspirito/pixabay.com&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shared-responsibility-model&quot;&gt;Shared Responsibility Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a misconception that cloud applications are more secure out of the box because the provider takes care of security. Security in the cloud remains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/whitepapers/latest/aws-risk-and-compliance/shared-responsibility-model.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shared responsibility&lt;/a&gt; between the user and the provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the shared responsibility model, the cloud provider is responsible, among other things, for the physical security of the hardware or the up-to-dateness of the drivers, for the underlying operating system, the runtime environments, and the physical protection of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud users, however, remain responsible for application security and the correct configuration of the cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User overall responsibility varies from 8 to 52 percent, as estimated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ory_51733/serverless-and-the-evolution-in-cloud-security-how-faas-differs-from-iaas-4ea8bc7b1dff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ory Segal&lt;/a&gt;. In the following sections, we will outline best practices and tools that specifically apply to the responsibilities of cloud customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-security-with-sca&quot;&gt;Application Security with SCA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Composition Analysis (SCA) examines which third-party libraries are contained in an application. This is necessary to detect existing security vulnerabilities in the third-party libraries, better known as &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/cve-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVEs (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an analysis of the software composition also examines the application environment. For example, it looks at which applications and shared libraries are installed in a virtual machine or Docker container and whether they contain known security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCA has become an inevitable tool for enforcing application security. This is mainly due to the fact that software nowadays makes extensive use of existing code in the form of libraries instead of reinventing the wheel for each project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-security-with-sast&quot;&gt;Application Security with SAST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static Application Security Testing (SAST) is essential in any well-structured Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC). It examines the source code of applications to identify security vulnerabilities and anti-patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many commercial and free tools exist on the market for performing static code analyses. Some can be integrated as plug-ins directly into the developer’s integrated development environment (IDE) so that developers already receive early feedback on potential security vulnerabilities. This “shift left” approach prevents surprises during the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-configuration-security-with-ciem&quot;&gt;Cloud Configuration Security with CIEM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access management is an essential security topic and is used to manage access to services and resources. In addition to the individual cloud resources such as databases, virtual machines, containers, functions, and S3 buckets that communicate with each other, it is also necessary to tightly manage user accounts in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Infrastructure Entitlements Management (CIEM) is the right tool for this and provides a graphical representation of the access permissions within the cloud. From an organizational perspective, CIEM allows the access permissions to be kept to a minimum in line with the Principle of Least Privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-configuration-security-with-cspm&quot;&gt;Cloud Configuration Security with CSPM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM) tool finds misconfigurations within a cloud account. It checks all resources for conformity with common rule sets such as the Service Organization Control 2 (SOC2), Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), or the benchmarks of the Center of Internet Security (CIS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common rules in the benchmarks include typical errors such as open ports for SSH, missing data encryption in transit or at rest, or publicly exposed resources such as S3 buckets and databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;context-and-prioritization&quot;&gt;Context and Prioritization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mentioned tools are essential to secure cloud environments. Errors in the cloud setup or vulnerabilities in the application can easily open a door for attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, security teams would close all vulnerabilities as soon as they appear - but the reality is more complex. DevOps and Security teams are often understaffed in terms of personnel and available resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams need to focus on the most critical issues to keep up with the large number of alerts from various tools. Often, the severity assigned to vulnerabilities automatically define the priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But judging solely based on severity can easily lead to misjudgment. For example, an affected database server could be an unused test instance that cannot be reached from the internet and doesn’t have any critical data on it. The priority of such a vulnerable database would be low despite a high severity of a finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security teams have to be cautious when prioritizing mitigation activities and can’t exclusively rely on severity scores. The full picture (context) of the application and environment is necessary to accurately assess the risk of a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-security/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup May 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update-on-the-viasat-satellite-network-cyberattack&quot;&gt;Update on the ViaSat satellite network cyberattack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start this months news with an update on the ViaSat attack. We have been tracking this story in our updates from &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-032022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;March&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-042022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;April&lt;/a&gt;. One of the first signs of the hack occurred when more than 5,800 wind turbines belonging to the German energy company Enercon were knocked offline. Russia is now accused of being responsible for the mysterious satellite hack - Ukraine’s military was the primary target and EU countries were collateral damage the article explains. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/05/us-and-its-allies-say-russia-waged-cyberattack-that-took-out-satellite-network/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interactive-kubernetes-security-learning-playground&quot;&gt;Interactive Kubernetes Security Learning Playground&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning and understanding Kubernetes security in a safe, practical, and efficient way can be challenging. Kubernetes Goat may just have solved this problem not only for security researchers but also for DevOps teams, and anyone interested in learning Kubernetes security. &lt;a href=&quot;https://madhuakula.com/kubernetes-goat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-targeted-by-a-package-backfill-attack&quot;&gt;AWS Targeted by a Package Backfill Attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS is not only the largest provider of cloud infrastructure in the world but also a major contributor to open-source components. The folks at WhiteSource have identified a targeted attack on some discontinued AWS packages. The malicious actors use a method called backfill attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitesourcesoftware.com/resources/blog/aws-targeted-by-a-package-backfill-attack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ransomware-as-a-service-understanding-the-cybercrime-gig-economy&quot;&gt;Ransomware-as-a-service: Understanding the cybercrime gig economy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cybercriminal economy - a network of players with a variety of skills, tools, and techniques - is evolving. The industrialization of attacks has progressed from malicious actors using off-the-shelf tools - to attackers being able to purchase network access and the payloads they deploy. Microsoft the RaaS affiliate model and how to protect yourself explains in this interesting article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/05/09/ransomware-as-a-service-understanding-the-cybercrime-gig-economy-and-how-to-protect-yourself/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/uploads/securityprod/2022/05/Fig1-RaaS-affiliate-model-3-1024x496.png&quot; alt=&quot;How the RaaS affiliate model enables ransomware attacks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;How the RaaS affiliate model enables ransomware attacks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;five-eyes-issue-a-warning-to-managed-service-providers&quot;&gt;Five Eyes issue a warning to Managed Service Providers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the Five Eyes (FVEY) intelligence alliance issued a warning for managed service providers and their customers regarding supply chain attacks. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/alerts/aa22-131a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; states that if an attacker can compromise a service provider, then the resulting malicious activity could affect the provider’s infrastructure, and its customers. While the document is specifically issued to service providers, it highlights proper security measures applicable for any business handling sensitive data. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fbi-cisa-and-nsa-warn-of-hackers-increasingly-targeting-msps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://pypi.org/static/images/logo-large.6bdbb439.svg&quot; alt=&quot;PyPI logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PyPI logo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-supply-chain-attack-i-typosquatting&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain Attack I: Typosquatting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typosquatting occurs when an attacker takes a popular framework or library, adds malicious code, and publishes it in a package repository under a similar name to the original. And this is exactly what happened in the Python Package Index (PyPI). The linked article goes over the infection process and how to stay safe from such attacks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-pypi-package-opens-backdoors-on-windows-linux-and-macs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-supply-chain-attack-ii-malicious-code&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain Attack II: Malicious Code&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Python module “ctx” that gets downloaded over 20,000 times a week was replaced with a malicious version that stole the developer’s environment variables. This “new” version exfiltrates the developer’s environment variables, to collect secrets like Amazon AWS keys and credentials. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/popular-python-and-php-libraries-hijacked-to-steal-aws-keys/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;strategies-to-communicate-the-value-of-a-security-program&quot;&gt;Strategies to communicate the value of a security program&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/george-do-a473432/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;George Do&lt;/a&gt;, CISO and former NASA security engineer, gave the keynote address at Black Hat Asia this week about his go-to model for measuring security effectiveness - and how to influence others in the organization. We appreciate the approach to winning hearts and minds as a security professional. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/operations/black-hat-asia-top-strategies-communicate-security-value-biz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-security-maturity-model&quot;&gt;AWS Security Maturity Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good advice on how to improve the security maturity in AWS by breaking things down into the following phases: quick wins, foundational, efficient, and optimized. The website includes many videos and whitepapers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://maturitymodel.security.aws.dev/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;attackers-stole-login-details-of-100k-npm-users&quot;&gt;Attackers stole login details of 100K npm users&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub reported that an attacker stole the login credentials of roughly 100,000 npm accounts in mid-April using stolen OAuth app tokens issued by Heroku and Travis-CI. The threat actor escalated their access using a compromised AWS access key, acquired after downloading multiple private npm repositories using the stolen OAuth user tokens in the initial stage of the attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/github-attackers-stole-login-details-of-100k-npm-user-accounts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-052022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-052022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
