<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>cyber security and technology blog</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 08:13:36 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 08:13:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup August 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;our-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Our selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consequences-of-inadequate-identity-management-in-github&quot;&gt;Consequences of Inadequate Identity Management in GitHub&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Identity and Access Management is a major area of concern for security teams, including source control management like GitHub. The blog article raises three major risks people should be aware of. In addition, we suggest taking a good look at the CI/CD system and the service accounts controlling production environments. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cidersecurity.io/blog/research/the-consequences-of-inadequate-identity-management-in-your-github-organization/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;building-a-product-security-program&quot;&gt;Building A Product Security Program&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anshuman Bhartiya writes on his blog about the different aspects of building a product security program from scratch. He writes about the essential topics of risk appetite, prioritization, relationships, and empathy. This article is a great start for anyone who has to implement a secure development approach in an organization. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anshumanbhartiya.com/posts/building-product-security-program&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;get-a-headstart-on-post-quantum-cryptography&quot;&gt;Get A Headstart On Post-Quantum Cryptography&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topic of post-quantum (PQ) cryptography describes the fact practically all data sent over the Internet today is at risk in the future if a stable quantum computer is created. Cloudflare has released open-source software and experimental services to test post-quantum key agreements. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.cloudflare.com/experiment-with-pq/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/07/18/07/39/quantum-mechanics-1525470_960_720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Quantum Mechanics&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Quantum Mechanics / Credit: pixabay.com&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cisco-data-breach&quot;&gt;Cisco Data Breach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco has confirmed a breach of its network, the attacker used voice phishing to convince an employee to accept a malicious multifactor authentication (MFA). With access established, the attacker then moved through the network by escalating privileges and logging into multiple systems. Cisco believes the threat actor is an initial access broker - an adversary that gains unauthorized access to networks and then sells that access on the Dark Web. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/attacks-breaches/cisco-confirms-data-breach-hacked-files-leaked&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cisco Talos did a great write-up with all the details related to the cyber attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.talosintelligence.com/2022/08/recent-cyber-attack.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lastpass-data-breach&quot;&gt;LastPass Data Breach&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cyberattackers have compromised the internal systems of the password management company LastPass, stealing source code and intellectual property. LastPass said it detected anomalous activity in its development environment. After a forensic investigation, it was determined that the attacker compromised a developer account to gain access to the network, taking intellectual property from the company. The adversaries weren’t able to access customer data or encrypted password vaults according to LastPass. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/lastpass-developer-systems-hacked-to-steal-source-code/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;record-ddos-layer7-attack&quot;&gt;Record DDoS Layer7 Attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google reports a new record for DDoS on Layer 7: The Mēris botnet is believed to have sent a total of up to 46 million requests for HTTPS connections per second to the Google Cloud from 132 countries. The company compares the flood of data packets with all Wikipedia calls in an entire day, concentrated into ten seconds. According to its information, Google was able to fend off the attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/identity-security/how-google-cloud-blocked-largest-layer-7-ddos-attack-at-46-million-rps&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://storage.googleapis.com/gweb-cloudblog-publish/images/DDoS_Attack_Graphic_-_pretty.max-2200x2200.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;DDoS attack graph peaking at 46M requests per second&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;DDoS attack graph peaking at 46M requests per second / Credit: Google&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prioritize-vulnerability-management-with-ml&quot;&gt;Prioritize Vulnerability Management With ML&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We get a little suspicious of marketing fluff whenever we see machine learning and security mentioned in the same sentence, but researchers have now created a model for predicting which vulnerabilities will likely result in a functional exploit, an interesting tool for prioritizing patches and estimating risk. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/security-bugs-exploited-model-machine-learning&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ssh-commit-verification-on-github&quot;&gt;SSH Commit Verification On GitHub&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest service provider for git repositories is now supporting commit verification with self-generated SSH keys. While GPG keys have been supported for a long time, we are now able to use SSH to give others confidence about the origin of a change. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/changelog/2022-08-23-ssh-commit-verification-now-supported/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cloud-isolation-problem-postgresql&quot;&gt;Cloud Isolation Problem: PostgreSQL&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tenant separation is a fundamental premise of the cloud and is at the core of trusting your cloud provider. The team of Wiz Research examined how effectively the environments of customers are isolated from each other across different cloud service providers and discovered multiple vulnerabilities in the PostgreSQL offerings of major cloud providers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wiz.io/blog/the-cloud-has-an-isolation-problem-postgresql-vulnerabilities&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-082022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-082022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup July 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;massive-data-breach-in-china&quot;&gt;Massive Data Breach in China&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personally identifiable information (PII) of one billion people in China has been put up for sale on the darknet. The dataset was reportedly extracted from an unsecured Shanghai police database hosted on Alibaba’s cloud hosting platform. There have been countless instances where organizations have similarly exposed sensitive data by leaving it poorly secured. What makes the Shanghai breach notable is its sheer scale. By most accounts, it is one of the largest ever known compromises of PII. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud/questions-massive-shanghai-police-data-breach&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-modeling-field-guide&quot;&gt;Threat Modeling Field Guide&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid guide to a multitude of threat modeling methodologies has been published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/shellsharks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shellsharks&lt;/a&gt;. Each of the methods comes with a solid description and visualizations. The Appendix goes into data flow diagrams and tooling to perform the perfect threat modeling session for your use case. &lt;a href=&quot;https://shellsharks.com/threat-modeling&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://shellsharks-images.s3.amazonaws.com/2022/threatmodel/data-flow-diagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hackers hacking&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Data Flow Diagram&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;binary-vulnerability-toolset-with-ghidra-and-semgrep&quot;&gt;Binary Vulnerability Toolset With Ghidra and Semgrep&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/0xdea&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Marco Ivaldi&lt;/a&gt; released a technical article about automated vulnerability discovery via static analysis techniques. The walkthrough covers custom scripts for &lt;a href=&quot;https://semgrep.dev/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;semgrep&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ghidra-sre.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ghidra&lt;/a&gt; to build a toolset for binary bug hunting.  &lt;a href=&quot;https://security.humanativaspa.it/automating-binary-vulnerability-discovery-with-ghidra-and-semgrep/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;hackerone-employee-steals-vulnerability-reports-for-personal-gains&quot;&gt;HackerOne Employee Steals Vulnerability Reports for Personal Gains&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A HackerOne employee has been fired for collecting bug bounties from its customers after alerting them to vulnerabilities that were found by other researchers and shared privately with HackerOne through its vulnerability disclosure program. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/hackerone-employee-fired-for-stealing-and-selling-bug-reports-for-personal-gain&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://inversegravity.net/assets/images/culture_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Hackers hacking&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Hackers&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nist-announces-first-four-quantum-resistant-cryptographic-algorithms&quot;&gt;NIST Announces First Four Quantum-Resistant Cryptographic Algorithms&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security experts have warned that practical quantum computers could break many of today’s popular encryption algorithms, such as RSA and elliptic curve cryptography. On July 5, the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) announced the selection of four candidates to form the basis of future data-protection technologies able to withstand attacks from quantum computers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/news-events/news/2022/07/nist-announces-first-four-quantum-resistant-cryptographic-algorithms&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;most-of-the-domains-in-australia-have-security-issue-with-their-spf-and-dmarc-configuration&quot;&gt;Most Of The Domains in Australia Have Security Issue With Their SPF And DMARC Configuration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/sebastian-salla/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sebastian Salla&lt;/a&gt; scanned 1.7 million Australian domains and checked for various types of SPF &amp;amp; DMARC-related issues. His interesting writeup describes how he ran 400 concurrent lambda functions for 24 hours and reveals the less than optimal results from his scan. &lt;a href=&quot;https://caniphish.com/phishing-resources/blog/australian-spf-scan&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;unlock-honda-cars-remotely&quot;&gt;Unlock Honda cars remotely&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A team of security researchers found that several modern Honda car models have a vulnerable rolling code mechanism that allows unlocking the cars or even starting the engine remotely. Called Rolling-PWN, the weakness enables replay attacks where a threat actor intercepts the codes from the keyfob to the car and uses them to unlock or start the vehicle. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-can-unlock-honda-cars-remotely-in-rolling-pwn-attacks/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;time-to-patch-before-scan-15-minutes&quot;&gt;Time To Patch Before Scan: 15 Minutes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is less time to patch disclosed security vulnerabilities than previously thought, as a new report from Palo Alto’s Unit 42 shows. Threat actors scan for vulnerable endpoints within 15 minutes of a new CVE being publicly disclosed. The speed at which actors target devices and systems only adds additional pressure on security teams that already struggle to get vulnerabilities managed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/hackers-scan-for-vulnerabilities-within-15-minutes-of-disclosure/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-072022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-072022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup June 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;steampipe-cli&quot;&gt;Steampipe CLI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://steampipe.io/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Steampipe&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source CLI to instantly query cloud APIs using SQL-based queries to explore dynamic data. Mods extend Steampipe’s capabilities with dashboards, reports, and controls. One of our favorite modes is the AWS compliance mode which includes 120+ controls for cloud environments. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hub.steampipe.io/mods/turbot/aws_compliance/dashboards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/turbot/steampipe-mod-aws-compliance/main/docs/aws_cis_v140_console.png&quot; alt=&quot;Steampipe CIS Dashboard&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Steampipe CIS Dashboard&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;code-execution-vulnerability-in-ms-office---follina&quot;&gt;Code Execution Vulnerability In MS Office - Follina&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Follina 0-day vulnerability &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2022-30190&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(CVE-2022-30190)&lt;/a&gt; was made public when &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/nao_sec/status/1530196847679401984&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;nao_sec&lt;/a&gt; reported a malicious Word document on VirusTotal submitted from an IP Address in Belarus. The document performs command execution on a target even though the document is a .docx and does not contain the usual way of exploitation namely macros. &lt;a href=&quot;https://fourcore.io/blogs/follina-ms-office-msdt-code-execution-zero-day-vulnerability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;atlassian-injection-observed-in-the-wild&quot;&gt;Atlassian Injection Observed In The Wild&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a security advisory published on the 2nd of June, Atlassian addressed a remote code execution vulnerability &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=2022-26134&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;(CVE-2022-26134)&lt;/a&gt; affecting all supported versions of its Confluence Server and Data Center products. This vulnerability allows an unauthenticated remote attacker to execute code. Greynoise documents the details of how quickly this vulnerability was exploited. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.greynoise.io/blog/observed-in-the-wild-atlassian-confluence-server-cve-2022-26134&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;analysis-of-the-wizard-spider-hacking-group&quot;&gt;Analysis Of The Wizard Spider Hacking Group&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wizard Spider is a highly profitable cybercrime group that operates a number of sophisticated malware variants in its attacks. This report contains a technical analysis of Wizard Spider’s capabilities and its command structure, which includes a complex set of sub-teams divided into software-specific groups. This information can help organizations prepare for highly coordinated cyberattacks that use distributed command structures to exploit high-value targets. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prodaft.com/m/reports/WizardSpider_TLPWHITE_v.1.4.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-intelligence-conti-logs&quot;&gt;Threat Intelligence: Conti Logs&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following blog from Microsoft explains a workflow for deeper data analysis and visualization as well as extraction and analysis of indicators of compromise (IOCs). Data sets from the February 2022 leak of data from the ransomware-as-a-service (RaaS) coordinated operation called “Conti” is used as a case study. The slang translation dictionary is hilarious. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/06/01/using-python-to-unearth-a-goldmine-of-threat-intelligence-from-leaked-chat-logs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/uploads/securityprod/2022/05/fig-10-connections-to-user-Stern.png&quot; alt=&quot;Graph Connections&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Graph of the connections of a single user&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;consider-attackability-for-vulnerability-management&quot;&gt;Consider “Attackability” for Vulnerability Management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As vulnerability-management workloads surge in the face of heightened software supply chain security risks, a study reports only 3% of flaws can actually be exploited. The study also explores how to find and fix the critical 3%. It is suggested to execute a simplified threat analysis for open-source vulnerabilities resulting in a “attackability” and “reachability” score. While seeking a prioritization model like this is nothing new, the article provides a great perspective. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/open-source-software-bugs--attackability&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;7-steps-to-stronger-saas-security&quot;&gt;7 Steps to Stronger SaaS Security&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software-as-a-service (SaaS) application security is often a blind spot, so give your SaaS ecosystem some extra attention with the suggested 7 basic steps. SaaS is ubiquitous, highly configurable, and continuously updated, leaving many organizations vulnerable if they aren’t closely monitoring for security gaps and changes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud/7-steps-to-stronger-saas-security&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-062022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-062022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloud Security Toolkit</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;technologies-such-as-kubernetes-and-terraform-have-revolutionized-the-way-how-scalable-applications-are-deployed-using-cloud-native-applications-companies-can-focus-on-implementing-the-business-logic-of-their-applications-rather-than-having-to-maintain-a-dedicated-it-infrastructure&quot;&gt;Technologies such as Kubernetes and Terraform have revolutionized the way how scalable applications are deployed. Using cloud-native applications, companies can focus on implementing the business logic of their applications rather than having to maintain a dedicated IT infrastructure.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such environments, cloud security requires special attention - but it must also keep pace with technological advancements. What are the right priorities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.pixabay.com/photo/2016/03/25/01/49/abstract-1278060_960_720.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;CVSS logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Picture: insspirito/pixabay.com&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;shared-responsibility-model&quot;&gt;Shared Responsibility Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a misconception that cloud applications are more secure out of the box because the provider takes care of security. Security in the cloud remains a &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.aws.amazon.com/whitepapers/latest/aws-risk-and-compliance/shared-responsibility-model.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;shared responsibility&lt;/a&gt; between the user and the provider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the shared responsibility model, the cloud provider is responsible, among other things, for the physical security of the hardware or the up-to-dateness of the drivers, for the underlying operating system, the runtime environments, and the physical protection of the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud users, however, remain responsible for application security and the correct configuration of the cloud environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;User overall responsibility varies from 8 to 52 percent, as estimated by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ory_51733/serverless-and-the-evolution-in-cloud-security-how-faas-differs-from-iaas-4ea8bc7b1dff&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ory Segal&lt;/a&gt;. In the following sections, we will outline best practices and tools that specifically apply to the responsibilities of cloud customers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-security-with-sca&quot;&gt;Application Security with SCA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Composition Analysis (SCA) examines which third-party libraries are contained in an application. This is necessary to detect existing security vulnerabilities in the third-party libraries, better known as &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/cve-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVEs (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such an analysis of the software composition also examines the application environment. For example, it looks at which applications and shared libraries are installed in a virtual machine or Docker container and whether they contain known security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCA has become an inevitable tool for enforcing application security. This is mainly due to the fact that software nowadays makes extensive use of existing code in the form of libraries instead of reinventing the wheel for each project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;application-security-with-sast&quot;&gt;Application Security with SAST&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static Application Security Testing (SAST) is essential in any well-structured Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC). It examines the source code of applications to identify security vulnerabilities and anti-patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many commercial and free tools exist on the market for performing static code analyses. Some can be integrated as plug-ins directly into the developer’s integrated development environment (IDE) so that developers already receive early feedback on potential security vulnerabilities. This “shift left” approach prevents surprises during the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-configuration-security-with-ciem&quot;&gt;Cloud Configuration Security with CIEM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Access management is an essential security topic and is used to manage access to services and resources. In addition to the individual cloud resources such as databases, virtual machines, containers, functions, and S3 buckets that communicate with each other, it is also necessary to tightly manage user accounts in the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud Infrastructure Entitlements Management (CIEM) is the right tool for this and provides a graphical representation of the access permissions within the cloud. From an organizational perspective, CIEM allows the access permissions to be kept to a minimum in line with the Principle of Least Privilege.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cloud-configuration-security-with-cspm&quot;&gt;Cloud Configuration Security with CSPM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Cloud Security Posture Management (CSPM) tool finds misconfigurations within a cloud account. It checks all resources for conformity with common rule sets such as the Service Organization Control 2 (SOC2), Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard (PCI DSS), or the benchmarks of the Center of Internet Security (CIS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Common rules in the benchmarks include typical errors such as open ports for SSH, missing data encryption in transit or at rest, or publicly exposed resources such as S3 buckets and databases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;context-and-prioritization&quot;&gt;Context and Prioritization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mentioned tools are essential to secure cloud environments. Errors in the cloud setup or vulnerabilities in the application can easily open a door for attackers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an ideal world, security teams would close all vulnerabilities as soon as they appear - but the reality is more complex. DevOps and Security teams are often understaffed in terms of personnel and available resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams need to focus on the most critical issues to keep up with the large number of alerts from various tools. Often, the severity assigned to vulnerabilities automatically define the priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But judging solely based on severity can easily lead to misjudgment. For example, an affected database server could be an unused test instance that cannot be reached from the internet and doesn’t have any critical data on it. The priority of such a vulnerable database would be low despite a high severity of a finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security teams have to be cautious when prioritizing mitigation activities and can’t exclusively rely on severity scores. The full picture (context) of the application and environment is necessary to accurately assess the risk of a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-security/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup May 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;update-on-the-viasat-satellite-network-cyberattack&quot;&gt;Update on the ViaSat satellite network cyberattack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We start this months news with an update on the ViaSat attack. We have been tracking this story in our updates from &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-032022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;March&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-042022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;April&lt;/a&gt;. One of the first signs of the hack occurred when more than 5,800 wind turbines belonging to the German energy company Enercon were knocked offline. Russia is now accused of being responsible for the mysterious satellite hack - Ukraine’s military was the primary target and EU countries were collateral damage the article explains. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/05/us-and-its-allies-say-russia-waged-cyberattack-that-took-out-satellite-network/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;interactive-kubernetes-security-learning-playground&quot;&gt;Interactive Kubernetes Security Learning Playground&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning and understanding Kubernetes security in a safe, practical, and efficient way can be challenging. Kubernetes Goat may just have solved this problem not only for security researchers but also for DevOps teams, and anyone interested in learning Kubernetes security. &lt;a href=&quot;https://madhuakula.com/kubernetes-goat/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-targeted-by-a-package-backfill-attack&quot;&gt;AWS Targeted by a Package Backfill Attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AWS is not only the largest provider of cloud infrastructure in the world but also a major contributor to open-source components. The folks at WhiteSource have identified a targeted attack on some discontinued AWS packages. The malicious actors use a method called backfill attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.whitesourcesoftware.com/resources/blog/aws-targeted-by-a-package-backfill-attack/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ransomware-as-a-service-understanding-the-cybercrime-gig-economy&quot;&gt;Ransomware-as-a-service: Understanding the cybercrime gig economy&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cybercriminal economy - a network of players with a variety of skills, tools, and techniques - is evolving. The industrialization of attacks has progressed from malicious actors using off-the-shelf tools - to attackers being able to purchase network access and the payloads they deploy. Microsoft the RaaS affiliate model and how to protect yourself explains in this interesting article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/2022/05/09/ransomware-as-a-service-understanding-the-cybercrime-gig-economy-and-how-to-protect-yourself/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/security/blog/uploads/securityprod/2022/05/Fig1-RaaS-affiliate-model-3-1024x496.png&quot; alt=&quot;How the RaaS affiliate model enables ransomware attacks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;How the RaaS affiliate model enables ransomware attacks&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;five-eyes-issue-a-warning-to-managed-service-providers&quot;&gt;Five Eyes issue a warning to Managed Service Providers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Members of the Five Eyes (FVEY) intelligence alliance issued a warning for managed service providers and their customers regarding supply chain attacks. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cisa.gov/uscert/ncas/alerts/aa22-131a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;advisory&lt;/a&gt; states that if an attacker can compromise a service provider, then the resulting malicious activity could affect the provider’s infrastructure, and its customers. While the document is specifically issued to service providers, it highlights proper security measures applicable for any business handling sensitive data. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/fbi-cisa-and-nsa-warn-of-hackers-increasingly-targeting-msps/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://pypi.org/static/images/logo-large.6bdbb439.svg&quot; alt=&quot;PyPI logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;PyPI logo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-supply-chain-attack-i-typosquatting&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain Attack I: Typosquatting&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typosquatting occurs when an attacker takes a popular framework or library, adds malicious code, and publishes it in a package repository under a similar name to the original. And this is exactly what happened in the Python Package Index (PyPI). The linked article goes over the infection process and how to stay safe from such attacks. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/malicious-pypi-package-opens-backdoors-on-windows-linux-and-macs/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;software-supply-chain-attack-ii-malicious-code&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain Attack II: Malicious Code&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Python module “ctx” that gets downloaded over 20,000 times a week was replaced with a malicious version that stole the developer’s environment variables. This “new” version exfiltrates the developer’s environment variables, to collect secrets like Amazon AWS keys and credentials. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/popular-python-and-php-libraries-hijacked-to-steal-aws-keys/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;strategies-to-communicate-the-value-of-a-security-program&quot;&gt;Strategies to communicate the value of a security program&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/george-do-a473432/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;George Do&lt;/a&gt;, CISO and former NASA security engineer, gave the keynote address at Black Hat Asia this week about his go-to model for measuring security effectiveness - and how to influence others in the organization. We appreciate the approach to winning hearts and minds as a security professional. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/operations/black-hat-asia-top-strategies-communicate-security-value-biz&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-security-maturity-model&quot;&gt;AWS Security Maturity Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good advice on how to improve the security maturity in AWS by breaking things down into the following phases: quick wins, foundational, efficient, and optimized. The website includes many videos and whitepapers. &lt;a href=&quot;https://maturitymodel.security.aws.dev/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;attackers-stole-login-details-of-100k-npm-users&quot;&gt;Attackers stole login details of 100K npm users&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub reported that an attacker stole the login credentials of roughly 100,000 npm accounts in mid-April using stolen OAuth app tokens issued by Heroku and Travis-CI. The threat actor escalated their access using a compromised AWS access key, acquired after downloading multiple private npm repositories using the stolen OAuth user tokens in the initial stage of the attack. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/github-attackers-stole-login-details-of-100k-npm-user-accounts/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-052022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-052022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CVSS - The Vulnerability Scoring System</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-common-vulnerability-scoring-system-cvss-is-an-industry-standard-for-assessing-the-severity-of-potential-or-actual-vulnerabilities-in-computer-systems-we-explain-how-the-system-works-and-its-limitations&quot;&gt;The Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) is an industry-standard for assessing the severity of potential or actual vulnerabilities in computer systems. We explain how the system works and its limitations.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A scoring system is mainly concerned with assessing the threat posed by a security vulnerability. In some cases, this is easy, but the facts are not always clear and the question is how can the severity of a vulnerability be quantified systematically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vulnerability-risk-analysis&quot;&gt;Vulnerability Risk Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities are usually assessed using the method of risk analysis. In this process, the probability of exploits occurring and the possible damage they may cause are estimated. Assessments can, however, always be interpreted in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In vulnerability scoring systems, predefined factors are used to help quantify the degree and probability of damage as objectively as possible. The Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) describes vulnerability characteristics and determines the severity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/identity/cvss_web.png&quot; alt=&quot;CVSS logo&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;CVSS logo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cvss-metrics&quot;&gt;CVSS Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With CVSS, vulnerabilities are assessed based on so-called metrics. There are predefined options for each category and these are used to calculate a severity level from 0.0 to 10.0, with 10.0 corresponding to the highest possible severity level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on these numerical values, qualitative categories are then assigned (None, Low, Medium, High, and Critical), which are also familiar from vulnerability reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metrics are divided into three groups: Base Metrics, Temporal Metrics, and Environmental Metrics. Base metrics describe the essential technical and unchanging characteristics of a vulnerability. From these, a so-called “base score” can be calculated, which represents the technical severity of a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be readjusted later and adapted to changes over time (temporal metrics) or the environment of the affected system (environmental metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/v3-1/media/MetricGroups.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The CVSS metrics are divided into three groups&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The CVSS metrics are divided into three groups&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For vulnerabilities, a CVE ID is usually assigned as a unique vulnerability identifier in the format CVE-YYYY-NNNN. We have a separate detailed article on the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/cve-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVE System&lt;/a&gt; if you want to delve deeper into the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVSS assigns a severity level to vulnerabilities and CVE assigns a unique identifier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;base-score&quot;&gt;Base Score&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic metrics are used to calculate the probability of an attack (exploitability metrics) and the consequences of exploitation (impact metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prerequisites include, among others, if an attack can be carried out via the Internet or whether physical access to a system is required (attack vector).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also assessed if an attack can be carried out unauthenticated or if an attacker must have a valid user account with certain privileges (privileges required).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most critical determinant of the consequences of a successful attack is whether data can be extracted from the affected system, changed on the system, or if its availability can be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it is determined to what extent the protection goals of confidentiality, integrity, and availability (&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/cia-triad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CIA&lt;/a&gt;) are compromised by successful exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To calculate the base score, the metrics are offset against each other. Most CVSS assessments on the Internet use this score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adjustments&quot;&gt;Adjustments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base score can later be adapted to temporal changes (Temporal Metrics) or adjusted to the respective environment of the affected system (Environmental Metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, temporal changes occur when there is no longer just a possible description of an abstract vulnerability, but a fully functional exploit appears in the wild (exploit code maturity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criticality can also decrease if a workaround or an official manufacturer fix is available for the vulnerability (remediation level).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environmental metrics allow the score to be adapted to the specific IT environment within an organization. Depending on the importance of a system, the base score is upgraded or downgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/v3-1/media/EquationsDiagram.svg&quot; alt=&quot;CVSS Metrics and Equations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;CVSS Metrics and Equations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;severity&quot;&gt;Severity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base Score, Temporal Score, and Environmental Score are added up to a total score in the end. For each individual score as well as for the total score, a numerical value is obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These values are categorized in severity levels from “None” to “Critical”. This qualitative assignment is optional and primarily intended to support companies in prioritization when doing vulnerability management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview of the CVSS vector structure is provided by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/calculator/3.1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVSS Calculator&lt;/a&gt;. Metrics can easily be calculated via a web interface and scores and vectors are automatically calculated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-bias&quot;&gt;Assessment Bias&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities should be assessed as unbiased as possible. The interests of the person doing the assessment are likely to play a role. Manufacturers argue that they have a better basis of information and sometimes talk down vulnerabilities to avoid bad press. Researchers might benefit from a high rating of a finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, discussions within the security community usually have a correcting effect on such bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.0 of CVSS is already being actively &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1qmmk9TQulW9d1cuipu_ziXDX0pUswbZ1WSQyynHbvKU/edit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt;. The Temporale Metrics are to be improved and the introduction of supplemental metrics like “Mitigation Effort” or “Provider-Specific Urgency” is discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After almost two decades CVSS has become an indispensable part of vulnerability management and helps organizations to prioritize incidents with software and components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All metrics, options, and formulas of CVSS are described in detail in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/specification-document&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;specifications&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/user-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt; provides additional information on the usage of CVSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cvss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cvss/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Software Assurance Maturity Model</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;security-is-a-major-concern-for-all-software-products-introducing-security-activities-into-the-development-process-can-be-a-challenging-task-to-be-successful-close-integration-with-existing-processes-is-essential-to-embed-the-new-tasks-seamlessly-into-the-tried-and-tested-processes&quot;&gt;Security is a major concern for all software products. Introducing security activities into the development process can be a challenging task. To be successful, close integration with existing processes is essential to embed the new tasks seamlessly into the tried and tested processes.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) has developed a useful framework for this purpose in the form of the Software Assurance Maturity Model &lt;a href=&quot;https://owaspsamm.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SAMM&lt;/a&gt;. It enables companies not only to measure the maturity of their software development processes in terms of security but also to iteratively improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://owaspsamm.org//img/pages/SAMM_v2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The v2 SAMM&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The v2 SAMM&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maturity-model&quot;&gt;Maturity Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current version of the model (v2) is based on a set of 15 security practices grouped into five core areas of business functions. Governance, design, implementation, verification, and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on a detailed catalog of questions, companies can determine their maturity level not only per individual activity but also aggregated to the respective areas and the entire development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the evaluation of the actual situation, an evaluation of the maturity development over time can be presented, which enables the visualization of the project progress and a comparison with the targeted milestones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maturity model is agnostic in terms of techniques and development methodology, but a certain affinity to agile development methods cannot be denied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial maturity graph for a startup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Initial maturity graph for a startup&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;governance&quot;&gt;Governance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The governance chapter aims at key performance indicators (KPIs) which enables teams to see if they have achieved the targeted progress and where intervention is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it covers the policy and compliance of projects and the suppliers of third-party components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-trained and motivated employees are a key factor for a successful security program. These security champions are not only characterized by their interest and knowledge in the security topic but are also communicative and actively contribute to a positively reinforced security culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security activities in the design phase involve defining security requirements, creating a security architecture, and performing threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to find out what threats are affecting the application being developed and whether they are being handled appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Balanced medium maturity&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Balanced medium maturity&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, SAMM focuses on the tools to integrate security into the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions address the secure handling of credentials to minimize human involvement during initial setup and the subsequent renewal of secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While being important throughout the development lifecycle, the management of defects is also handled in the implementation questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;verification&quot;&gt;Verification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting software into the production environment without prior quality assurance has become unthinkable in many areas. This applies in particular to security checks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter recommends security checks that are based on concrete security requirements but generic tests still have their justification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAMM places a emphasis on denial of service benchmarks, fuzzing, regression testing for fixed vulnerabilities, and test automation in the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important not to lose sight of the appropriateness of the tests for the specific application criticality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;olid maturity with a opportunity for improvement in the verification section&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Solid maturity with a opportunity for improvement in the verification section&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;operation&quot;&gt;Operation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With DevOps, the boundaries of the software development process are increasingly beginning to blur. The maturity model adds a separate section for operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifications tolerate manual log analysis, ad hoc responses to incidents, and best efforts to detect attacks at a low maturity level. Improved maturity requires a dedicated incident response team and defined processes for the detection and remediation of incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patch management and configuration hardening have clear recommendations for regular and systematic activities across the entire technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest score points in SAMM require the rapid decommissioning of outdated applications or strategies to monitor such systems until they are replaced with modern successors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWASP SAMM provides a reliable framework for improving the software development process. Teams should start with an initial maturity assessment to get the status quo. From there, a roadmap can be created that defines the target picture and milestones along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/owasp-samm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/owasp-samm/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup April 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;spring4shell-the-internet-security-disaster-that-wasnt&quot;&gt;Spring4Shell: The Internet security disaster that wasn’t&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were naturally concerned when a researcher published a proof-of-concept exploit that could remotely exploit the popular Spring framework. Without much information available and no CVE assigned, people were unable to determine their exposure. Some security companies jumped on the hype train and warned of imminent danger that “could ruin the internet” to sell their snake oil. A great write-up on the worst side of the security industry, selling services through fear, comes from Arstechnica. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/04/explaining-spring4shell-the-internet-security-disaster-that-wasnt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ka-sat-network-cyber-attack-overview&quot;&gt;KA-SAT Network cyber-attack overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-032022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;March Roundup&lt;/a&gt; we had an article about thousands of KA-SAT terminals that stopped working for an unknown reason. The provider ViaSat has now released an incident report on the cyber-attack against the network. Spoiler alert, the misconfiguration in a VPN appliance was used to gain the initial foothold into the system. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.viasat.com/about/newsroom/blog/ka-sat-network-cyber-attack-overview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;graph-based-firewall-analysis&quot;&gt;Graph-based firewall analysis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good practice to review firewall rules after changes to identify potential attack paths that have been missed. The use of a graph-based approach can help tremendously to visualize the rules and find gaps in the configuration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://diablohorn.com/2022/04/09/firewall-analysis-a-portable-graph-based-approach/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://diablohorn.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/yed-layout-radial.png?w=628&quot; alt=&quot;Firewall analysis with graphs&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Display of data using yEd&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;distributed-tcpdump-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt;Distributed tcpdump for Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toolbox of any security professional includes capturing network traffic with tcpdump or Wireshark. Gathering the network traffic of distriubuted workloads in cloud environments has been a challenge for forensic analysis. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deepfence/PacketStreamer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PacketStreamer (GitHub)&lt;/a&gt; utilizes sensors to collect network packets on remote hosts and enables the collection of traffic activities on a large number of target systems. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/deepfence-cloud-native-security/introducing-packetstreamer-distributed-packet-capture-for-cloud-native-platforms-3e7f9ac57ab1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;authorization-in-a-microservices-world&quot;&gt;Authorization in a microservices world&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alolis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alexander Lolis&lt;/a&gt; wrote a great blog post about different authorization approaches and what a flexible mechanism could look like. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alexanderlolis.com/authorization-in-a-microservices-world#authorization-flow-overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.alexanderlolis.com/assets/images/authorization_architecture_overview-a7f2e4f08870034de08c831e81aae323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Authorization mechanism&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authorization mechanism&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-patch-against-log4j-introduces-new-security-holes&quot;&gt;AWS patch against Log4j introduces new security holes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still seeing the fallout from the worst Christmas present in years, Log4Shell. A hot patch system introduced to address Log4Shell has been exploited to escape containers and take over the underlying host in AWS. Unit 42 (Paloalto networks) researchers identified the severe security issues within the AWS patching solution. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/aws-log4shell-hot-patch-vulnerabilities/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction-to-csrf-how-can-a-cookie-get-you-hacked&quot;&gt;Introduction to CSRF: How can a cookie get you hacked?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cookies serve three purposes: session management, personalization, and tracking. They are assistants to webservers that work in conjunction with the browser to make your life easier. If, however, the web application relies only on cookies to manage sessions, the attacker can perform the infamous CSRF attack. Check out the following article for an introduction to CSRF attacks &lt;a href=&quot;https://systemweakness.com/introduction-to-csrf-how-can-a-cookie-get-you-hacked-1-2-d34e0a0e6319&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-042022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-042022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting Up the Ledger Nano S Wallet</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-management-is-the-most-important-aspect-of-your-crypto-journey-whoever-controls-your-keys-controls-the-assets-there-are-a-variety-of-options-for-key-management-including-online-services-smartphone-apps-or-hardware-devices&quot;&gt;Key management is the most important aspect of your crypto journey. Whoever controls your keys controls the assets. There are a variety of options for key management, including online services, smartphone apps or hardware devices.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-of-these-options-has-its-pros-and-cons-some-are-complicated-to-setup-while-others-leave-your-private-keys-in-the-hands-of-a-service-provider&quot;&gt;Each of these options has its pros and cons. Some are complicated to setup, while others leave your private keys in the hands of a service provider.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend a hardware wallet to access the full potential of crypto assets and limiting the exposure of your private keys to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial explains how to set up the hardware wallet &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ledger.com/products/ledger-nano-s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ledger Nano S&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; running &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/NanoS_PROD_CAM06.png&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Nano S&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ledger Nano S&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buy-the-hardware-wallet&quot;&gt;Buy The Hardware Wallet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ledger Nano S (or any other hardware wallet) should not be purchased from Amazon, eBay, or other online sellers. There is a risk of receiving a tampered or used device that may result in the loss of your crypto assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better purchase a legitimate, unopened, and brand new device from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot;&gt;Official Ledger Website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ledger-nano-s---initial-setup&quot;&gt;Ledger Nano S - Initial SetUp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the included USB cable, connect the Ledger device to your computer and watch it come to life. Navigate with the two buttons on the top of the device and follow the on-screen instructions. Press both buttons simultaneously to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing your device’s PIN code is the first step in the setup process. We recommend to use a 6-digit code. The next step is the documentation of the recovery phrase. The 24 random words will appear one by one on the device’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the only backup of the private keys and the words will only be displayed once&lt;/strong&gt;. Write them down on the provided paper recovery sheet or use an even more secure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Bitcoin-Cryptocurrency-Hardware-Storage-Compatible/dp/B097CZY65D/ref=pd_lpo_1?pd_rd_i=B097CZY65D&amp;amp;psc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;steel recovery sheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;virtualbox-and-guest-system-installation&quot;&gt;VirtualBox And Guest System Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The virtualization software VirtualBox is open source and can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We also require the ISO image for &lt;a href=&quot;http://releases.ubuntu.com/20.04/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/a&gt;. The “Desktop image” is sufficient for our purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ubuntu20.04.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Nano S&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ubuntu 20.04 in VirtualBox&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thorough step-by-step guide for the installation of virtual machines on VirtualBox can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxhint.com/install_ubuntu_virtualbox_2004/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;linuxhint blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setup-the-udev-devices-on-host-and-guest&quot;&gt;Setup the udev devices on host and guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to setup the Linux sub-sytem for dynamic device detection and management aka udev. It creates or removes device nodes dynamically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following command will execute the configuration of Ledger devices and has to be executed on both, the host &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the guest system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wget -q -O - https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LedgerHQ/udev-rules/master/add_udev_rules.sh | sudo bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the installation of the rules, you must either restart the computer or reload the udev ruleset with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo udevadm control --reload-rules &amp;amp;&amp;amp; udevadm trigger&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now connect the Ledger device to the host computer and execute the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command. The device should show up in the list of devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lsusb.png&quot; alt=&quot;lsusb&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Output of the lsusb command&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note of the device ID &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;VendorID&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;ProductID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;configure-the-usb-device-in-the-virtualbox-guest&quot;&gt;Configure the USB device in the VirtualBox guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the USB device is available on the host system, we need to map it to the guest system.
In VirtualBox go to Machine &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; USB and add an empty Filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/VBoxUSBFilter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create an empty USB Filter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Create an empty USB Filter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update the entry with the exact data we received from the output of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command. The &lt;strong&gt;Vendor ID is 2c97&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Product ID is 1011&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://devicehunt.com/view/type/usb/vendor/2C97&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vendor ID&lt;/a&gt; is a fixed value while the Product ID can vary. So make sure you use the correct one for your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/USBFilter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Configure the Filter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Configure the Filter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to start the VirtualBox Guest system and check for the availability of the USB device with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;install-the-ledger-live-software-on-the-guest&quot;&gt;Install the Ledger Live Software on the guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the device available on the guest system we can now install the ledger-live software. Download the image from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/ledger-live/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the file executable by issuing the following command in the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chmod +x ledger-live-*.AppImage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch the application with the following command from the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./ledger-live-desktop-*.AppImage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software will detect your USB hardware wallet and you can now install the desired accounts for the cryptocurrencies you’d like to secure with the wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/LedgerinVBox.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Software in a VirtualBox&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ledger Software in a VirtualBox&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you are now ready to receive and send crypto assets with your hardware wallet. Please make sure you always confirm the wallet address displayed on your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No USB Device found in the VirtualBox Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox Extension Pack&lt;/a&gt; installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet not detected by Ledger Software when installing Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened to me when I added the Ethereum account on the wallet. The Bitcoin account worked  without an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the Ledger S changes the Device ID for some accounts. I noticed this by monitoring the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; output on the host system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just add a second Filter in VirtualBox for the other Device ID. My wallet has &lt;strong&gt;Device ID 1011 for Bitcoin and 1015 for Ethereum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital crypto assets enable us to have independent ownership without the involvement of any third party. Having assets sitting in an exchange broker or with a wallet service provider puts us at the mercy of said companies’ resilience to outside interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owning the private key is vital to unleashing the full potential of self-custody. By using a hardware wallet we exercise self-custody. We are responsible for the safety of our keys and in exchange for this effort, we prevent any state, bank, or hacker to take our assets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/ledger-hardware-wallet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/ledger-hardware-wallet/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;github-shares-vulnerability-database-with-community&quot;&gt;GitHub shares vulnerability database with community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GitHub Advisory Database is the world’s largest database for recording security vulnerabilities in open-source software. A team maintains this data full-time. The database is used, among other things, for security checks of the package managers npm and NuGet as well as for GitHub’s Dependabot warnings. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2022-02-22-github-advisory-database-now-open-to-community-contributions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;satcom-terminals-under-attack&quot;&gt;SATCOM terminals under attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parallel to the Russian invasion of Ukraine, thousands of KA-SAT terminals stopped working in several European countries. Remotely operated wind turbines, connected via SATCOM link, lost contact with their servers as a result. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubensantamarta/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ruben Santamarta&lt;/a&gt; analyses the publicly available information in his interesting article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reversemode.com/2022/03/satcom-terminals-under-attack-in-europe.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2e/IP-SATCOM.svg/1920px-IP-SATCOM.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;SATCOM&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;critical-vulnerabilities-in-apc-uninterruptible-power-supply&quot;&gt;Critical vulnerabilities in APC Uninterruptible Power Supply&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armis has discovered three critical vulnerabilities in APC Smart-UPS devices. These are of course controlled through an internet connection nowadays. A malicious actor can use TLS bypass and TLS overflow to gain unauthenticated access to the UPS and use the device for further lateral movement in the network.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armis.com/research/tlstorm/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pro-tips-for-burpsuite&quot;&gt;Pro-tips for BurpSuite&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burp Suite is a network analysis toolbox for testing web applications. It includes a proxy, which intercepts HTTP/HTTPS traffic and modifies the HTTP headers before sending the data to the server. The article by N00PY gives great tips for the powerful software. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.n00py.io/2017/10/how-to-burp-good/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;famous-npm-package-deletes-files-to-protest-ukraine-war&quot;&gt;Famous npm package deletes files to protest Ukraine war&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of supply chain security for open source components in business code has been highlighted once again this month. The developer of the npm module node-ipc.js added malicious code to it that deletes files if the software thinks it is on a Russian or Belarusian system based on a geo-location IP determination. The incident has drawn sharp criticism from the open-source community for actively deploying destructive payloads in a popular library without any warning to honest users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/big-sabotage-famous-npm-package-deletes-files-to-protest-ukraine-war/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nsa-hardening-guide-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt;NSA hardening guide for Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest sources of compromise in Kubernetes are supply chain risks, malicious
threat actors, and insider threats. The NSA guide describes the security challenges associated with setting up and securing a Kubernetes cluster and provides strategies to avoid common misconfiguration and implement hardening measures. &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.defense.gov/2021/Aug/03/2002820425/-1/-1/0/CTR_Kubernetes_Hardening_Guidance_1.1_20220315.PDF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;escaping-privileged-containers-for-fun&quot;&gt;Escaping privileged containers for fun&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pwningsystems&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jordy&lt;/a&gt; writes on his blog about discovering an escape from a privileged container via the kernel’s coredump handling code. Interesting read and let’s all agree to not run privileged containers, not even for fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://pwning.systems/posts/escaping-containers-for-fun/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-032022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-032022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
