<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>blog about watch and book reviews</description>
    <link>https://damaex17.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://damaex17.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 10:47:15 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 10:47:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Starship Troopers' by Robert A. Heinlein</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Author&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Robert A. Heinlein was born in July 1907 in Missouri and died in May 1988 aged 80 years. He was a science-fiction author, aeronautical engineer, and retired navy officer. He fought aboard an aircraft carrier during Wold War II and this time is considered to have had a strong influence on his writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is the pioneer of hard science fiction, a sugenre which emphasizes scentific accuracy. His work continues to have an influence on the science-fiction genre, and on modern culture more generally. Heinlein repeatedly addressed social themes in his science-fiction stories. The importance of liberty and self-reliance, the individuals obligation to societies or societies repression of nonconfrom thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/troopers_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of Robert A. Heinlein&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heinlein was named the Science Fiction Grand Master in 1974 and won many awards during his career. He predicted in his books later inventions like the cell phone or computer aided design. Robert also coined terms that have become part of the English language. “There ain’t no such thing as a free lunch” or “Space Marine” are commonly used even by the President of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at his most famous book. This is one of my personal all time favorite books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting&quot;&gt;Setting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future society of Earth is ruled by the Terran Federation, a global government dominated by the military elite. The rights of a “full citizen” are not universally granted, but must be earned through Federal Service. Only “full citizens” can vote or hold a public office. At the age of 18 people of either gender are expected to enlist in the Terran Federation. This structure arose ad hoc after the collapse of the 20th century Western democracies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two alien civilizations are known. The “Skinnies” a humanoide species with thin appearance. And the “Arachnids” or “Bugs” an insectoid species and main antagonists of the story. The Bugs have multiple castes; workers, soldiers, brains, and queens and their society is similar to ants and termites. The Skinnies are initially allies of the Arachnids, but switch to being allies of the humans midway through the novel. Faster than light travel exists in the novel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/troopers_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Book cover of Starship Troopers&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starship Troopers main character is Johnny Rico a member of the TF Mobile Infrantry. Rico is from a wealthy family, whose members did not serve in the army and see the military drive society critical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story is loosened up by a series of flashbacks into Rico’s time at school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The novel opens with Rico aboard the corvette Rodger Young, platoon transport for the “Rasczak’s Roughnecks”, about to embark on a raid against the planet of the “Skinnies”, allies of the Arachnids. The raid is relatively brief: the platoon lands on the planet, destroys its targets, and retreats, suffering two casualties in the process. The story then flashes back to Rico’s graduation from high school and his decision to not attend Harvard University, but rather sign up for Federal Service, despite the objections of his wealthy father. This chapter is mostly monologues of two people: retired Lt. Colonel Jean V. Dubois, Rico’s school instructor in the subjects of History and Moral Philosophy, and Fleet Sergeant Ho, a recruiter for the Armed forces of the Terran Federation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubois delivers one of the famous statements of the book on how Violence “has settled more issues in history than has any other factor”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rico is assigned to the Mobile Infantry, and moves to Camp Arthur Currie for his training under Sergeant Charles Zim. He receives combat training of all types, including simulated fights in armored suits. During his training a Arachnid attack destroys the city of Buenos Aires, Rico’s mother is killed in the attack. The “Bug War” changes from border skirmishes to a full-scale war. His first assignment is the Battle of Klendathu, an attack on the Arachnid’s home world, which turns into a disastrous defeat for the Terran Federation with many casualties. With his unit decimated, he is assigned to the “Razak’s Roughnecks” onboard the TF Rodger Young.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several battles with the Arachnids follow and Rico is promoted to corporal and later lieutenant. In the final battle of the book, Rico commands a platoon during “Operation Royalty”, a raid to capture members of the Arachnid brain caste and queens. This operation is a success and a “Brain Bug” is captured. The novel ends with his platoon renaming to “Rico’s Roughnecks”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quotes&quot;&gt;Quotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There are no dangerous weapons; there are only dangerous men.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Liberty is never unalienable; it must be redeemed regularly with the blood of patriots or it always vanishes. Of all the so-called natural human rights that have ever been invented, liberty is least likely to be cheap and is never free of cost.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Happiness consists in getting enough sleep. Just that, nothing more.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/troopers_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Starship Troopers fan art&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Our behavior is different. How often have you seen a headline like this?–TWO DIE ATTEMPTING RESCUE OF DROWNING CHILD. If a man gets lost in the mountains, hundreds will search and often two or three searchers are killed. But the next time somebody gets lost just as many volunteers turn out.
Poor arithmetic, but very human. It runs through all our folklore, all human religions, all our literature–a racial conviction that when one human needs rescue, others should not count the price.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Any group is weaker than a man alone unless they are perfectly trained to work together.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To permit irresponsible authority is to sell disaster.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commentators have stated that Starship Troopers is not driven by its plot, it contains only few desciptions of military combat. Instead, much of the novel’s content is the discussion of ideas.  The book is based on the social Darwinist idea of society as a struggle for survival based on military strength. It suggests that some conflicts must be resolved by force: one of the lessons Rico is repeatedly taught is that violence can be an effective method of settling conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ricos transformation from boy to soldier is another major theme and the book can be considered a “coming of age” nove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heinlein also ridicules the idea of inalienable rights, such as “Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness”, arguing that people only have the rights that they are willing to fight and die for to protect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Critics of the book and the author accused him of glorification of militarism and facism. To me those allegations are refuted by the satirical undertone of the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starship Troopers has been influential for the sci-fi genre and praised by reviewers for its scenes of training and combat and its visualization of a future military.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/starship-troopers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/starship-troopers/</guid>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Old Man's War' by John Scalzi</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Author&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scalzi was born in May 10, 1969 in California. Scalzi’s books are known for their humor. His style of writing has been influenced by Robert Heinlein (eg. Starship Troopers) and Joe Haldeman (eg. The Forever War) which are both masters and celebrities of the scifi genre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John was also the elected president of the Science Fiction and Fantasy Writers of America organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/omw_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of John Scalzi&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Perry, a 75-year-old retired advertising writer, joins the Colonial Defense Forces (CDF) who protect human interplanetary colonists. Volunteers sign letters of intent and provide DNA samples at age 65. John and his recently deceased wife had both done so. After visiting his wife’s grave to say goodbye as volunteers can not return to Earth, Perry takes a space elevator called “Beanstalk” to the CDF ship Henry Hudson, where he meets fellow male and female retiree volunteers. They call themselves the “Old Farts”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/omw_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;one of the book covers of Old Man's War&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perry’s mind is transferred to a new body based on his genetic code. The new body is a younger version of himself, but genetically improved with enhanced musculature, green skin, and yellow cat-like eyes. He now possesses more strength, nanobot-enhanced artificial blood, better eyesight and most critically, the BrainPal - a neural interface that allows owners to communicate with other members of the CDF via thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a week of orgies in their new bodies, Perry and the other recruits are transferred to a remote planet for basic training. Perry is promoted to platoon leader during the training and shipped out to the CDF ship Modesto for his first engagement with the alien species called Consu. Perry improvises a tactic which enables the Colonial Defense Forces to win the battle quickly. This is soon followed by a number of successful battles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a veteran, Perry participates in the Battle for Coral. The planet contains reefs valuable to the attacking Rraey, as well as a human colony. Perry is grievously wounded but and the lone survivor of the battle. He is left for dead by a Rraey search party and later rescued by members of the mysterious “Ghost Brigades”, the Special Forces units of the CDF. Perry thinks he has died when he sees a younger green version of his deceased wife Kathy, who in reality is Jane Sagan, the leader of the Ghost Brigades rescue team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/omw_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Fan Art of Old Man's War&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later it turns out that Sagan has been grown based on Kathy Perry’s DNA, as legally allowed by her letter of intent. Unlike John, Segan has no memories of Kathy’s life. She is eager to learn about Kathy, “realborn” people and what kind of life one can have outside the CDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sagan has John join the Ghost Brigate in an advisory role to gather information from the Consun. Perry discovers that the Rraey had received tachyon detection technology from the Consu, which was used to set up the ambush at the battle of Coral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perry and Sagan participate in a Special Forces operation to capture or destroy the borrowed Consu technology in advance of a major attack to recapture Coral from the Rraey. Perry is instrumental in the successful outcome of the battle by capturing the technical manual for the Consu detection system. He is saving Sagan’s life after she is severely wounded. He never sees her again after delivering her to a shuttle which returns her to the secretive Ghost Brigades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the conclusion of the book, Perry is promoted to captain following his success at Coral and holds hope of meeting with Sagan again when their terms of service conclude.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;excerpt&quot;&gt;Excerpt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How to prepare for battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, systems check your MP-35 Infantry Rifle. This is the easy part; MP-35s are self-monitoring and self-repairing, and can, in a pinch, use material from an ammunition block as raw material to fix a malfunction. Just about the only way you can permanently ruin an Empee is to place it in the path of a firing maneuvering thruster. Inasmuch as you’re likely to be attached to your weapon at the time, if this is the case, you have other problems to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, put on your war suit. This is the standard self-sealing body-length unitard that covers everything but the face. The unitard is designed to let you forget about your body for the length of the battle. The “fabric” of organized nanobots lets in light for photosynthesis and regulates heat; stand on an artic floe or a Saharan sand dune and the only difference your body notes is the visual change in scenery. If you somehow manage to sweat, your unitard wicks it away, filters it and stores the water until you can transfer it to a canteen. You can deal with urine this way too. Defecating in your unitard is generally not recommended.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a bullet in your gut (or anywhere else), and the unitard stiffens at the point of impact and transfers the energy across the surface of the suit, rather than allowing the bullet to burrow through. This is massively painful but better than letting a bullet ricochet merrily through your intestines. This only works up to a point, alas, so avoiding enemy fire is still the order of the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add your belt, which includes your combat knife, your multipurpose tool, which is what a Swiss army knife wants to be when it grows up, an impressively collapsible personal shelter, your canteen, a week’s worth of energy wafers, and three slots for ammo blocks. Smear your face with a nanobot-laden cream that interfaces with your unitard to share environmental information. Switch on your camouflage. Try to find yourself in the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, open a BrainPal channel to the rest of your squad and leave it open until you return to the ship or you die. I thought I was pretty smart to think of this in boot camp but it turns out to be one of the holiest of unofficial rules during the heat of battle. BrainPal communication means no unclear commands or signals – and no speaking to give away your position. If you hear a CDF soldier during the heat of battle, it’s because he is either stupid or screaming because he’s been shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawback to BrainPal communication is that your BrainPal can also send emotional information if you’re not paying attention. This can be distracting if you suddenly feel like your going to piss yourself in fright, only to realize it’s not you who’s about to cut loose on the bladder, but your squadmate. It’s also something none of your squadmates will ever let you live down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link only to your squadmates – try to keep a channel open to your entire platoon and suddenly 60 people are cursing, fighting and dying inside your head. You do not need this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, forget everything except to follow orders, kill anything that’s not human and stay alive. The CDF makes it simple to do this; for the first two years of service, every soldier is infantry, no matter if you were a janitor or surgeon, senator or street bum in your previous life. If you make it through the first two years, then you get the chance to specialize, to earn a permanent colonial billet instead of wander from battle to battle, and to fill in the niche and support roles every military body has. But for two years, all you have to do is go where they tell you, stay behind your rifle and kill and not be killed. It’s simple, but simple isn’t the same as easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old Man’s War belongs to the military science fiction genre but adds the topics of the ethics of life, marriage, friendship, the significance of mortality and what makes a human. The ethics of aging is outlined in the beginning of the book with society having a way to reverse the effects. Marriage is explored in the continued love of John for his dead wife Jane. When it comes to the identiy of what makes a human it is left to the reader to decide at the end of the novel about John and if he can still be considered a human being despite his altered genetic code and the enhancement he received by the CDF.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Old Man’s War is a conscious homage to  Robert Heinlein’s Starship Troopers. He wanted to make the story in a way that the reader can understand the events of the book - such as being in a war or moving on after losing someone you love.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/old-mans-war/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/old-mans-war/</guid>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Rescue Party' by Arthur C. Clarke</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Author&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sir Arthur Charles Clarke was a British science fiction writer, science writer, futurist, explorer and tv host. He was born 16 December 1917 in England and died on 19 March 2008 in Sri Lanka aged 90 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Arthur C. Clarke&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He is known to the broader public for co-writing screenplay for the 1968 Stanley Kubrick film 2001: A Space Odyssey, widely considered to be one of the most influential films of all time. An possibly the best sci-fi movie ever produced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His science fiction writings earned him a number of awards and one of the founding figures of contemporary science fiction. For many years Clarke, Robert Heinlein and Isaac Asimov were known as the “Big Three” of science fiction. Arthur C. Clarke was also nicknamed the “Prophet of the Space Age”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resuce Party was first published in “Astounding Science Fiction” in May 1946. It was the first story Clarke sold and gives us a insight into the beginnings of this titan of science fiction. He is one of my all time favorite writers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Astounding Science Fiction magazine from 1946&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story begins with an alien ship visiting Earth a few hours before the sun will explode, destroying the planet. The mission of the aliens is to save as many humans as possible. The galactic civilization does surveys of planets every one million years for new intelligent species, but the human race did not exist the last time the survey was done four hundred thousand years before. However, radio signals had been detected, indicating intelligent life had arisen on Earth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the aliens arrive on the blue planet they are surprised by the planet being empty of intelligent life, except for empty cities and other remnants of the civilization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We find out during the exploration of the cities by the aliens that it is unusual for civilizations to develop space travel so quickly after radio communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aliens find a communication tower pointing into space. They follow the towers direction and find an enormous fleet of human ships, powered by rockets. The aliens, equipped with faster-than-light ships, are amazed that humans dared to cross interstellar space with rockets. Humans have taken the audacious tactic of using generational starships, in the hopes that their descendants will one day arrive at a new planet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/rescue_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cover of 'Rescue Party'&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ending&quot;&gt;Ending&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wonder what they’ll be like?” he mused. “Will they be nothing but wonderful engineers, with no art or philosophy? They’re going to have such a surprise when Orostron reaches them—I expect it will be rather a blow to their pride. It’s funny how all isolated races think they’re the only people in the Universe. But they should be grateful to us; we’re going to save them a good many hundred years of travel.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alveron glanced at the Milky Way, lying like a veil of silver mist across the vision screen. He waved toward it with a sweep of a tentacle that embraced the whole circle of the galaxy, from the Central Planets to the lonely suns of the Rim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know,” he said to Rugon, “I feel rather afraid of these people. Suppose they don’t like our little Federation?” He waved once more toward the star-clouds that lay massed across the screen, glowing with the light of their countless suns.
“Something tells me they’ll be very determined people,” he added. “We had better be polite to them. After all, we only outnumber them about a thousand million to one.”
Rugon laughed at his captain’s little joke.
Twenty years afterward, the remark didn’t seem funny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;audio-book&quot;&gt;Audio Book&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a excellent narrated episode of “Escape Pod” about this magnificient short story of Arthur C. Clarke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://escapepod.org/2013/06/18/ep400-rescue-party/&quot;&gt;Escape Pod Ep400: Rescue Party&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reception-and-foreword-by-arthur-c-clarke&quot;&gt;Reception and Foreword by Arthur C. Clarke&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Rescue Party,” written in March 1945, while I was still in the Royal Air Force, was the first story I sold to the legendary John W. Campbell, Jr., editor of Astounding Science Fiction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t believe I’ve reread it since its original appearance, and I refuse to do so now — for fear of discovering how little I have improved in almost four decades. Those who claim that it’s their favorite story get a cooler and cooler reception over the passing years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rescue-party/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rescue-party/</guid>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Rolex Explorer II' Ref. 216570</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1971, Rolex unveiled the Explorer II as the larger sibling to the original &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/&quot;&gt;Explorer I&lt;/a&gt;. The new line of watches were created specifically for speleologist. Rolex has a history of watches for specific purposes. The Rolex Submariner as the iconic dive watch. The Rolex Daytona as a watch for race car drivers and the Rolex GMT for commerzial airline pilots. The Rolex Explorer II has features that make it a particularly practical item for cave exploration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a extra 24-hour hand that points to a fixed bezel with 24-hour markings. The logic behind this is that cave explorers are often in the dark and therefore, can’t tell the difference between AM and PM. The 24-hour hand points to either 10:00 or 22:00, the wearer can now know whether it’s day or night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ref. 216570 is also heavily lumed on all hour markers and all 4 hands. The watch does a great job of telling the wearer the exact time of day (and night) even in complete darkness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/216570_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the explorer II&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rolex-explorer-ii-ref-216570&quot;&gt;Rolex Explorer II Ref. 216570&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the 40th anniversary of the model, Rolex presented the Explorer II ref. 216570 in 2011. Although it’s a modern model, it pays fitting tribute to the inaugural ref. 1655.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new Explorer ref. 216570 comes with an increased case size of 42mm, making it the largest version of the Explorer II. To balance the large case, hands, lume markers and the date disc also grew in size for even better legibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/216570_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the explorer II&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In honor of the original Explorer II, Rolex outfitted the latest X2 with a orange arrow-tipped 24-hour hand. Unlike the original reference, the new model is a GMT watch with a second time zone display. Adding the date window at 3 o’clock makes this now the ideal watch for adventurers and global travelers. Powering the Explorer II ref. 216570 is the Caliber 3187.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/216570_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the explorer II&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honoring the original Explorer II, the Ref. 216570 performs great in the dark thanks to the Chromalight display. The blue hue that comes alive in low light lasts up to eight hours, which is double that of standard luminescent material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latest version of the Explorer II with the polar dial joined my collection in 2018. The watch provides fantastic value and can be picked up below MSRP, which makes it a very rare watch in the Rolex steel sports collection. While the GMT line is made out of “unobtainium”, the X2 is the most accessible entry into a Rolex watch with GMT function. The white dial differentiates it from the commonly seen black Rolex Submariners. The watch goes well with casual or smart cassual attire.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-II-216570/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-II-216570/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>rolex</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Jaeger-LeCoultre Grande Reverso Tribute to 1931' Ref. 2788570</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;heritage&quot;&gt;Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of the Reverso starts in the year of 1931. The legends tells that Cesar de Trey, a Swiss businessman and watch aficionado, was attending a polo match of British army officers while travelling India. One of the players had just broken the glass of his watch. De Trey discussed the idea of a watch model robust enough to survive the hard knocks of a polo game with Jacques-David LeCoultre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LeCoultre tasked the firm Jaeger S.A with the creation of a reversible case. The case can be swivelled in its carrier to protect the watch glass. The Reverso was born. The name is inspired by the Latin “I turn around”. The well proportioned rectangular shape with the three grooves at the top and bottom of case is considered a classic of Art Deco design. To this day the Reverso is still produced and is a statement of Jaeger-LeCoultre’s relationship with polo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;reverso advertisement&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reverso-tribute-to-1931&quot;&gt;Reverso Tribute to 1931&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Jaeger-LeCoultre celebrated the 80th anniversary of the Reverso and during SIHH 2011, JCL commorated this anniversary with the Grande Reverso Ultra Thin Tribute to 1931 model. This authentic model comes with the original dial and hands and is presented in an extremely flat and large case, measuring 46.8mm x 27.4mm wide and 7.3 mm thick. There is no brand name on the dial, just the word “Reverso” which is of course well known and closely related to JLC itself. The lugs are thick and downward sloped to make the watch comfortable on the wrist. On the black dial is a rectangular minute with aged hour markers and a double mark at the 12 o’clock position. The watch uses aged baton hands to tell the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of my reverso&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the watch ticks the manually wound Jaeger-LeCoultre Calibre 822 (21 jewels) which beats at 21.600 vibrations per hour. It has a power reserve of 45 hours. Most rectangular and tonneau shaped cases in the industry contain a round movement. But this is a JLC watch, the movement is shaped to the dimensions of the watch itself (true case movement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the Calibre 822&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the modern watch to the original, it’s clear that Jaeger-LeCoultre was successful in developing a honorable tribute to the 1931 icon. The watch captures the essential elements of the original Reverso. Perhaps the best example of staying true to it’s origin is the the solid caseback. Imposing a sapphire caseback would have damaged the credibility of the watch as a re-edition of an iconic sports watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Reverso Tribute joined my collection in 2017 as a present from my mother. I equipped the JLC with an aftermarket strap from Casa Fagliano, a historical Polo leather workshop from Argentina. The watch is certainly not meant for daily use and abuse but whenever the circumstances allow, it is a pleasure to wear. A solid movement, vintage looks, outstanding quality and a significance to history makes this watch a modern classic.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>jlc</category>
        
        <category>jaeger-lecoultre</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'Rolex Explorer' Ref. 114270</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stealth-rolex&quot;&gt;The stealth rolex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created in 1953 to honor the adventures of the Everest conquerors Norgay and Hillary, the Rolex Explorer was the first of a long line of Rolex tool watches designed to go anywhere.
The Explorer was developed from the original 1930s Oyster Perpetual “bubblebacks” and the first water-resistant and self-winding wristwatches to achieve technical and commercial success. Norgay and Hillary immortalized the Rolex Explorer and the continuous incremental improvements by Rolex led to the Explorer 114270 produced from 2002 until 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rolex explorer stock picture&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the general public may not understand the depth of the Rolex tool watch heritage, even the average “man on the street” understands that the brand stands as a synonym for quality. And in the Explorer, Rolex delivers. The Geneva watchmaker ranks among the exclusive club of true manufactures that produce virtually every part of their watches by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 36mm stainless steel case itself is a testament to Rolex’s eye for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It begins with the steel itself; Rolex makes it in its own company foundry. The steel used to build the Explorer is of the 904L type, not the lesser resilient 316L employed by the majority of watchmakers. 904L is more expensive to produce and harder to work with. The payoff is the watch’s lifetime and scratch resistance. The steel preserves the polished and brushed finishes and the corrosion resistance is higher than with conventional stainless steel. 
Rolex is building watches that last a life time (or two, or three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rolex explorer advertisement&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the case is the Rolex Cal. 3130 chronometer grade movement which beats at 28.800 vibrations per hour. The movement is COSC certified in a two-week evaluation process. This certification tests the movement in different positions and temperatures. Another testament to the quality requirements of Rolex watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the rolex explorer&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than any other aspect of the watch, the dial is what makes the Explorer unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three Arabic numerals at 3, 6, and 9 o’clock combines with the triangular marker at 12 and intermediate stick indexes, no date, smooth bezel. Signature “Mercedes” cathedral hands are, like all indexes, rendered in white gold for enduring resistance to corrosion and tarnish. The rich black lacquer dial provides a beautiful gloss backdrop to the white gold elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the rolex explorer&quot; style=&quot;float: center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270 is the last of the 36mm Explorers. It represents a time where Rolex built tools rather than jewellery and investment pieces. But make no mistake… the Explorer can be worn with a suite to a evening in the opera. If there is one lesson learned from history, it’s that a Rolex Explorer is your companion anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the 114270 in 2016 and since then it has become my daily companion. It might just be the perfect Rolex. The Explorer is durable, accurate and doesn’t get in your way. The design is timeless and blends in perfectly. People don’t associate the brand Rolex with this inconspicuous watch. This Ref. 114270 is for me the ultimate Oyster Professional model in the history of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>rolex</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>'The Expanse' by James S.A. Corey</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting&quot;&gt;Setting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Expanse is a science fiction novel by James S. A. Corey, the pseudonym of Daniel Abraham and Ty Franck. It is set in the near future in which humanity has colonized most of the solar system, but does not have faster than light travel. The setting was orininaly developed as a pitch for a MMO computer game but was later adoped into a series of books and a successful tv show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the first 3 books of the expanse&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story provides a realistic outlook into the future of humanity. Gravity is for example not created by a mysterious and unexplained device as in Star Wars or Star Trek but by acceleration. Spaceships brake by accelerating into the other direction (flip and burn). And there are no pew-pew lasers but bullets, torpedos and railguns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;earth---the-united-nations&quot;&gt;Earth - The United Nations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_un.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the un logo&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding: 0px 10px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the mid and late 21st century, humanity’s national governments are confronted with overpopulation and the resulting difficult state of Earth’s ecosystem. They unite under a global government. The United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UN begins to establish colonies on other planets and moons in the Sol system, the most notable of these being Luna and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 22nd century the colonial government of Mars demands independence. The United Nations refuses and war is imminent. 
Mars offers to share the revolutionary Epstein drive technology in exchange for independence. The UN agrees in order to avoid Mars having a tactical advantage in spaceship technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now free to expand into the outer Sol system, the UN establishes colonies on several Jovian moons, as well as Titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mars---martian-congressional-republic&quot;&gt;Mars - Martian Congressional Republic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_mcrn2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the mcrn logo&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding: 0px 10px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally a colony of Earth and in the beginning highly depending on the blue planet, three generations after the first settlers landed, Mars became largely self-sustaining. Mars also became a leader in environmental technology and research as well as the design and manufacture of advanced spaceships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the colonists on Mars during this period want to secede from Earth, comparing themselves to the American colonies of the 17th century. If not for Solomon Epstein and his accidental invention of what would come to be called the Epstein Drive, war between the planet and its colony may have been inevitable. Mars had a major technological advantage over Earth with this drive. The new ships could go further and faster than anything that had been built before, opening up the rest of the solar system for exploration, settlement and resource gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Martian government offered the UN access to the Epstein Drive in exchange for granting Mars its sovereignty. The UN accepted and the Martian Congressional Republic was formed. Mars is a militaristic society with the goal of terraforming their planet and protecting their interests in the solar system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-belt---outer-planets-alliance-opa&quot;&gt;The Belt - Outer Planets Alliance (OPA)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_opa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;the opa logo&quot; style=&quot;float: left; padding: 0px 10px 10px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Asteroid Belt, often referred to as just The Belt, is a circumstellar disc located in the region of the Sol system between the orbits of the planets Mars and Jupiter. The Belt was colonized by humans in the 21st century. Humans born in the Belt, called Belters, are thinner and taller than humans from the inner planets due to the lower gravity environment. The population of the Belt is estimated at around 50 million according to inner planets censuses. The Outer Planets Alliance (OPA) is a loosely affiliated group uniting under a common ideology that started as a labor union or advocacy group, fighting for the interests of inhabitants of the Belt. Often in direct conflict with the inner planets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice hauling ship Canterbury is traveling back from Saturn to Ceres when it encounters a distress signal. Five members (Jim Holden (Earth), Naomi Nagata (Belt), Alex Kamal (Mars), Amos Burton (Earth) and Shed Garvey(Earth)) of the crew are sent in a shuttle to investigate and discover a transport vessel called Scopuli. There is no trace of the crew but they discover the beacon transmitting the distress signal. They leave the Scopuli with the beacon and head back to the Canterbury in fear of a pirate trap. Before they arrive, a unknown stealth warship decloaks and destroys the Canterbury with a nuclear torpedo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the advanced technology of the warship and the discovery that the beacon from the Scopuli is of Martian origin, the survivors suspect the MCRN of being behind the attack. With the shuttle damaged by the debris field of the explosion the crew decides to send out a message to the entire system implicating Mars in the destruction of the Canterbury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MCRN battleship Donnager, flagship of the Mars Jupiter fleet responds and the shuttle is ordered to rendezvous with the Donnager. Aboard the battleship the captain denies any knowledge of the MCRN involvment in the attack on the Canterbury. More unknown stealth ships arrive to the site and open fire on the Donnager. Despite the fact that the Donnager is one of the most advanced warships in the Solar System, it is overwhelmed by the mysterious enemy ships and eventually boarded. During the battle a railgun round penetrates the hull and kills Garvey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that the Canterbury survivors are the target of the attack, a team of MCRN Marines is ordered to evacuate them from the battleship. All Marian Marines are killed in the process and the four surviving crew members are able to escape aboard the light frigate Tachi just before the Donnager is scuttled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other arc of the book tells the story of detective Joe Miller (Belt) who is contracted to locate Julie Mao. The daughter of the wealthy Earth magnate Jules-Pierre Mao. Later the story lines merge and Miller joins the crew of the Tachi (later renamed to Rocinante). They eventually discover the body of Julie Mao on the moon Eros. The corpse is covered in a strange organic material. This material is later unveiled of being of alien origin and named the Protomolecule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Protomolecule is able to transform biomass in order to create a structure of unknown purpose. This is the beginning of the story surrounding the crew of the frigate Rocinante.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding the Protomolecule to the high tensions between the fractions develops the story. The members of the crew with their diverse backgrounds and character makes The Expanse the best Sci-Fi of the early 21st century. The books have been adapted by a TV Show which is also highly recommended. This is the future the way it was supposed to be!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/the-expanse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/the-expanse/</guid>
        
        <category>expanse</category>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
