<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>technology, security, watch and book reviews</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:49:40 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2019 13:49:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight - Ref. 79030N</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-black-bay-fifty-eight-was-introduced-at-baselworkd-2018-it-is-an-anniversary-model-to-commemorate-60-years-of-the-tudor-submariner-which-was-released-in-1958&quot;&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight was introduced at Baselworkd 2018. It is an anniversary-model to commemorate 60 years of the Tudor Submariner which was released in 1958.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind this watch is to go back to the original Big Crown models and create a vintage-inspired modern take on the Submariner-like dive watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58.png&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tudor-submariner-heritage&quot;&gt;Tudor Submariner Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tudor Oyster Prince Submariner ‘Big Crown’ reference 7924 used many parts from Rolex Submariners in those days. The crown and bracelet carried for exampled Rolex markings. The watch was water-resistant up to 200m (600 feet) and featured a large screw-down crown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the same year, the reference 7925 was released with a depth rating of 100m (300 feet) and the distinctive red triangle at the zero point of the diving bezel. The Marine nationale francaise (MN), the US Navy (USN) and other military organizations throughout the world equipped their elite personnel with the Tudor Sub.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watches delivered to these military entities were neither custom-designed nor specially developed. They were just references listed in the Tudor cataloge. Their only distinction was an engraving on the screw-down case back. The Marine nationale francaise watches, for example, bear the initials M.N. accompanied by the last two digits of the year in which they were delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples surviving to this day are rarely in perfect condition since they were used in extremely harsh conditions. The relative rarity of these watches and their respective stories make them a highly prized collectors item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;downsizing-the-original-black-bay&quot;&gt;Downsizing the original Black Bay&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initially, the new Tudor Black Bay 58 looks just like another Black Bay, a Submariner-like dive watch with vintage inspiration. But the watch is an evolution and at the same time a return to the original dimensions of the Tudor Submariner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A modern Tudor Black Bay 58 vs. a vintage Tudor Submariner&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The alignment with the original Big Crown models – mainly the Tudor Submariner 7924 and 7925 means the 58 is a smaller and slimmer version of the bulky Black Bay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 58 is 39mm in diameter. While the original ref. 7924 was even smaller at 37mm, the effort taken by Tudor to reduce the case size from the original Black Bay is a nod to watch enthusiasts who have been asking for smaller watches for years. The lug width has also been reduced to 20mm, to keep the proportions balanced. The case was condensed in height to now only 11.9mm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall the 58 ist a well-proportioned watch and sits nicely on the wrist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tudor58_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of the bb58&quot; style=&quot;float: center; margin: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;snowflakes-on-a-guilt-dial&quot;&gt;Snowflakes on a guilt dial&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a modern interpretation of a classic, the Fifty-Eight has golden writing and minuteries. Also, a one-directional rotating bezel with gold lettering, classic with aluminum inlay and a red triangular marking at 12 adorns the watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tudor went with golden snowflake hands which is a deviation from the original Submariner but it works surprisingly well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BB58 comes with the Tudor in-house MT5402 movement which is COSC certified. It has a power reserve of a whopping 70 hours.
This means one can easily leave the watch on the nightstand over the weekend and pick it up on Monday without having to adjust the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;specifications&quot;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Number:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Black Bay Fifty-Eight Ref. 79030N&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Movement:&lt;/strong&gt; Tudor Calibre MT5402 (COSC)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Case Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Stainless Steel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Glass Material:&lt;/strong&gt; Sapphire Crystal&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lug Width:&lt;/strong&gt; 20mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diameter/Height:&lt;/strong&gt; 39 mm/11.9 mm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six years after the first Black Bay and 60 years after the first Big Crown Submariner, Tudor impressively shows how to use past models to create an equally modern and historically true watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Black Bay Fifty-Eight is a good looking dive watch and comes at a fair price.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/tudor-blackbay-fityeight/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>tudor</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Social Credit Systems</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;nosedive-is-a-episode-in-the-british-science-fiction-series-black-mirror-it-examines-the-idea-of-a-fictional-society-where-people-can-rate-each-other-from-one-to-five-stars-for-every-interaction-they-have-with-each-other-the-resulting-score-has-an-impact-on-the-social-and-economic-status-of-the-individual&quot;&gt;“Nosedive” is a episode in the British science fiction series &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Black_Mirror&quot;&gt;Black Mirror&lt;/a&gt;. It examines the idea of a fictional society where people can rate each other from one to five stars for every interaction they have with each other. The resulting score has an impact on the social and economic status of the individual.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story follows Lacie, who is a young woman overly obsessed with her ratings; she finds an opportunity to improve her ratings greatly and move into a more luxurious residence after being chosen by her popular childhood friend as the maid of honour for her wedding. Her obsession leads to several mishaps on her journey to the wedding that culminate in a rapid reduction in her ratings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many critics noted the similarity of the episode to real-world Social Credit Systems. Indeed we already live in a world where the judgment of people is being replaced by numbers. Algorithms calculate the value of a human being and create digitally transparent people&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a wall of CCTV&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nudge-theory&quot;&gt;Nudge Theory&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social Credit Systems belong to a behavioral science concept called Nudge Theory. It proposes positive reinforcement and indirect suggestions as a way to influence the behavior and decision making of groups or individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nudging contrasts with other ways to achieve compliance, such as education, legislation or enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The utilization of “nudging” has been widely criticized for diminishing autonomy, threatening dignity, and violating liberties. Some call it psychological manipulative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;china&quot;&gt;China&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chinese system uses a combination of mass surveillance and big data to score citizens. It is currently voluntary but will be made mandatory by 2020.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the final stage, every citizen and company will be ranked whether they like it or not. The system will manage the punishments and rewards of citizens based on their economic and personal behavior.
The exact methodology for the rating is a secret but examples of infrations include bad driving, smoking in non-smoking areas, or posting fake news.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Punishments include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flight ban&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;exclusion from schools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;slow internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;public display of blacklisted individuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/scs_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;inside of a chinese airport&quot; style=&quot;center; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of 2018, 5.5 million high-speed rail trips and 17.5 million flights had been denied to prospective travelers who were on a Chinese social scoring blacklist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;western-world&quot;&gt;Western World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Germany has its own social scoring system. The universal credit rating system known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schufa&quot;&gt;Schufa&lt;/a&gt; is a private company that assesses the creditworthiness of the majority of the German citizens and that of over 5 million companies in the country. Factors like living in a low-income neighborhood (geo-scoring) can lower the Schufa score. There is mounting criticism in Germany of what some view as a lack of transparency in establishing Schufa scores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schufa has also been criticized for being a privately controlled central database that provides personality profiles for individuals. Having a bad score in the credit rating system will prevent people from getting a loan or renting an apartment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparable credit systems are common in most western democracies. The US counterpart to Schufa is &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FICO&quot;&gt;FICO&lt;/a&gt; and the UK has &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Experian&quot;&gt;Experian&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An increasing number of societal “privileges” related to transportation, accommodations, communications, and the rates we pay for services (like insurance) are controlled by algorithms and our behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are in a critical phase of technological development and we need to discuss our values. Private companies will keep scoring people in areas like finance, criminality, rental housing, or mail-order businesses. It works like a charm and some citizens are even welcoming the ideal of “digitally transparent” people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you have something that you don’t want anyone to know, maybe you shouldn’t be doing it in the first place -Eric Schmidt, Google&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it’s only a question of time until government institutions will pull all the information from different databases together and come up with a social score for each citizen. Arguments will be made for it improving the security of people and businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do we want to live in a world as predicted in the Black Mirror episode? Our societies have to be made aware of what algorithms really can, and cannot, do. Education is the answer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/social-scoring-system/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>politics</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-open-web-application-security-project-owasp-was-founded-in-2001-and-is-a-community-that-produces-freely-available-documentation-tools-articles-and-methodologies-in-the-field-of-security-and-risk-the-owasp-top-10-application-security-risk-list-was-first-published-in-2003-and-is-probably-the-closest-that-the-development-community-has-ever-come-to-a-set-of-rules-on-how-to-keep-products-secure&quot;&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Main_Page&quot;&gt;OWASP&lt;/a&gt;) was founded in 2001 and is a community that produces freely-available documentation, tools, articles, and methodologies in the field of security and risk. The “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_Application_Security_Risks&quot;&gt;OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risk&lt;/a&gt;” list was first published in 2003 and is probably the closest that the development community has ever come to a set of rules on how to keep products secure.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Top 10 list focuses on identifying the most serious web application security risks for a broad array of organizations. For each of these risks, generic information about the likelihood and technical impact is provided which is based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/OWASP_Risk_Rating_Methodology&quot;&gt;OWASP Risk Rating Methodology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a wasp&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many standards and organizations reference the Top 10 project, including but not limited to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Payment_Card_Industry_Data_Security_Standard&quot;&gt;PCI DSS&lt;/a&gt; or the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Federal_Trade_Commission&quot;&gt;FTC&lt;/a&gt;. The latest version of the list was released in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-goal-of-the-top-10&quot;&gt;The Goal of the Top 10&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of the list is to raise awareness for security issues in application development. It’s a guideline for avoiding common mistakes people make when they’re inexperienced, or don’t know any better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SQL injection and cross-site scripting vulnerabilities are regularly exploited and there is no sign of that changing anytime soon. The Top 10 makes people aware of those threats when writing code or auditing others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWASP’s Top 10 shouldn’t be used as a tick box exercise after the code is written and ready to be rolled out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approach of discrediting developers who fail to follow the teachings of OWASP is counterproductive and misses the goal of encouraging people to be more knowledgable about security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;team-culture-and-composition&quot;&gt;Team Culture and Composition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good security culture is about educating people. Giving them the knowledge and processes to stay secure. While it is always important to run QA and security checks before going live with a release, security is best baked into the product instead of built on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One increasingly trendy approach for bringing security into the heart of product development is in embedding security folks into cross-functional teams. This enables people to learn from each other and address security best practices in a less confrontational way. The OWASP Top 10 list will naturally be part of discussions in the team and awareness for common vulnerabilities will increase. The list is a great start for conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;improving-the-technologies&quot;&gt;Improving the Technologies&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Implementing tools along the deployment pipelines will help to amplify developers’ capabilities in addressing the OWASP Top 10 list.
Some examples are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Composition Analysis to address the Security of the  &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/software-supply-chain-security/&quot;&gt;Software Supply Chain&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Static Code Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dynamic Code Analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuously applied tests and analysis provide quick feedback and is helping teams to build better and more secure products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-2017-list&quot;&gt;The 2017 List&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a look at the latest list and the meaning of the risks. The list is created from gathering the data from hundreds of organizations and over 100,000 real-world applications and APIs. The Top 10 items are selected and prioritized according to this prevalence data, in combination with consensus estimates of exploitability, detectability, and impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;owasp logo&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A1-Injection&quot;&gt;A1:2017-Injection&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Injection flaws, such as SQL, NoSQL, OS, and LDAP injection, occur when untrusted data is sent to an interpreter as part of a command or query. The attacker’s hostile data can trick the interpreter into executing unintended commands or accessing data without proper authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A2-Broken_Authentication&quot;&gt;A2:2017-Broken Authentication&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Application functions related to authentication and session management are often implemented incorrectly, allowing attackers to compromise passwords, keys, or session tokens, or to exploit other implementation flaws to assume other users’ identities temporarily or permanently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A3-Sensitive_Data_Exposure&quot;&gt;A3:2017-Sensitive Data Exposure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Many web applications and APIs do not properly protect sensitive data, such as financial, healthcare, and PII. Attackers may steal or modify such weakly protected data to conduct credit card fraud, identity theft, or other crimes. Sensitive data may be compromised without extra protection, such as encryption at rest or in transit, and requires special precautions when exchanged with the browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A4-XML_External_Entities_(XXE)&quot;&gt;A4:2017-XML External Entities (XXE)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Many older or poorly configured XML processors evaluate external entity references within XML documents. External entities can be used to disclose internal files using the file URI handler, internal file shares, internal port scanning, remote code execution, and denial of service attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A5-Broken_Access_Control&quot;&gt;A5:2017-Broken Access Control&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Restrictions on what authenticated users are allowed to do are often not properly enforced. Attackers can exploit these flaws to access unauthorized functionality and/or data, such as access other users’ accounts, view sensitive files, modify other users’ data, change access rights, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A6-Security_Misconfiguration&quot;&gt;A6:2017-Security Misconfiguration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Security misconfiguration is the most commonly seen issue. This is commonly a result of insecure default configurations, incomplete or ad hoc configurations, open cloud storage, misconfigured HTTP headers, and verbose error messages containing sensitive information. Not only must all operating systems, frameworks, libraries, and applications be securely configured, but they must be patched/upgraded in a timely fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A7-Cross-Site_Scripting_(XSS)&quot;&gt;A7:2017-Cross-Site Scripting (XSS)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - XSS flaws occur whenever an application includes untrusted data in a new web page without proper validation or escaping, or updates an existing web page with user-supplied data using a browser API that can create HTML or JavaScript. XSS allows attackers to execute scripts in the victim’s browser which can hijack user sessions, deface web sites, or redirect the user to malicious sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A8-Insecure_Deserialization&quot;&gt;A8:2017-Insecure Deserialization&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Insecure deserialization often leads to remote code execution. Even if deserialization flaws do not result in remote code execution, they can be used to perform attacks, including replay attacks, injection attacks, and privilege escalation attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A9-Using_Components_with_Known_Vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;A9:2017-Using Components with Known Vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Components, such as libraries, frameworks, and other software modules, run with the same privileges as the application. If a vulnerable component is exploited, such an attack can facilitate serious data loss or server takeover. Applications and APIs using components with known vulnerabilities may undermine application defenses and enable various attacks and impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10-2017_A10-Insufficient_Logging%26Monitoring&quot;&gt;A10:2017-Insufficient Logging&amp;amp;Monitoring&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; - Insufficient logging and monitoring, coupled with missing or ineffective integration with incident response, allows attackers to further attack systems, maintain persistence, pivot to more systems, and tamper, extract, or destroy data. Most breach studies show time to detect a breach is over 200 days, typically detected by external parties rather than internal processes or monitoring.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/owasp-top-10/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/owasp-top-10/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptographic Deletion</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;recent-advances-in-privacy-laws-and-regulations-like-the-right-to-be-forgotten-or-gdpr-show-that-secure-deletion-is-becoming-a-requirement-for-organizations&quot;&gt;Recent advances in privacy laws and regulations like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Right_to_be_forgotten&quot;&gt;right to be forgotten&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/General_Data_Protection_Regulation&quot;&gt;GDPR&lt;/a&gt; show that secure deletion is becoming a requirement for organizations.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;most-companies-dont-consider-this-when-using-todays-cloud-storage-services-established-processes-for-the-secure-deletion-of-on-site-storage-do-not-apply-to-the-cloud-storage-service-of-choice&quot;&gt;Most companies don’t consider this when using today’s cloud storage services. Established processes for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.simsrecycling.com/reuse/data-destruction/&quot;&gt;secure deletion of on-site storage&lt;/a&gt; do not apply to the cloud storage service of choice.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/deletion.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a person burning a paper&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deletion-of-data&quot;&gt;Deletion of Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a unix-style filesystem, every file or directory (technically there is no difference between them) has an inode. This inode contains all of the metadata like the owner or the creation date. The inode also contains a list of all the blocks in which a file is stored. Those blocks are called data blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://linux.die.net/man/1/rm&quot;&gt;default linux delete command&lt;/a&gt; removes just the inode information. The data blocks remain - no inode is pointing to them and the filesystem will overwrite them eventually. This means that the actual data is recoverable until the data blocks are used again by a new file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-sanitization&quot;&gt;Data Sanitization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data sanitization is the process of deliberately, permanently and irreversibly removing or destroying the data stored on a device and make it unrecoverable. A device that has been sanitized has no usable data. Even advanced forensic tools will not be able to recover any data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three methods to achieve &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.datasanitization.org/data-sanitization-terminology/#data-sanitization&quot;&gt;data sanitization&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;physical destruction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cryptographic erasure&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;data erasure&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deletion-in-the-cloud&quot;&gt;Deletion in the cloud&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud providers use abstraction to map physical resources to logical endpoints. The resulting pool of virtual resources is used for servers, storage systems, or networks. This enables customers to scale their workload easily across multiple physical devices but makes it very difficult to verify the location and absolute state of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a operation centre&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud-based storage solutions are a popular service today. But the adoption of such storage services challenges organizations in regards to secure data deletion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a cloud storage scenario, the data sanitization methods of physical destruction and data erasure are no longer applicable. Physical devices are shared amongst different applications or even customers and cloud providers use complex tiered-storage setups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://help.dropbox.com/files-folders/restore-delete/delete-files&quot;&gt;Dropbox&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/security/deletion/&quot;&gt;google cloud storage&lt;/a&gt; inform about their secure deletion and hardware decommission concepts. None are deleting immediate or verifiable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cryptographic-deletion&quot;&gt;Cryptographic Deletion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptographic deletion or crypto-shredding is the practice of deliberately deleting or overwriting the decryption key for encrypted data. Effectively making the data unreadable until the deployed encryption protocol is broken or being brute-forced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Crypto-shredding is an effective technique for the cloud since it ensures that any data in storage that’s outside of an organization’s physical control is unreadable once the keys are unavailable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider the following for cryptographic deletion:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a strong &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-symmetric/&quot;&gt;symmetric encryption algorithm&lt;/a&gt; like AES-256-CBC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;only store the sensitive data that you need (&lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-5-gdpr/&quot;&gt;Art. 5 GDRP 1c&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;consider BYOE (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bring_your_own_encryption&quot;&gt;bring your own encryption&lt;/a&gt;) and avoid vendor lock-in with cloud providers crypto services&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;document your approach for the authorities and verify the key deletion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;crypto-shredding is only as good as the deletion of the key (consider key backups)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;the unpredictable pace of technological development could render many encryption methods unreliable in the future&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/cryptographic-deletion/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/cryptographic-deletion/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>PGP - The Web of Trust is Dead</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;pretty-good-privacy-was-committed-to-making-good-encryption-available-to-everyone-the-used-crypto-was-revolutinary-at-the-time-but-one-of-the-big-problems-with-key-encryption-persisted-how-do-i-get-the-right-key-from-the-person-i-dont-know&quot;&gt;Pretty Good Privacy was committed to making good encryption available to everyone. The used crypto was revolutinary at the time. But one of the big problems with key encryption persisted: How do I get the right key from the person I don’t know?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-of-trust&quot;&gt;Web of Trust&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web of Trust was intended for this exact purpose but only ever worked in a small community of PGP fans. The promise of “encryption for the masses” could never be kept. The inflationary signing of keys causes serious problems and is, therefore, removed in GnuPG in version 2.2.17. By default this version is ignoring all signatures coming from a key server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis of the Web of Trust is that “no two people are more than six degrees apart”. Everybody knows everyone. If you authenticate the key of your acquaintances, you’ll eventually reach a state where you can trust the key of person X that came from a central key server. Alter all, the sister of your uncles friend confirmed that the key actually belonged to X and wasn’t placed there by some malicious actor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyone can sign any key and upload the signed version to the keyserver - in theory only after verifying its authenticity. To prevent state actors from forcing key server operators to replace real keys with fake ones, the Synchronizing Key Server (SKS) was designed in such a way that no key or signatures can be deleted. This, however, enabled a range of abuse scenarios. Currently, unknown people load keys onto keyservers again and again, which carry hundreds of thousands of signatures. Read the crisis communication by &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/rjhansen/67ab921ffb4084c865b3618d6955275f&quot;&gt;Robert J. Hansen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whoever imports such a key will stall their PGP installation. There is currently no known fix on the side of the SKS servers. Other options to rescue PGP had to be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We’ve known for a decade this attack is possible. It’s now here and it’s devastating” rjh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-end-of-key-signatures&quot;&gt;The end of key signatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a direct response, GnuPG from version 2.2.17 added a new option &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;self-sign-only&lt;/code&gt;, which is now a default option. It ensures that only the key servers own signatures are retained when a key is imported. The spam signatures and also those of the sister of your uncles friend - are no longer imported into the local keychain. This doesn’t affect manually imported keys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This solves the signature spam problem for GPG users. But it comes with a hefty price tag. You no longer have any indication as to whether the imported key from a server is real or not. This problem is real because anyone can upload a key for any identity to the key servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenPGP enthusiasts introduced a new keyserver a few weeks ago. It verifies the e-mail address given in the key and only publishes it after successful verification. As things currently stand, there are a lot of arguments for using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;keys.openpgp.org&lt;/code&gt; instead of the SKS servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/mailbox.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a mailbox&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-future&quot;&gt;The future&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Web of Trust is practically dead and can be considered a failure. The question arises on how the trust in PGP keys can be restored. Some people argue the community should look at messengers like Signal and Threema. They provide a convenient way of key verification and do not require any user actions or signatures. Those services provide basic trust in the genuineness of the delivered keys.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/web-of-trust-dead/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/web-of-trust-dead/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Password Entropy</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;entropy-is-a-way-to-express-the-unpredictability-of-a-character-or-string-it-is-based-on-the-number-of-characters-the-set-and-the-length-of-a-given-string&quot;&gt;Entropy is a way to express the unpredictability of a character or string. It is based on the number of characters (the set) and the length of a given string.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One can think of entropy as the randomness of a string. A password with high entropy is theoretically harder to brute force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;disclaimer&quot;&gt;Disclaimer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security features should be seen as sequential measures, where one failing safeguard is protected by another one. Weakening one link in the security chain reduces the overall security. I am therefore a strong supporter of password policies with a high entropy potential, rate-limits, multi-factor authentication, and &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/gdpr-passwords-hashing-you/&quot;&gt;strong hashing functions&lt;/a&gt; for password storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/complex.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing chaos&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;random-passwords&quot;&gt;Random Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In computer science, it is common to specify the password strength of a random password in bits of entropy. This approach is derived from &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Entropy_(information_theory)&quot;&gt;information theory&lt;/a&gt;. Instead of the number of guesses needed to find the password with certainty, the base-2 logarithm of that number is used, which is the number of “entropy bits” in a password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The formula to calculate the entropy is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;H = log2(N^L)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt; = entropy, &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; = character set or number of possible symbols, &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt; = string length or number of characters&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A password with an entropy of 128 bits calculated in this way would be as strong as a string of 128 bits chosen randomly, for example by a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fair_coin&quot;&gt;fair coin toss&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To find the length, &lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;, needed to achieve the desired strength &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;, with a password, created randomly from a set of &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt; symbols, one computes (rounded up to the next largest whole number)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;L = H/(log2N)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a table with some character sets and how many digits are required for 128 bit of entropy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;character set&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;symbol count &lt;strong&gt;N&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;entropy per symbol &lt;strong&gt;H&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;symbols required for 128 bits of entropy&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;fair coin 0/1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;1.000 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;arabic numerals (0-9)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;3.322 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;39&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;hexadecimal numerals (0–9, A–F) (e.g. WEP keys)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;16&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.000 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case insensitive Latin alphabet (a–z or A–Z)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;26&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;4.700 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case sensitive Latin alphabet (a–z, A–Z)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;52&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.700 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;case sensitive alphanumeric (a–z, A–Z, 0–9)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;62&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;5.954 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;22&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;all ASCII printable characters&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;95&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;6.570 bits&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: right&quot;&gt;20&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wrote a short python script to calculate the theoretical entropy of a random password:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#!/usr/bin/python3
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;argparse&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kn&quot;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nn&quot;&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;argparse&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;ArgumentParser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_argument&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;num_symbols&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;character set or number of symbols&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;add_argument&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;length&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;help&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;password length in characters&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;parse_args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;print&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;log2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;num_symbols&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;**&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;args&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;human-generated-passwords&quot;&gt;Human-generated Passwords&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People are notoriously poor at achieving sufficient entropy to produce satisfactory passwords. According to one study involving half a million users &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/wp-content/uploads/2006/11/www2007.pdf&quot;&gt;PDF&lt;/a&gt;, the average password entropy was estimated at 40.54 bits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It gets worse with the most common number used is “1”, and the most common letters are a, e, o, and r. Users don’t make full use of larger character sets when forming passwords. For example, hacking results obtained from a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wired.com/2006/12/myspace-passwords-arent-so-dumb/?currentPage=all&quot;&gt;MySpace phishing scheme in 2006&lt;/a&gt; revealed 34,000 passwords, of which only 8.3% used mixed case, numbers, and symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The full strength associated with using a certain character set is only achieved if each possible password is equally likely. The human behavior is a reduction of the theoretical password “strength”. A better requirement would be to require a password &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; to contain words from dictionaries or names. If patterned choices are required, humans are likely to use them in predictable ways, such a capitalizing a letter, adding only one or two numbers, and a special character. This predictability means that the increase in password strength is minor when compared to random passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;common-password-guidelines-in-2019&quot;&gt;Common Password Guidelines in 2019&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a password manager to generate truly random passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use a minimum password length of 12 or more characters.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use lowercase, uppercase alphabetic characters, numbers and symbols if permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid using the same password twice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid using information that is or could be publicly associated with the user.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoid character repetition, keyboard patterns, dictionary words, letter or number sequences (e.g. dates), usernames, names (ancestors, pets, [ex]partners), biographical information (e.g. ID number)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check passwords against those obtained from previous data breaches (e.g. &lt;a href=&quot;https://haveibeenpwned.com/Passwords&quot;&gt;HIBP&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/password-entropy/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/password-entropy/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adaptive Transaction Security by Contact Frequency</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;adaptive-security-is-traditionally-a-network-security-model-to-accommodate-for-the-increasing-complexity-of-threats-targeting-the-network-of-organizations-intrusion-detection-systems-for-example-are-one-application-of-adaptive-security-and-use-a-heuristic-system-that-correlates-information-to-make-recommendations-rather-than-using-hard-blocking-rules-as-a-firewall-does&quot;&gt;Adaptive security is traditionally a network security model to accommodate for the increasing complexity of threats targeting the network of organizations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Intrusion_detection_system&quot;&gt;Intrusion Detection Systems&lt;/a&gt;, for example, are one application of adaptive security and use a heuristic system that correlates information to make recommendations rather than using hard blocking rules as a &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firewall_(computing)&quot;&gt;Firewall&lt;/a&gt; does.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally, Adaptive Security is an approach to cybersecurity that analyzes behaviors and events to continuously assess risk and automatically provide proportional enforcement that can be dialed up or down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest this model to adopt the transaction security features for an imaginary online bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;traditional-transaction-security-in-banking&quot;&gt;Traditional Transaction Security in Banking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Financial information is surely near the top of the list of all the things people want to keep safe. The login to the online system of a bank is usually only protected by username (identification) and password (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Authentication&quot;&gt;authentication&lt;/a&gt;) and gives access to the account in a read-only mode. Past transaction and account information can only be looked at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second layer of security (&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Multi-factor_authentication&quot;&gt;two-factor authentication&lt;/a&gt;) is necessary once the user intends to do an online change to the account. This change could be a new standing order, a money transaction, or the change of the address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional authentication methods vary from bank to bank and include one-time passwords from a tan list (classic TAN), SMS or push notifications to mobile devices (mobileTAN or pushTAN), or the use of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:SmartTAN_optic-Gadget.jpg&quot;&gt;device to create the TAN&lt;/a&gt; (cardTAN or chipTAN).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/adaptive.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a chameleon&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adaptive-transaction-security&quot;&gt;Adaptive Transaction Security&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to suggest a security model where the frequency of interaction between people can be used to remove the enforcement of a second factor for future transactions between those people. This model is improving the usability for the customer while it manages the risk of fraud for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A malicious player who hacks the account could not benefit from the removal of 2FA for those transactions because it would only whitelist accounts with a strong transaction relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;graph-database&quot;&gt;Graph Database&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graph Databases allow to represent related data as it is as a set of objects connected by a set of relationships. Graph theory dates back to 1735, when Leonard Euler solved the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Seven_Bridges_of_K%C3%B6nigsberg&quot;&gt;Seven Bridges of Königsberg&lt;/a&gt; problem by devising a topology consisting of nodes and relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In computing, a graph database uses graph structures for semantic queries with nodes, edges, and properties to represent and store data. A key concept of the system is the graph (relationship). The graph relates the data items in the store to a collection of nodes and edges, the edges representing the relationships between the nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Graph databases, by design, allow simple and fast retrieval of complex hierarchical structures that are difficult to model in relational systems. A graph is essentially an index data structure. It never needs to load or touch unrelated data for a given query. They’re an excellent solution for real-time big data analytical queries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some example transactions between four people. Each customer and transaction is an object and the transaction flow is represented by a graph.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;_:bob &amp;lt;first.name&amp;gt; &quot;Bob&quot; .
_:alice &amp;lt;first.name&amp;gt; &quot;Alice&quot; .
_:chuck &amp;lt;first.name&amp;gt; &quot;Chuck&quot; .
_:rudi &amp;lt;first.name&amp;gt; &quot;Rudi&quot; .
_:bob &amp;lt;sends&amp;gt; _:tn1 .
_:alice &amp;lt;receives&amp;gt; _:tn1 .
_:bob &amp;lt;sends&amp;gt; _:tn2 .
_:alice &amp;lt;receives&amp;gt; _:tn2 .
...
_:bob &amp;lt;receives&amp;gt; _:tn19 .
_:alice &amp;lt;sends&amp;gt; _:tn20 .
_:bob &amp;lt;receives&amp;gt; _:tn20 .
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I inject the data into &lt;a href=&quot;https://dgraph.io/&quot;&gt;dgraph&lt;/a&gt; and visualize the amount of nodes (transactions) between people:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/graph.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing the relationship&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see a strong relationship between Alice and Bob. Alice is sending money on a regular basis to Bob. We could suggest her to remove 2FA when initiating new transactions to Bob. A more advanced data model with additional parameters, like the transaction value and the date, would help to consider only certain transactions between Alice and Bob.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, effective security came at the expense of usability and vice versa. Today we have technologies that present the user with appropriate security solutions to match the task, risk, and real world scenario. Organizations need to start looking at the historical data and use it to tailor security around it. Smart risk management models can be applied to benefit the user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nobody will question strong authentication when a first-time transaction is made to a vendor in a foreign country. But having the same requirements whenever sending money to siblings, parents, or friends just doesn’t make any sense. Using the frequency of interaction with other people can help to accomplish security features that adapt to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/adaptive-transaction-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/adaptive-transaction-security/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptography - Applications</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-the-last-article-in-my-series-about-cryptography-now-that-we-covered-the-crypto-basics-with-various-cryptographic-algorithms-digital-signatures-and-public-key-infrastructure-we-can-take-a-look-at-applied-cryptography&quot;&gt;This is the last article in my series about cryptography. Now that we covered the crypto basics with various cryptographic algorithms, digital signatures, and public-key infrastructure, we can take a look at applied cryptography.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-history-basics/&quot;&gt;First Part: Cryptography - History and Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-symmetric/&quot;&gt;Second Part: Cryptography - Symmetric Key Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key/&quot;&gt;Third Part: Cryptography - Asymmetric Key Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/&quot;&gt;Fourth Part: Cryptography - Hash Functions &amp;amp; Digital Signatures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;web-appications---tlsssl&quot;&gt;Web Appications - TLS/SSL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web traffic is widely protected by encryption. There are many reasons for it but the main topics are the protection of user privacy, secure logins (username/password), and the exchange of financial information over the web. There ware two technologies responsible for the small lock icon in the web browser. Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) and Transport Layer Security (TLS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/https.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a web browser&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSL&lt;/strong&gt; was developed by Netscape to provide encrypted web traffic between client and server. Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure (HTTPS) is using port 443 to communicate sessions between browser clients and web servers. When Microsoft adopted SSL into its popular Internet Explorer browser in 1995, it became the de facto standard for secure web communication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL depends on the exchange of server digital certificates to negotiate encryption/decryption parameters between the browser and the web server. The goal of the protocol is to create a secure channel that remains open for an entire web browsing session. SSL uses a combination of symmetric and asymmetric cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:&lt;/strong&gt; The browser retrieves the web server certificate and extracts the public key from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:&lt;/strong&gt; The browser creates a random symmetric key, encrypts it with the servers public key and sends it back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:&lt;/strong&gt; The server decrypts the symmetric key with its own private key and the two systems exchange all future messages using symmetric key encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SSL utilizes the advanced functionality of asymmetric cryptography for the exchange of the secret key while the majority of data is exchanged using the faster symmetric algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TLS&lt;/strong&gt; was proposed by security engineers in 1991 as a replacement for the SSL standard. As with SSL, TLS uses TCP port 443 but incorporated many security enhancements. While the early version of TLS supported a downgrade to SSL, this backward compatibility was dropped in 2011 with TLS v1.2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, an attack known as &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/POODLE&quot;&gt;POODLE&lt;/a&gt; demonstrated a flaw in the SSL 3.0 fallback mechanism of TLS. Many organizations have since completely dropped SSL support and solely rely on TLS now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TLS is also utilized to encrypt communication between mobile applications and API endpoints. Apple even enforces this since January 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;email---pgp-openpgp-and-smime&quot;&gt;Email - PGP, OpenPGP and S/MIME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electronic mail (email or e-mail) is a method of exchanging messages between people using electronic devices. It first entered limited use in the 1960s and by the mid-1970s had taken the form now recognized as email. Email may travel and be stored on networks and computers without the sender’s or the recipient’s control. During the transit, it is possible that third parties read or even modify the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Email messages not encrypted by default.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Email messages have to go through intermediate computers before reaching their destination, meaning it is relatively easy for others to intercept and read messages.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Email messages are stored on servers and can be accessed by IT personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/email.png&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing email&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are solutions to protect emails in transit (e.g. SMTP over TLS) but for sensitive email messages, it is recommended to use end-to-end encryption and not rely on email providers goodwill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some recommendations for email usage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Confidentiality can be achieved by &lt;em&gt;message encryption&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Integrity and nonrepudiation require to &lt;em&gt;hash the message&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Authentication, integrity and non repudiation can be implemented by &lt;em&gt;digitally signing the message&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Confidentiality, authentication, integrity, and nonrepudiation requires &lt;em&gt;encrypting and digitally signing the message&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PGP - Pretty Good Privacy&lt;/strong&gt; was invented by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Phil_Zimmermann&quot;&gt;Phil Zimmerman&lt;/a&gt; in 1991 and made available to the public. It initially encountered a number of hurdles by the U.S. government regarding its distribution (export regulation). Those restrictions have been repealed, and PGP may be freely distributed to most countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commercial version of PGP uses RSA for key exchange, IDEA for encryption/decryption, and MD5 as the hash function for message digest creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenPGP&lt;/strong&gt; is the freeware version of PGP and uses Diffie-Hellman for key exchange, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CAST-128&quot;&gt;CAST 128-bit&lt;/a&gt; for encryption/decryption, and the SHA-1 algorithm as the hash function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;S/MIME&lt;/strong&gt; is the Secure/Multipurpose Internet Mail Extension protocol and has emerged as a de facto standard for encrypted email. It has been incorporated in a large number of commercial products and relies on the usage of X.509 certificates (see my posting about &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key-infrastructure/&quot;&gt;PKI&lt;/a&gt;). S/MIME extracts the public key from the certificate (same as TLS) and uses it for digital signing and the exchange of symmetric keys. RSA is the public key cryptographic protocol of S/MIME and AES or 3DES is used for symmetric encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;data-encryption-on-portable-devices---notebooks-smartphones-and-tablets&quot;&gt;Data Encryption on Portable Devices - Notebooks, Smartphones, and Tablets&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wide usage of portable devices brings new risks to organizations. Notebooks, Smartphones, and Tablets often contain highly sensitive information that could cause serious harm if the device is lost or stolen. Many organizations turn to encryption to protect the data on these devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Current versions of all operating systems now include disk encryption capabilities that make it easy to manage encryption on all devices. Microsoft Windows includes BitLocker and Encrypting File System (EFS), MacOSX includes FileVault encryption and the open-source &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.veracrypt.fr/en/Home.html&quot;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt; allows disk encryption on Linux, MacOSX, and Windows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a variety of commercial tools to provide added features and device management capabilities. The differentiators of those tools are how they protect the keys stored in memory, whether they encrypt full disk (FDE) or only volumes, and if they support hardware-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Trusted_Platform_Module&quot;&gt;Trusted Platform Modules (TPMs)&lt;/a&gt;. A TPM is a chip that can often be found in modern computer devices. It provides the operating system with access to the keys and prevents the decryption of a disk device in case the drive is removed from the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any selection of an encryption software must include an analysis of the capabilities during the due diligence process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;networking&quot;&gt;Networking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Providing secure networking services is an important application of cryptography. Generally, there are two different concepts at play. &lt;em&gt;Link encryption&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;End-to-end encryption&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Link encryption&lt;/strong&gt; is the concept of creating a secure tunnel between two points using either a hardware or software solution. In this concept, all traffic entering one side of the tunnel is encrypted and decrypted on the other side. Link encryption is protocol independent and encrypts all the traffic including data, header, address, or routing information. An example is the VPN connection between two offices. Link encryption usually happens at the lower layers of the OSI model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;End-to-end encryption&lt;/strong&gt; protects the communication between two parties like a client and a server and is performed independently from the network link. It is found in the higher layers of the OSI model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SSH - Secure Shell&lt;/strong&gt; is an example of &lt;em&gt;end-to-end encryption&lt;/em&gt; and provides encrypted alternatives to common internet applications such as FTP, Telnet, and rlogin. SSH1 supports DES, 3DES, IDEA, and Blowfish and is considered insecure. SSH2 drops the support of DES and IDEA and adds several other algorithms like Diffie-Hellman for key exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IPSec&lt;/strong&gt; is a security architecture that supports secure communications and is a standard of the Internet Engineering Task Force (IETF). The Internet Protocol Security (IPSec) secures the communication between two entities. Those entities can be routers, gateways, or any combination of those. Generally, IPSec is used to connect two networks but it can also connect one computer to a network or two computers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses public-key encryption to provide access control, nonrepudiation, and message authenticity. IPSec is primarily used for virtual private networks (VPN) and can operate in either a tunnel or transport mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tunnel mode encrypts the entire packet (including the header) and is designed for securing gateway to gateway communication.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Transport mode encrypts only the payload and is designed for securing peer-to-peer communication.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IPSec is commonly paired with the Layer 2 Tunneling Protocol (L2TP) and then known as L2TP/IPSec. The protocol provides a complete infrastructure to secure network communication and has gained widespread acceptance in all major operating systems. It relies on two components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Authentication Header (AH) provides message integrity, nonrepudiation, authentication, and access control.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) provides confidentiality and integrity of packet content. It has limited authentication features but not to the extent of AH.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IPSec is creating a &lt;em&gt;security association&lt;/em&gt; (SA) during runtime. This SA represents a simplex communication session and configuration. Two-way communication requires two SAs and for using both AH and ESP in two-way communication, the requirement is four SAs. The advantage is that each SA can be filtered or managed independently which gives IPSec its flexibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ISAKMP&lt;/strong&gt; provides the background security support services of IPSec by negotiating, establishing, modifying, and deleting security associations. ISKMP is described in detail in &lt;a href=&quot;https://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc2408&quot;&gt;RFC 2408&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wireless-networking&quot;&gt;Wireless Networking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The widespread adoption of wireless networks creates a tremendous security risk. Traditional wired networks do not implement encryption for routine communication between host because of the assumption that it would be too difficult for an attacker to gain physical access to the network equipment. Wireless networks transmit data through the air, leaving them extremely vulnerable to interception. There are two types of wireless security implementations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WEP - Wireless Equivalent Privacy&lt;/strong&gt; provides 64- and 128-bit encryption options to protect wireless communication. WEP is described in IEE 802.11 as an optional component of the wireless networking standard. Cryptanalysis has demonstrated significant flaws in the WEP algorithm. This makes it possible to completely undermine the security features of a WEP protected network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WPA - WiFi Protected Access&lt;/strong&gt; improves on WEP encryption by implementing a Temporal Key Integrity Protocol (TKIP). WPA2 is adding AES cryptography to the protocol, improving it even further. WPA2 is the de facto standard for protecting wireless networks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cryptography-key-sizes-and-recommendations&quot;&gt;Cryptography Key Sizes and Recommendations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://paragonie.com/blog/2019/03/definitive-2019-guide-cryptographic-key-sizes-and-algorithm-recommendations&quot;&gt;Paragon Guide&lt;/a&gt; holds some good advice for Cryptographic Key Sizes and Algorithm Recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symmetric Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Block Size&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Key Size&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Advanced Encryption Standard (AES)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128, 192, 256&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rijndael&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128, 192, 256&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Blowfish&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32 - 448&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Data Encryption Standard (DES)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;56&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;IDEA&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rivest Cipher 2 (RC2)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Rivest Cipher 5 (RC5)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;32, 64, 128&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;0 - 2,040&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Skipjack&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Triple DES (3DES)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;64&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;112, 168&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Twofish&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1 - 256&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hash Algorithms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Digest Size&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SHA-1&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SHA-256, SHA3-256&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;256&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SHA-224, SHA3-224&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;224&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SHA-512, SHA3-512&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;512&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;SHA-384, SHA3-384&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;384&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MD2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MD4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;128&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;MD5&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;160&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;HMAC&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Variable&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/applied-cryptography/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/applied-cryptography/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cryptography - Hash Functions &amp; Digital Signatures</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;welcome-to-the-fourth-posting-in-a-series-about-cryptography-this-article-is-about-hash-functions-and-digital-signatures&quot;&gt;Welcome to the fourth posting in a series about cryptography. This article is about hash functions and digital signatures.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-history-basics/&quot;&gt;First Part: Cryptography - History and Basics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-symmetric/&quot;&gt;Second Part: Cryptography - Symmetric Key Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key/&quot;&gt;Third Part: Cryptography - Asymmetric Key Algorithms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hash-functions---definition&quot;&gt;Hash Functions - Definition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hash functions take a potentially long message as the input and generate a unique output value from the content. The output of a hash function is commonly referred to as the &lt;em&gt;message digest&lt;/em&gt;. Hashing is a one-way function and with a properly designed algorithm, there is no way to reverse the hashing process to reveal the original input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compare this to encryption (two-way function) which allows encryption and decryption with the proper key or key-pair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another use case of hash functions is in data structures like &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hash_table&quot;&gt;hash tables&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bloom_filter&quot;&gt;bloom filters&lt;/a&gt;. The goal here is not security but rapid data lookup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my posting about &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/gdpr-passwords-hashing-you/&quot;&gt;password hashing&lt;/a&gt;, we had the requirement that the same input provides different outputs (nondeterministic). This is achieved by a random salt and prevents attacks against low-entropy secrets like passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hash functions in the context of digital signatures are supposed to produce the same output for the same input (deterministic). This enables the recipient of a message to recompute the &lt;em&gt;message digest&lt;/em&gt; with the same hash function and compare it to the transmitted digest to verify that the message wasn’t modified in transit. If the message has even a minor difference in spacing, punctuation, or content, the message digest will be completely different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not possible to derive the degree of difference between two messages by comparing the digest. The slightest difference in the input will produce a totally different digest value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/one-way.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a city&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are five requirements for a cryptographic hash function:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The input can be of any length.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The output has a fixed length.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The hash function is relatively easy to compute for any input.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The hash function is one-way (this means it is extremely hard if not impossible to determine the input from the output).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The hash function is collision free (there can’t be two different messages producing the same hash value).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;sha---secure-hash-algorithm&quot;&gt;SHA - Secure Hash Algorithm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secure hash algorithm SHA and its successors, SHA-1, SHA-2, SHA-3, are government standard hash functions promoted by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHA-1&lt;/strong&gt; takes an input of virtually any length and produces a 160-bit message. It processes a message in 512-bit blocks. If a message length isn’t a multiple of 512-bit, the SHA algorithm pads the message with data until the length reaches the next highest multiple of 512-bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SHA-1 is no longer considered secure against well-funded adversaries. All major web browser manufactures sopped accepting SHA-1 SSL certificates in 2017. Google even &lt;a href=&quot;https://phys.org/news/2017-02-cwi-google-collision-industry-standard.html&quot;&gt;demonstrated&lt;/a&gt; a collision in SHA-1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHA-2&lt;/strong&gt; was published in 2001 as a reaction to the weaknesses in SHA-1. It includes significant changes from its predecessor and has four major variants:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SHA-256 produces a 256-bit message digest using a 512-bit block size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SHA-224 uses a truncated version of the SHA-256 hash and produces a 224-bit digest using a 512-bit block size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SHA-512 produces a 512-bit message digest using a 1,024-bit block size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SHA-384 uses a truncated version of the SHA-512 hash and produces a 384-bit digest using a 1,024-bit block size.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cryptographic community generally considers SHA-2 algorithms as secure, but it theoretically suffers from the same weakness as the SHA-1 algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHA-3&lt;/strong&gt; was published in 2015, while part of the same series of standards, SHA-3 is internally different from the MD5 like structure of SHA-1 and SHA-2. SHA-3 is a subset of the broader cryptographic primitive family Keccak. It was developed as a drop-in replacement of SHA-2, offering the same variants (SHA3-256/SHA3-224/SHA3-512/SHA3-384) and hash lengths but using a more secure algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;md2---message-digest&quot;&gt;MD2 - Message Digest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MD2 Message-Digest Algorithm was developed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ron_Rivest&quot;&gt;Ronald Rivest&lt;/a&gt; (yes, the one from Rivest, Shamir, and Adleman aka RSA Security) in 1989 to provide a secure hash function for 8-bit processors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MD2&lt;/strong&gt; pads the message to a length of a multiple of 16-bit and computes a 16-byte(!) checksum which is appended to the end of the input message. Then a 128-bit message digest is generated by using the original message along with the appended checksum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cryptanalytic attacks against the MD2 algorithm exist and it was even proven that MD2 is not a one-way function. Therefore, it should no longer be used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MD4&lt;/strong&gt; is an enhancement of MD2, was released in 1990 and supports 32-bit processors. It increases the security level with an enhanced algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MD4 pads the message to a length of 64-bit smaller than a multiple of 512-bits. The MD4 algorithm then processes 512-bit blocks of the message in thee rounds of computation to produce a 128-bit message digest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 8-bit message would be padded with 440 additional bits of data to make it 448-bits, which is 64-bit smaller than a 512-bit message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several flaws have been found in the MD4 algorithm and therefore it is no longer considered secure. Usage should be avoided if possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MD5&lt;/strong&gt; was released in 1991 as the next version of the message digest algorithm. It also processes 512-bit blocks of the message but uses four rounds of computation to produce the same 128-bit message digest length as in MD2 and MD4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MD5 has the same padding requirements as MD4, the message length must be 64-bit less than a multiple of 512-bit. MD5 introduced additional security features that reduced the speed of message digest production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent cryptanalytic attacks demonstrated that MD5 is subject to collisions. In 2005 it was demonstrated that two digital certificates from different public keys have the same MD5 hash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All algorithms in the MD family are no longer accepted as suitable hashing functions. However, they may still be found in use today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/digisign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture showing a city&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;digital-signatures&quot;&gt;Digital Signatures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a secure hash function, we can now implement a digital signature system. A digital signature infrastructure has two goals:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Digitally signed messages assure the recipient that the message came from the claimed sender. This provides nonrepudiation.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Digitally signed messages provide the recipient with the assurance that the message was not altered while in transit. This provides protection against malicious (man in the middle) or unintentional (communication interference) modification.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital signatures rely on the combination of two concepts, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/public-key/&quot;&gt;public-key cryptography&lt;/a&gt;, and hash functions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alice is sending a digitally signed but &lt;strong&gt;not encrypted&lt;/strong&gt; message to Bob:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1:&lt;/strong&gt; Alice generates a message digest of the original plaintext message using a secure hash function like SHA3-512.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2:&lt;/strong&gt; Alice then encrypts the message digest using her private key. The output is the digital signature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3:&lt;/strong&gt; Alice appends the digital signature to the plaintext message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:&lt;/strong&gt; Alice then sends the appended message to Bob&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:&lt;/strong&gt; Bob removes the digital signature from the appended message and decrypts it with the public key of Alice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6:&lt;/strong&gt; Bob calculates the hash of the plaintext message with SHA3-512.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:&lt;/strong&gt; Bob then compares the decrypted message digest he received from Alice with the message digest Bob computed. If the two digests match, he can be assured that the message he received was sent by Alice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The digital signature process does not provide any privacy by itself. It only ensures that the cryptographic goals of authentication, integrity, and nonrepudiation are met. If Alice wants to ensure the privacy of her message to Bob, she could encrypt the appended message generated in step &lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt; with the public key of Bob. Bob then would need to first decrypt the encrypted message with his private key before continuing with step &lt;strong&gt;5&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital signatures are used not only for messages but software vendors are often using digital signature technology to authenticate code distribution over insecure networks like the internet. &lt;strong&gt;Checksums&lt;/strong&gt; do not require any encryption key, they are simple digests of fingerprints to represent some kind of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hmac---hashed-message-authentication&quot;&gt;HMAC - Hashed Message Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hashed message authentication code (HMAC) algorithm implements a partial digital signature and guarantees the integrity of a message but it does not provide nonrepudiation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HMAC relies on the combination of two concepts, &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-symmetric/&quot;&gt;private-key cryptography&lt;/a&gt; and hash functions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMAC can be combined with any secure hash function such as SHA3. The resulting message authentication code (MAC) is called HMAC-SHA3. HMAC combines a secret key with a hash function and represents a halfway point between unencrypted use of a message digest algorithm and computationally expensive digital signature algorithms based on public-key cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HMAC does not encrypt the message. Instead, the message (encrypted or not) must be sent alongside the HMAC hash. Parties with the secret key will hash the message again themselves, and the received and computed hashes will match if it is authentic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dss---digital-signature-standard&quot;&gt;DSS - Digital Signature Standard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This standard specifies that all federally approved digital signature algorithms must use the SHA-3 hashing function. DSS also specifies the encryption algorithms that can be used to support digital signature infrastructure. Currently approved in version &lt;a href=&quot;https://nvlpubs.nist.gov/nistpubs/FIPS/NIST.FIPS.186-4.pdf&quot;&gt;186-4&lt;/a&gt; are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;DSA - Digital Signature Algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;RSA - Rivest-Shamir-Adleman Algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;ECDSA - Elliptic Curve DSA&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;key-confusion&quot;&gt;Key Confusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public-Key Cryptography and Digital Signatures can be confusing. Encryption, Decryptio, message signing, and signature verification all use the same algorithms with different key inputs. Here are a few simple rules:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You encrypt a message with the recipients public key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You decrypt a message with your own private key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You digitally sign a message with your own private key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You verify the signature of a message with the senders public key.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Personnel Security</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;humans-are-the-weakest-element-in-any-security-solution-no-matter-what-physical-or-logical-controls-are-deployed-humans-will-discover-ways-to-avoid-circumvent-subvert-or-disable-them-insider-threats-originate-from-past-or-present-employees-contractors-or-business-partners-they-can-misuse-their-inside-knowledge-or-access-to-harm-people-customers-assets-or-reputation&quot;&gt;Humans are the weakest element in any security solution. No matter what physical or logical controls are deployed, humans will discover ways to avoid, circumvent, subvert or disable them. Insider threats originate from past or present employees, contractors or business partners. They can misuse their inside knowledge or access to harm people, customers, assets or reputation.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;to-apply-security-governance-an-organization-has-to-address-the-weakest-link-in-the-security-chain---people&quot;&gt;To apply security governance, an organization has to address the weakest link in the security chain - people.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Issues, compromises, and problems related to humans occur at all stages and on all levels of an organization. People are involved throughout the development, implementation, and administration of a security solution and therefore have to be evaluated regarding their effect on the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strong relationship between the security department and human resources is essential to maintain control and minimize risks in an organization. 
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/personnel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing employees&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hiring-people&quot;&gt;Hiring People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a secure environment, the first step of hiring new personnel is to create a &lt;em&gt;job description&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;position description&lt;/em&gt;. Without this description, there is no consensus on what type of individual should be hired. Personnel should only be added to an organization because there is a need for their specific skills and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The description also has to include potential security issues originating from the position (e.g. handling of sensitive material or classified information). This classification of the position includes the type of access required (e.g. secure network) to perform the intended tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this information, the &lt;em&gt;screening of candidates&lt;/em&gt; can be performed. This involves background checks, verified reference calls, checking police and government records, and screening of social media accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hiring an individual, they need to sign an employment agreement. This document outlines the rules and restrictions of the organization, the security policies, and consequences of violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;separation-of-duties&quot;&gt;Separation of Duties&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Separation of duties&lt;/em&gt; is a security concept in which sensitive, critical and significant work is divided among individuals. This prevents undermining or subversion of security mechanisms by an individual. It also reduces the risk of collusion which is the occurrence of negative activity by two or more people. Collusion is often performed for the purpose of fraud, theft, or espionage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Limiting the power of individuals requires employees to work with others to commit large violations of security. Finding others to assist in a violation is more likely to leave behind detectable evidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;job-rotation&quot;&gt;Job Rotation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rotating employees among multiple job positions help an organization to improve its overall security. Job rotation servers two functions. It provides knowledge redundancy and reduces the risk of fraud, data modification, theft, sabotage, and misuse of information. The longer a person works in a specific position, the more likely they are to be assigned additional tasks and therefore expand their privileges and access.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Job rotation requires that privileges and access rights have to be reviewed regularly to maintain the principle of &lt;em&gt;least privilege&lt;/em&gt;. In failure to do so, the employee will accumulate privileges over time. This is called &lt;em&gt;privilege creep&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;onboarding&quot;&gt;Onboarding&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Onboarding&lt;/em&gt; is the process of adding a new employee to the identity and access management (IAM) system of an organization. The onboarding process is also performed when an employee’s role or position changes or when the person is awarded additional privilege or access rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/personnel_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing employees&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onboarding also refers to organizational socialization. In this process, the new employee is properly prepared for performing their job responsibilities. It includes training, job skill acquisition, and behavioral adaptation in order to integrate the employee efficiently into the existing processes and procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;offboarding-and-termination&quot;&gt;Offboarding and Termination&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The personnel security lifecycle includes the &lt;em&gt;Termination&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Offboarding&lt;/em&gt; of the employee. This stage is very critical and numerous issues must be addressed in order to maintain a secure environment. Termination should be handled in a private and respectful manner but this does not mean that no precautions should be taken. Once the employee has been informed of their release, they need to be escorted off the premises and are no longer allowed to return to their work area without an escort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the release, all keys, badges, cards, tokens, and the work equipment have to be collected. When possible an &lt;em&gt;exit interview&lt;/em&gt; should be performed. In this conversation, the liabilities and restrictions should be reviewed. This includes obligations based on the employment agreement, nondisclosure agreement, and any other security-related documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/personnel_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a picture representing employees&quot; style=&quot;left; padding: 10px 10px 10px 10px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is essential to offboard the employee from the IAM system shortly before or while informing the employee about the termination. Botched termination processes can cause critical damage to the organization. The completeness of information in the IAM system is critical for this process of disabling network access and removing company accounts from the individual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vendor-consultant-and-contractors&quot;&gt;Vendor, Consultant, and Contractors&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Controls have to be defined for vendors, consultants, and contractors in order to define the expectation, compensation, and consequences for external entities to the own organization. These controls are defined and documented in a &lt;em&gt;service-level-agreement&lt;/em&gt; or SLA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is best practice to put an SLA in place not only for external personnel but for all applications, connections, database, information systems, and any other critical part of an organizations infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By clearly defining the expectations and penalties for external parties, everyone involved knows what is expected of them and what the consequences are in case of a failure to meet the expectations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;onboarding&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;offboarding&lt;/em&gt; of external personnel have to follow the same procedures as the ones for regular staff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2019/personnel-security/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2019/personnel-security/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
