<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>cyber security and technology blog</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:14:08 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 18:14:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry PI - 10 Years of hacking</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-raspberry-pi-is-one-of-those-things-that-has-become-so-commonplace-that-you-wonder-how-we-ever-got-along-without-it-before-whenever-a-cheap-small-and-low-power-consuming-computer-is-required-the-pi-is-ready&quot;&gt;The Raspberry Pi is one of those things that has become so commonplace that you wonder how we ever got along without it before. Whenever a cheap, small, and low-power-consuming computer is required, the Pi is ready.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;originally-the-device-was-intended-for-classrooms-since-the-number-of-computer-science-students-in-the-uk-dropped-in-the-2000s-and-british-schoolchildren-were-to-be-inspired-by-the-single-board-computer&quot;&gt;Originally the device was intended for classrooms since the number of computer science students in the UK dropped in the 2000s, and British schoolchildren were to be inspired by the single-board computer.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Raspberry_Pi_4_Model_B_-_Side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-low-price-and-accessible-os-a-full-fledged-linux-runs-on-the-minicomputer-made-it-attractive-to-hackers-and-tinkerers-worldwide&quot;&gt;The low price and accessible OS, a full-fledged Linux runs on the minicomputer, made it attractive to hackers and tinkerers worldwide.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first model had a CPU with only one core clocked at 700 MHz and 256 MB of RAM, which was completely undersized for a PC or even smartphone of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten years and 40 million units sold later, a rich ecosystem has formed around all iterations of the little computer. There is a huge developer community that has developed open-source software for many applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-and-projects&quot;&gt;Applications And Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is hardly anything that can’t be monitored or controlled with the Raspberry Pi. Home automation is a big field of application: From &lt;a href=&quot;https://iotdesignpro.com/projects/iot-based-solenoid-door-lock-using-raspberry-pi-4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;door locks&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects-raspberry.com/home-alarm-system-with-raspberry-pi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alarm systems&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2020/07/24/a-complete-raspberry-pi-power-monitoring-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solar panels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.magicmirrorcentral.com/complete-raspberry-pi-magic-mirror-tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;smart mirrors&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://dordnung.de/raspberrypi-ledstrip/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lighting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi is also widely used for home entertainment. The microcomputer reliably provides &lt;a href=&quot;https://darko.audio/2020/01/raspberry-pi-audio-streaming-101/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;audio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pimylifeup.com/raspberry-pi-plex-server/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video streams&lt;/a&gt; to various devices in a home network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, one of the most frequently used applications is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;, a network-wide adblocker that uses a DNS filtering to block online advertising for all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-accomplished&quot;&gt;Mission Accomplished?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eben_Upton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eden Upton&lt;/a&gt; and his team had set out to create a classroom computer that is both inexpensive and very low-threshold to program and use. Even though it is used for teaching purposes in schools and universities, it is mainly utilized by tech-savvy people to automate their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As trivial as it may seem to technical users writing a Linux image to an SD card to boot the Raspberry Pi, this hurdle is too high for many people who are otherwise only used to their smartphone. Ultimately, Pi has not quite become what it was supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;against-consumerism&quot;&gt;Against Consumerism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all is lost as the Pi plays an important role in shaping our consumer culture. The industry has been designing smartphones and tablets so that they can largely only be operated in a consuming manner. Writing code yourself, intervening in the system, exchanging hardware components - has all become increasingly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, devices and apps are collecting more data than ever and sending them to manufacturers, for mostly no consumer benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi has formed a countermovement to this development. The operating system and most major software projects are open-source. Not only is it possible to add or swap hardware components but the system has to be assembled in the first place. The device triggers the creativity of users and motivates them to experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi hit a nerve with its features: sufficiently powerful, many connectors, cheap - but not too complicated, especially thanks to good Linux support and an active community. It has spawned a whole ecosystem and we hope the little microcomputer will continue to push the boundaries and provide users with an opportunity to tinker with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/raspberry-pi-anniversary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/raspberry-pi-anniversary/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>February 2022 Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/inversegravity.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cybersecurity-has-always-been-about-recognizing-and-responding-to-new-developments-each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-we-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity has always been about recognizing and responding to new developments. Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and we recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stop-storing-secrets-in-environment-variables&quot;&gt;Stop Storing Secrets In Environment Variables!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Hamilton argues that an application is the most trustworthy at initialization before the execution of business logic. He suggests utilizing ephemeral filesystems to provide secrets to an application. A very interesting article that got a lot of attention. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.forcesunseen.com/stop-storing-secrets-in-environment-variables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-beautiful-complexity-of-the-sha256-algorithm&quot;&gt;The beautiful complexity of the SHA256 Algorithm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/manceraio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Domingo Martin&lt;/a&gt; presents on his website the inner workings of the SHA256 hashing algorithm. Knowing the theory is one thing but having such an engaging graphical representation is quite a treat!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sha256algorithm.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-i-hacked-a-hardware-crypto-wallet-and-recovered-2-million&quot;&gt;How I hacked a hardware crypto wallet and recovered $2 million&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very entertaining video reached us from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joegrand&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joe Grand&lt;/a&gt; aka Kingpin. The video is running us through the hack of a Trezor One hardware wallet to recover $2 million in cryptocurrency (THETA). Joe uses a technique called fault-injection - also known as glitching — to undermine the security protection of the wallet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dT9y-KQbqi4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;watch&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898712/crypto-hardware-wallet-hacking-lost-bitcoin-ethereum-nft&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vQqFr3C363AsxquC-9oLwOdpNDU=/0x0:3360x1632/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3360x1632):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191888/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_2.53.21_PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;hack&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;father-accidentally-knocks-out-mobile-network&quot;&gt;Father accidentally knocks out mobile network&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between midnight and 3 AM every day of the week, the mobile network in the French municipality of Messanges did not work. Turns out a father wanted to prevent his children from surfing the Internet with a jammer - and as a side effect shut down the mobile network of a municipality in France. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/technology/dad-takes-down-towns-internet-by-mistake-to-get-his-kids-offline/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;open-source-tool-unredacter-makes-pixelated-text-readable-again&quot;&gt;Open-source tool Unredacter makes pixelated text readable again&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixelation is not a secure way to make text passages unreadable. The software “Unredacter”, developed by Dan Petro, a senior researcher at security provider Bishop Fox, takes redacted pixelized text and reverses it back into its readable form. We recommend a black bar to securely redact text. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bishopfox.com/blog/unredacter-tool-never-pixelation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;little-improvements-in-vulnerability-management&quot;&gt;Little improvements in vulnerability management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most organizations appear to be making little progress in addressing application security issues despite all of the heightened concerns around the topic. A study, by researchers at NTT Application Security, shows that organizations left more than half (53%) of known critical flaws nonremediated. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/key-application-security-metrics-show-little-sign-of-improvement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advisory-western-digital-my-cloud-pro-series&quot;&gt;Advisory: Western Digital My Cloud Pro Series&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wonderful world of IOT provides us with a dead simple command injection and execution for the WD PR4100. Turns out the device sends a HTTP (not HTTPS) based healthcheck to the WD remote cloud service every 300 seconds. This can be hijacked and untrusted data can be injected. The lack of input validation leads to the execution of said untrusted data.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iot-inspector.com/blog/advisory-western-digital-my-cloud-pro-series-pr4100-rce/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-022022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-022022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloud &amp; Schrems II: What now?</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;cloud-computing-has-been-one-of-the-most-disruptive-technologies-in-the-last-decade-unprecedented-flexibility-scalability-and-cost-effectiveness-seduced-organizations-to-equate-digital-transformation-with-cloud-migration&quot;&gt;Cloud computing has been one of the most disruptive technologies in the last decade. Unprecedented flexibility, scalability, and cost-effectiveness seduced organizations to equate digital transformation with cloud migration.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;but-in-2020-the-bright-future-of-cloud-computing-darkened-when-the-eu-court-of-justice-cjeu-invalidated-the-transfer-deal-privacy-shield-the-legal-foundation-on-which-eu-companies-outsourced-to-us-cloud-providers&quot;&gt;But in 2020, the bright future of cloud computing darkened when the EU Court of Justice (CJEU) invalidated the transfer deal “Privacy Shield”, the legal foundation on which EU companies outsourced to US cloud providers.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/schrems2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-so-called-schrems-ii-ruling-leaves-many-companies-in-an-awkward-situation-us-cloud-providers-are-mostly-no-help-and-retreat-to-mere-lip-services&quot;&gt;This so-called Schrems II ruling leaves many companies in an awkward situation. US cloud providers are mostly no help and retreat to mere lip services.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No false conclusions should be drawn from the supposed inaction of the data protection authorities. In the case of the USA in particular, the CJEU’s ruling has given the supervisory authorities clear guidelines that leave little room for discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we describe technical measures that organizations can take to continue the use of US cloud providers post-Schrems II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr-schrems-ii--us-cloud-act&quot;&gt;TL;DR Schrems II &amp;amp; US Cloud Act&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large US companies, such as Microsoft, Amazon, or Google, advertise that they have an EU subsidiary with server locations in Europe, which means that no transfer to the USA would take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Schrems II ruling states that a server located in the EU does not protect against US laws: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CLOUD_Act&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CLOUD Act&lt;/a&gt; authorizes US authorities to access data stored by US service providers and their subsidiaries outside the USA - even if this represents a conflict with local national law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CJEU notes that data protection standards, in general, cannot be guaranteed when outsourcing to US providers. US law is incompatible with the requirements of EU consumer rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the GDPR, EU businesses have to prevent unauthorized access to personal data. What’s new about Schrems II, however, is that this time we do not have to fear hackers or human error, but American law enforcement. The cloud environment has become hostile territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some technical safeguards for the post Schrems II era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-and-classification&quot;&gt;Assessment And Classification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task, in any case, is an honest evaluation of the situation to plan for supplementary measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What cloud providers are used?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What processes are outsourced to the provider?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which laws apply to the service provider?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the privacy and security policy appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of data is transferred?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do we need a data processing agreement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations are well-advised to maintain a detailed list of suppliers and sub-suppliers. The full outsourcing chain has to be considered. For example, an EU-based HR software provider can potentially run on a US infrastructure service (IaaS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymization&quot;&gt;Anonymization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completely anonymized data is not protected by the GDPR and can consequently be transferred to US cloud providers. The challenge is to preserve the usability of such anonymized data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenSource tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://arx.deidentifier.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ARX&lt;/a&gt; are very helpful in building proper documentation and help businesses to strike the right balance between anonymization and data usability. Proof for the anonymization must be defendable against objections from data authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smart-clients&quot;&gt;Smart Clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have written a whole article on this topic here: &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/privacy-client-shift/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shift To The Client&lt;/a&gt;. Smart Client architecture emphasizes the client over the backend when it comes to the processing and storage of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach has, for example, been chosen for the official German &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corona-Warn-App&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COVID-19 contact tracing app&lt;/a&gt;. The app is not supported by a centralized storage system and anonymized data is only shared when a warning to other users is initiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized architecture and smart clients are a much too rarely considered possibility when planning for a business case. With Schrems II, however, the traditional client-server architecture will be a challenge in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provider-independent-encryption&quot;&gt;Provider Independent Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud providers make key management easy to use with integrated services. But this doesn’t address the underlying issue of Schrems II since the key ownership stays with the cloud provider and therefore enables the provider to decrypt any sensitive data in transit or storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provider independent encryption (or key management) on the other hand is a suitable approach to prevent unauthorized access. Organizations with such a system can effectively block cloud providers from reading sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great solution for cloud storage solutions like Google Drive or Dropbox is the usage of key management services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptomator.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cryptomator&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boxcryptor.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Boxcryptor&lt;/a&gt;. These tools hide the content of files from the storage provider by implementing full end-to-end encryption (e2ee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cryptomator.org/img/home/split-screenshots.png&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have highlighted some technical ideas that can serve as a starting point for a cloud outsourcing approach in line with the GDPR. However, the most important question is if every single outsourcing project needs to be done with a US provider or whether there is not a suitable EU solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your battles carefully. The days of pragmatically transferring data to vendors and configuring something that somehow worked are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of outsourcing to the cloud lies in the deliberate planning of processing activities and supplementary measures to secure a run-of-the-mill cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-post-schrems2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-post-schrems2/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>January 2022 Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/inversegravity.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-we-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and we recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;log4j-newest-vulnerability-in-log4j-2170-more-hype-than-substance&quot;&gt;Log4j: Newest Vulnerability in Log4j 2.17.0 more hype than substance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/breadchris&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris Thompson&lt;/a&gt; has an insightful article about the current hype on log4j. With as much attention as there is now on the Log4j project, it can be difficult to truly understand the impact of the recently disclosed vulnerabilities when they are being compared against the original Log4Shell vulnerability, a perfect 10/10 severity. The latest vulnerabilities found in log4j 2.17.0 are much less serious. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lunasec.io/docs/blog/log4j-hype-train/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vulcano-breaks-communication-with-the-archipelago-tonga&quot;&gt;Vulcano breaks communication with the archipelago Tonga&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massive eruption of the Hunga Tonga-Hunga Haʻapai volcano in Tonga in the Pacific damaged several submarine cables. This is reported by New Zealand media referencing to various operators of submarine cables in the South Pacific. It is feared that the island state of Tonga will remain largely cut off from the Internet for at least several weeks.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stuff.co.nz/world/south-pacific/127517682/cable-repair-ship-to-set-sail-from-png-to-restore-communications-to-tonga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;never-before-seen-cross-platform-rat-discovered&quot;&gt;Never-before-seen cross-platform RAT discovered&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have uncovered a remote access trojan (RAT) written from scratch for systems running Windows, macOS, or Linux that remained undetected by virtually all malware scanning engines. The discovery is significant for several reasons and is described in detail in the following article.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/01/backdoor-for-windows-macos-and-linux-went-undetected-until-now/1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;10-real-world-stories-of-compromised-cicd-pipelines&quot;&gt;10 real-world stories of compromised CI/CD pipelines&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build pipelines are highly-privileged targets with a substantial attack surface. Not only does this article by nccgroup detail the exploits and deficiencies, but lays out clear actionable steps to remedy them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.nccgroup.com/2022/01/13/10-real-world-stories-of-how-weve-compromised-ci-cd-pipelines/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;patchmanagement---a-comprehensive-series&quot;&gt;Patchmanagement - a comprehensive series&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unpatched known vulnerabilities remain one of the most common attack vectors in today’s cyberattacks. The insightful series of articles on darkreading covers the evolution of patchmanagement, the risk-based approach we are all used to today, and an outlook to the future development of keeping systems updated. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/the-evolution-of-patch-management-how-and-when-it-got-so-complicated&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-intelligence---free-and-open-source&quot;&gt;Threat intelligence - free and open-source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Sullivan has created a community-driven alerting system for high-impact vulnerabilities. We think this is an amazing alternative to commercial threat intelligence systems and worth supporting. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mattslifebytes.com/2022/01/04/bugalert-org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-purchased-a-machine-from-china-and-it-came-with-malware-preinstalled&quot;&gt;We purchased a machine from China and it came with malware preinstalled&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to end this roundup with a hilarious and informative story from the folks at rmcybernetics. They ordered a small Pick and Place machine from AliExpress and found malware preinstalled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmcybernetics.com/general/zhengbang-zb3245tss-pick-place-machine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-012022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-012022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>December 2021 Roundup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/inversegravity.png&quot; alt=&quot;logo&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;another-year-is-coming-to-an-end-and-we-start-a-new-format-here-on-inversegravity-kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month-we-wish-you-all-the-best-for-2022&quot;&gt;Another year is coming to an end and we start a new format here on inversegravity. Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month. We wish you all the best for 2022!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-cisos-practical-advice-on-log4j&quot;&gt;A CISO’s Practical Advice on log4j&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/lamont-orange-99540a/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lamont Orange&lt;/a&gt; gives some great advice on darkreading.com. He writes: “it’s easy to get weighed down in hype, marketing, and speculation and forget that there are important things we need to do, right now, to improve our posture, strengthen our team, and put us in a better position for the next Log4j.” Well-spoken, sir!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/log4j-a-ciso-s-practical-advice&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ms-teams-1-feature-4-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;MS Teams: 1 feature, 4 vulnerabilities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fabian Bräunlein and his team from &lt;a href=&quot;https://positive.security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Positive Security&lt;/a&gt; stumbled upon 4 vulnerabilities in Microsoft Team’s link preview feature. The vulnerabilities allow accessing internal Microsoft services, spoofing the link preview, and, for Android users, leaking their IP address and running a DoS attack.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://positive.security/blog/ms-teams-1-feature-4-vulns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cloud-security-breaches-and-vulnerabilities-2021-in-review&quot;&gt;Cloud Security Breaches and Vulnerabilities: 2021 in Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christophe Tafani-Dereeper has written a great summary of common cloud security incidents. We especially appreciate his insight into the prevention and detection of these common misconfigurations.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.christophetd.fr/cloud-security-breaches-and-vulnerabilities-2021-in-review/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ccc-rc3-nowhere-2021&quot;&gt;CCC rc3 Nowhere 2021&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chaos Communication Congress is the largest gathering of the hacker community in Europe. For the second time, the annual event was replaced by a virtual one due to COVID-19 restrictions. You can find the videos of the 2021 talks &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3-2021&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. All the German language presentations are translated and some are held in English. We hope for the CCC folks (and us) that everything will be back to normal in 2022. &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3-2021&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;streaming link&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-with-speckle-patterns-and-lasers&quot;&gt;Fun with speckle patterns (and lasers)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anfractuosity has an exciting project with lasers, a calculator, and a vice. He writes “The approach takes advantage of the fact that tiny surface deformations cause phase changes in reflected coherent light which alter the speckle pattern visible under laser illumination.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anfractuosity.com/projects/fun-with-speckle-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;that-toy-you-got-for-christmas-could-be-spying-on-you&quot;&gt;That Toy You Got for Christmas Could Be Spying on You&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Montalbano has written an interesting article about security flaws in the recently released Fisher-Price Chatter Bluetooth telephone. Keeping those kids protected! &lt;a href=&quot;https://threatpost.com/toy-christmas-spying/177288/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;make-your-pc-notify-your-phone-whenever-there-is-movement-around-it&quot;&gt;Make Your PC Notify Your Phone Whenever There is Movement Around it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great holiday project comes from c0d3x27. In the article, he/she describes how to use the camera of a computer with OpenCV to capture images and detect motion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.devgenius.io/make-your-pc-notify-your-phone-whenever-there-is-movement-around-it-c6c4ccd734b7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/roundup-122021/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/roundup-122021/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Scalability Problem Of Bitcoin</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;bitcoin-is-the-best-known-cryptocurrency-of-all-and-by-far-the-most-important-one-it-is-ahead-of-the-competition-in-market-capitalization-and-no-other-digital-currency-can-hold-a-candle-to-it-in-terms-of-transaction-volume-but-can-btc-become-the-global-currency-of-the-future&quot;&gt;Bitcoin is the best-known cryptocurrency of all and by far the most important one. It is ahead of the competition in market capitalization and no other digital currency can hold a candle to it in terms of transaction volume. But can BTC become the global currency of the future?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was committed to making electronic transactions viable for everyone. Without relying on the centralized control by financial institutes, but rather with a peer-to-peer consensus mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-hash-digital-signature/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hashed and digitally signed&lt;/a&gt; transactions and a public ledger based on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blockchain&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; made the design revolutionary. Satoshi Nakamoto, the mysterious inventor of BTC, had solved the double-spending problem of digital currencies and mined the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.bitcoin.it/wiki/Genesis_block&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;genesis block&lt;/a&gt; on the 3rd of January in 2009.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/crypto.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increasing popularity of bitcoin didn’t only result in a higher value for the digital asset but has also surfaced the inevitable problem: No system is built for endless scalability. To better understand the issue we have to get a bit technical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transactions-tx&quot;&gt;Transactions (TX)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important concepts in Bitcoin is transactions. These “transfer” value, in form of Bitcoins, from one wallet to another on the network. Transactions contain the number of Satoshis (the smallest Bitcoin unit), the wallet addresses of the sender and the receiver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TX is broadcasted to the network, awaiting verification, and is then added to the distributed ledger (blockchain) by a node. Transactions transfer the property rights on Bitcoins between people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;nodes&quot;&gt;Nodes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In his &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitcoin.org/bitcoin.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;whitepaper&lt;/a&gt;, Satoshi used the term node synonymously with a miner. Generally speaking, nodes verify transactions and then add them to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the verification of a TX, the node will double-check that each coin sent in a transaction also refers to a previously received coin. Nodes have to solve complex cryptographic computational tasks (mining) to create a new block before the verified TX can be added to the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;throughput-of-btc&quot;&gt;Throughput of BTC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current Bitcoin network creates one new block every 10 minutes. This block has a size limit of 1 megabyte and 4000 transactions. This results in the following limitations of the BTC system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;max. 7 transactions/sec&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;min. 10 minutes for a transaction confirmation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bitcoin network takes bandwidth limitations into account. In situations where there are more transactions than bandwidth, the mempool of nodes is acting as a buffer or waiting room for transactions. Here, the TX sits until being inserted in a newly created block.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;prioritization-of-transactions&quot;&gt;Prioritization of Transactions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In times of high congestion of the network, there are many more transactions than there is space in the blockchain. It is then the transaction fee that decides the priority (who will be served first).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The higher the fee, the more likely it is that the node chooses a transaction to be part of the next block in the chain. Transactions with low fees can end up not being written to the blockchain for days, weeks, or even months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a not preferred situation when you want to pay your goods. You either have to pay a high fee on top of the price of the good or the vendor will wait for your payment until your cappuccino is cold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;protocol-issues&quot;&gt;Protocol Issues&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin won’t be able to become a meaningful digital currency without technical changes to the protocol. The throughput is just too low for this purpose. Any medium-sized bank exceeds the limit of 24,000 transactions per hour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The increasing amount of fees necessary to guarantee a timely transaction is a result of the scalability issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;protocol-changes&quot;&gt;Protocol Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making changes to the protocol of bitcoin is the only way to improve the transaction speed of the network and build a more sustainable system. But changes have their challenges as we have seen in 2017 when an upgrade called &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SegWit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SegWit&lt;/a&gt; was introduced to the bitcoin network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The update increased the effective blocksize by a factor of 1.8 by redesigning the content in each block. This change was controversial and lead to the hard-fork &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bitcoin_Cash&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Bitcoin Cash&lt;/a&gt;. The community was stuck in a discussion on who controls the changes to the protocol. As a result of the debate, Bitcoin did not receive any major protocol upgrade since 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now in 2021, the network introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_bitcoin_forks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Taproot&lt;/a&gt; which is a soft-fork and features the new Pay-to-Taproot (P2TR) transaction type, which combines the concepts of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Schnorr_signature&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Schnorr signatures&lt;/a&gt; and Merklized Alternative Script Trees (MAST); it increases transaction privacy and requires significantly less storage for complex output conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recent updates to the BTC protocol have increased the transaction volume of the network. Nevertheless, Bitcoin is no longer focused on “Fast Money” or usability in commerce but rather has become a digital asset to store value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other cryptocurrencies have emerged and might become a way to pay your cappuccino.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/bitcoin-scale/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/bitcoin-scale/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Lifecycle Models</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;in-this-article-we-cover-the-lifecycle-models-used-by-project-management-to-direct-the-development-process&quot;&gt;In this article, we cover the lifecycle models used by project management to direct the development process.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Lifecycle Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Established engineering disciplines (such as electrical or mechanical) often state that software engineering is not an engineering discipline at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They contend that software engineering is a combination of chaotic processes that sometimes manages to create a workable solution. It might not be fair to compare age-old disciplines to those of an industry that’s only a few decades old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the adoption of formalized lifecycle management processes in software development can help to mature the application engineering discipline. Stakeholders often employ project management to implement those lifecycle models and keep development projects on target towards a refined product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wfh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development frameworks have several activities in common. The names are not necessarily consistent in each model, but the following core activities are essential to the sound development of a system:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptual-definition&quot;&gt;Conceptual Definition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This phase of development involves creating the basic concept statement for a system or application. In this very high-level contract, all interested stakeholders agree to the purpose of a project as well as the general requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all phases of the development process, the concept statement should be referred to in order to avoid getting lost in the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;functional-requirements&quot;&gt;Functional Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all stakeholders have agreed on the concept, it’s time to start the functional requirement phase. Specific functionalities are listed and how deliverables from the development phase meet these requirements. The three major characteristics of a functional requirement are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt; The data provided to a function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavior&lt;/strong&gt; The business logic describing what actions the system should take in response to the input&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt; The data provided from a function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s again very important that all stakeholders agree on the functional requirements document before progressing. The document is used as a checklist to ensure all functional requirements in the testing and evaluation stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-requirements&quot;&gt;Security Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations have to ensure that adequate security controls are designed into every system. It’s therefore essential to have the definition of such control specifications in the product development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the conceptual definition and the functional requirements, the security engineers can analyze the system from their perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threat modeling on public entry points and the trust boundaries is a great practice to surface the risks to the system. The product team can then mitigate those threats by implementing appropriate measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All too often, systems are designed without security planning, and then developers try to retrofit the system with security enhancements. These afterthought improvements do often not fully integrate with the system’s design and can leave gaping vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security requirements have to be revisited whenever a significant change is made to the design specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-review&quot;&gt;Design Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the functional and security specifications, the system designers can start doing their thing. The designers determine exactly how the various parts of the system will interoperate and how the system structure will be laid out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the formal design document is finished, a review meeting will usually be held where all stakeholders ensure that everyone is in agreement with the desired functionality and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-review&quot;&gt;Code Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the blessing of the stakeholders, the software developers can start writing code. Code reviews at various milestones throughout the coding process will ensure that flaws in the code or problems with the data flow are avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code reviews are an instrumental tool in ensuring that the code produced by development teams perform according to specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acceptance-testing&quot;&gt;Acceptance Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the developer wrote the final lines of code and declares the system as complete (is a system ever complete?), it’s time to begin the acceptance testing phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial testing should seek for obvious errors and as the testing progresses more detailed input is provided to simulate predefined scenarios. A copy of the test plan and the results has to be kept for future review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this phase is complete, the application can be deployed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maintenance-and-change-management&quot;&gt;Maintenance and Change Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the system being operational, a range of maintenance tasks is required to ensure stable operation in the face of real user traffic. At this point, the operations team will ensure the observability and reliability of the application and support the developers in optimizing the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in production, any changes to the code are handled by a formalized change management process to ensure availability, confidentiality, and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lifecycle-models-in-detail&quot;&gt;Lifecycle Models in Detail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following sections, we’ll take a look at several specific software development lifecycles. All these frameworks are meant to improve the resulting products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waterfall Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed in the 1970s this model seeks to view the development lifecycle as a series of sequential activities. Traditionally the framework has six stages of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;System Requirements &amp;amp; Software Requirements -&amp;gt; Analysis -&amp;gt; Design -&amp;gt; Code &amp;amp; Debug -&amp;gt; Testing -&amp;gt; Operations &amp;amp; Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern approach of the waterfall model also allows returning to previous phases to correct defects. This framework was one of the first comprehensive attempts to structure the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/de/1970_Royce_Managing_the_Development_of_Large_Software_Systems_Fig10.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Waterfall Summary&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spiral Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This alternative lifecycle model allows for multiple iterations of the waterfall process. Each loop of the spiral results in the development of a new system prototype. This metamodel provides a solution for the major criticism of the waterfall model - it allows developers to return to the planning stages as requirements change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ec/Spiral_model_%28Boehm%2C_1988%29.svg/1024px-Spiral_model_%28Boehm%2C_1988%29.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spiral Summary&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agile Software Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile software development has seen increasing adoption in the last years. The framework is not built on a rigid model but rather emphasizes certain principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individuals and interaction&lt;/strong&gt; over processes and tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working software&lt;/strong&gt; over comprehensive documentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; over contract negotiation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responding to change&lt;/strong&gt; over following a plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile software development was initially seen as best suitable for non-critical product development and excluded from use in domains such as medical devices, financial, nuclear systems, and avionics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there have been initiatives to adopt agile to match key concerns in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality Assurance&lt;/strong&gt; Systematic and inherent quality management underpinning a controlled professional process and reliability and correctness of product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety and security&lt;/strong&gt; Formal planning and risk management to mitigate safety risks for users and securely protecting users from unintentional and malicious misuse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceability&lt;/strong&gt; Documentation providing auditable evidence of regulatory compliance and facilitating traceability and investigation of problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management models in application development support the software industry to mature and close the gap with established engineering disciplines. It’s important to constantly verify the adequacy of a framework to prevent failure in meeting business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The involvement of security experts during the phases of the lifecycle will support the creation of a product that has security embedded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Basic Principles</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;in-the-first-part-of-this-series-we-have-been-taking-a-look-at-several-types-of-languages-and-the-resulting-security-implications&quot;&gt;In the first part of this series, we have been taking a look at several types of languages and the resulting security implications.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-time-we-focus-on-the-baseline-for-secure-development-we-will-cover-the-most-basic-principles-that-apply-independently-of-the-creation-of-a-more-specific-application&quot;&gt;This time, we focus on the baseline for secure development. We will cover the most basic principles that apply independently of the creation of a more specific application.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Lifecycle Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secure software is the result of a security-aware software development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a mountaineer&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;failure-management&quot;&gt;Failure Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications will fail at some point in time, no matter how cutting-edge and security-aware programmers, project managers, and product designers are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sense of how to handle failures is essential to stay in control of unpredictable situations for an application or system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two general practices when planning for failure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fail-open state&lt;/strong&gt; allows a system to continue operations when failure conditions occur. This approach should only be taken in limited circumstances. It might be appropriate on the lower-layers of multilayered security concepts. A good example is an electronic locking door that unlocks in case of failure to ensure the exit in the event of a natural disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fail-closed state&lt;/strong&gt; puts a system into a high level of security or even shuts down a failing system. This strategy should be the default where there are security concerns. An example is when a forgotten password results in the denied entry to an account and multiple wrong password entries result in the lock of the account.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authentication-and-session-management&quot;&gt;Authentication and Session Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many applications require that users authenticate before accessing sensitive information or modify the data in an application. One of the most basic security tasks developers are facing is to ensure that those users are properly authenticated, that they perform only authorized activities, and that their sessions are securely tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally more secure to use an existing and hardened authentication system than to try to develop a system for a specific application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, programmers should be encouraged to use established methods for session management. This includes the usage of encrypted channels and that identifiers used in sessions are long and randomly generated. Session tokens have to expire after a specific time and require reauthentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;input-validation&quot;&gt;Input Validation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many applications receive data from potentially untrusted sources. This includes user input on internet-facing web applications or API communication with suppliers, partners, or other applications in the backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers often expect these values to fall within certain parameters. For example, if the programmer asks the user to enter a telephone number, the program may expect to see a chain of integer values. If the user enters a value outside the range or character set, a poorly written program may crash or even allow the user to gain control of the underlying system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input validation verifies that the values match the programmer’s expectation before allowing further processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input escaping describes a check for unusual characters, such as quotation marks within a text field, which may indicate an attack. Escaping can be performed with a blacklisting or better whitelisting approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All input validation efforts should be performed on the server-side of a transaction and as early as possible in the processing of a request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;error-handling&quot;&gt;Error Handling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detailed error messages with in-depth information are crucial to debugging code and make it easier for developers to diagnose a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, those errors are exposing potentially sensitive information to attackers, including the address of internal servers, database schemas, and other data that may be useful in preparing an attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, developers have to disable detailed error messages on any publicly available application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logging&quot;&gt;Logging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While user-facing error messages may present a security threat, the information that those messages contain is quite useful. Not only to developers but also to security analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, applications should be sending detailed logging messages to a centralized log repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-pdf-archive/OWASP_SCP_Quick_Reference_Guide_v2.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;OWASP Secure Coding Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; suggest logging the following events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Input validation failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Authentication events, especially failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Access control failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apparent tampering events&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempts to connect with invalid or expired session tokens&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exceptions by systems and applications&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use of administrative privileges&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TLS connections failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cryptographic errors&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above topics are the most basic principles to guide stakeholders in creating secure software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next article, we’ll take a look at several specific activities of a development process and how security can be applied in each of these.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-baseline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-baseline/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Programming Languages</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;software-and-system-development-is-a-complex-and-demanding-activity-undertaken-by-people-with-different-skill-levels-and-varying-security-awareness&quot;&gt;Software and System development is a complex and demanding activity undertaken by people with different skill levels and varying security awareness.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-can-present-a-serious-risk-to-organizations---security-teams-must-understand-these-risks-balance-them-with-business-requirements-and-enforce-appropriate-mitigation-mechanisms&quot;&gt;This can present a serious risk to organizations - security teams must understand these risks, balance them with business requirements and enforce appropriate mitigation mechanisms.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Lifecycle Models&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An in-house development team supports unique objectives in many organizations, tailored software is a competitive advantage and can ultimately decide on the success of a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Careless or even malicious development on the other hand can introduce vulnerabilities and backdoors to such software and leave the organization open to exploitation by &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/threat-landscape/&quot;&gt;malicious actors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s, therefore, crucial to introduce controls and a structured process to the entire development process to protect against vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is the first in a series about security in software and system development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of an old control pannel&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-languages&quot;&gt;Programming Languages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Developers use programming languages to develop software. This chapter takes a look at the different types of languages and the security implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions that a computer processes are a long series of binary digits in a language known as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_code&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;machine code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a language of 0s and 1s and no human can understand anything but the simplest instructions without the assistance of specialized software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Assembler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a higher-level language to represent the machine code. It’s still a complex and obscure way of programming and requires specific knowledge about the hardware it will interact with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language#Current_usage&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;situations&lt;/a&gt; in which developers might choose to use assembly language, the preference is to use &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-level_programming_language&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;high-level languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, such as Java, Ruby, Python, R, and C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These languages are feature-rich and provide standards for common tasks, permit debugging, and maintain architectural agnosticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compiled-vs-interpreted&quot;&gt;Compiled vs. Interpreted&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using a &lt;em&gt;compiled language&lt;/em&gt; like C or Java, a tool known as a compiler converts the higher-level language into an executable file that is distributed and designed to be used on a specific operating system. It is not possible to directly view or modify the software instructions in such a compiled executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconstructing the source code from an executable with a decompiler is described with the term reverse engineering. This is useful for malware analysis or intelligence gathering, where access to the original source code is not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Languages like Python, R, and JavaScript are &lt;em&gt;interpreted languages&lt;/em&gt;. Developers distribute these programs by sharing the source code with all instructions. End-users use an interpreter to execute the source code on their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compiled and interpreted languages both have advantages and disadvantages from a security perspective. Compiled code is less likely to be manipulated by a third party, but security flaws or backdoors in the source code are harder to detect since the original instructions can’t be accessed by the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interpreted code on the other hand is very transparent because the end-user can read the code before executing it in an interpreter. The disadvantage is that everyone who touches the software can introduce malicious instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;object-oriented-programming&quot;&gt;Object-Oriented Programming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OOP is a standard based on the concept of “objects” and focuses on the interaction of such objects rather than on a series of steps as seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming&quot;&gt;functional programming&lt;/a&gt;. Many modern programming languages (such as Java, Python, etc.) are multi-paradigm and support OOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Object-Oriented programming is generally speaking more reliable and reduces the propagation of errors in a system. From a security perspective, OOP is a black-box abstraction because users don’t need to know the inner working of an object but rather the details and abilities of the interface to an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desired characteristic in OOP is the self-containment of an object or in other works the encapsulation. Below are some core concepts of object-oriented programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt; is commonly used in OOP to describe the input of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; this is the name for the instructions (or code) of an object. It specifies the actions in response to a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class&lt;/strong&gt; is a collection of methods and acts as a template for the creation of objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegation&lt;/strong&gt; describes the forwarding of a request an object receives to another object. Objects delegate if they don’t have a method to handle certain requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polymorphism&lt;/strong&gt; is the characteristic of an object to respond differently to the same message because of changes in external parameters. This can be static polymorphism during compile time or dynamic polymorphism during runtime (JVM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cohesion&lt;/strong&gt; is the degree of focus of a method (or class). Low cohesion means an unfocused variety of actions and low specialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coupling&lt;/strong&gt; describes the level of interaction between objects. High coupling of objects means low independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High cohesion and loose coupling is an important principle in software engineering. It results in strong focus and high independence and is desired for objects (and development teams).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor - 25 Years of Anonymization</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;anonymization-technology-is-at-the-core-of-self-defense-in-the-digital-world-in-this-article-we-take-a-look-at-the-great-anonymization-project&quot;&gt;Anonymization technology is at the core of self-defense in the digital world. In this article, we take a look at the great anonymization project.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle of Tor was developed in the mid-1990s by the United States to protect U.S. intelligence communications online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25 years after its inception as a state-funded project, Tor is the most important adversary of state surveillance and the leader in distributed anonymization technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;the logo of the Tor project&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allows users to protect their privacy and circumvent censorship but also allows selling or buying illicit drugs. The Tor Project has been full of contradictions since the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;onion-routing&quot;&gt;Onion Routing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor aims to conceal its users’ identities and their online activity from surveillance and traffic analysis by separating identification and routing. It is an implementation of a technique called onion routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an onion network, messages are encapsulated in layers of encryption, analogous to several peels of an onion. The encrypted data is transmitted through a randomly selected series of network nodes called onion routers, each of which “peels” away a single layer, uncovering the data’s next destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the final layer is decrypted, the message arrives at its destination. The user remains anonymous to the service provider because each intermediary knows only the location of the immediately preceding and following nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deep-and-dark-onion&quot;&gt;Deep and Dark Onion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tor software can be used in two ways: either as an anonymization service to accesses the regular internet or to access services in the virtual top-level domain “.onion”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many misunderstandings and generalizations regarding the “.onion”. Let’s look at some subsets of the web and the naming first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor_users.png&quot; alt=&quot;tor users per day&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;SurfaceWeb&lt;/strong&gt; is everything publicly available and accessible through search engines. This is where we find news sites, blogs like inversegravity, or shopping sites. The &lt;strong&gt;DeepWeb&lt;/strong&gt; describes the parts of the internet that are hidden behind a login and therefore not publicly accessible. Examples are online banking sites or content behind a paywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;DarkWeb&lt;/strong&gt; describes services that require specific software to access them. Tor is such software and the TLD “.onion” is a major player in the so-called DarkWeb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostnames under “.onion” are not actual DNS names, and the TLD is not registered in the root of the regular internet domain services. The purpose of the network is to hide both the identity of the service provider and the person accessing the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mutual anonymity and the emergence of anonymous digital currencies created the possibility to buy and sell services and goods in complete anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-worth-the-costs&quot;&gt;Benefits worth the costs?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not without reason that stories about the Darkweb are popular in the media. There is everything that makes a good story, anonymous criminals engaging in illegal activities including sex and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor_users_country.png&quot; alt=&quot;tor users per country&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outrage from politicians and calls for regulation accompany many of these stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2020/11/24/2011893117/tab-article-info&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;research article&lt;/a&gt; has shown that only ~6.7% of all Tor users are actually accessing Onion services for potentially illegal purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority uses it as a privacy-enhancing tool to circumvent censorship or stay anonymous on the regular internet. Ultimately Tor is by its very nature dual-use and the question is if the benefits outweigh the costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 25th anniversary of Tor, there is no clear answer. The internet is a very young technology and we are grappling with the implications to personal freedom, censorship, human nature, social evil, and government policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy birthday Tor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/tor-onion-anniversary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/tor-onion-anniversary/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
