<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>personal blog</description>
    <link>https://damaex17.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://damaex17.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 07:56:17 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 07:56:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jaeger-LeCoultre Grande Reverso Tribute to 1931 Ref. 2788570</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;heritage&quot;&gt;Heritage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of the Reverso starts in the year of 1931. The legends tells that Cesar de Trey, a Swiss businessman and watch aficionado, was attending a polo match of British army officers while travelling India. One of the players had just broken the glass of his watch. De Trey discussed the idea of a watch model robust enough to survive the hard knocks of a polo game with Jacques-David LeCoultre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LeCoultre tasked the firm Jaeger S.A with the creation of a reversible case. The case can be swivelled in its carrier to protect the watch glass. The Reverso was born. The name is inspired by the Latin “I turn around”. The well proportioned rectangular shape with the three grooves at the top and bottom of case is considered a classic of Art Deco design. To this day the Reverso is still produced and is a statement of Jaeger-LeCoultre’s relationship with polo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reverso-tribute-to-1931&quot;&gt;Reverso Tribute to 1931&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Jaeger-LeCoultre celebrated the 80th anniversary of the Reverso and during SIHH 2011, JCL commorated this anniversary with the Grande Reverso Ultra Thin Tribute to 1931 model. This authentic model comes with the original dial and hands and is presented in an extremely flat and large case, measuring 46.8mm x 27.4mm wide and 7.3 mm thick. There is no brand name on the dial, just the word “Reverso” which is of course well known and closely related to JLC itself. The lugs are thick and downward sloped to make the watch comfortable on the wrist. On the black dial is a rectangular minute with aged hour markers and a double mark at the 12 o’clock position. The watch uses aged baton hands to tell the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the watch ticks the manually wound Jaeger-LeCoultre Calibre 822 (21 jewels) which beats at 21.600 vibrations per hour. It has a power reserve of 45 hours. Most rectangular and tonneau shaped cases in the industry contain a round movement. But this is a JLC watch, the movement is shaped to the dimensions of the watch itself (true case movement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the modern watch to the original, it’s clear that Jaeger-LeCoultre was successful in developing a honorable tribute to the 1931 icon. The watch captures the essential elements of the original Reverso. Perhaps the best example of staying true to it’s origin is the the solid caseback. Imposing a sapphire caseback would have damaged the credibility of the watch as a re-edition of an iconic sports watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid movement, vintage looks, outstanding quality and a significance to history makes this watch a modern classic.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>jlc</category>
        
        <category>jaeger-lecoultre</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stealth-rolex&quot;&gt;The stealth rolex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally created to honor the adventures of the Mt. Everest conquerors Tenzing Norgay and Sir Edmund Hillary, the 1953 Rolex Explorer was the first of a long line of Rolex tool watches designed to go anywhere.
The Explorer was developed from the original 1930s-50s Oyster Perpetual “bubblebacks,” the first water-resistant and self-winding wristwatches to achieve technical and commercial success. Norgay and Hillary immortalized the Explorer and the continuous incremental refinement by Rolex led to the Explorer 114270 produced from 2002 until 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the general public may not understand the depth of the Rolex tool heritage, even the average “man on the street” understands that the brand stands as a synonym for quality. And in this Explorer, Rolex delivers. The Geneva watchmaker ranks among the exclusive club of true manufactures that produce virtually every part of their watches by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 36mm stainless steel case itself is a testament to Rolex’s eye for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all begins with the steel itself; Rolex makes it in its own company foundry. The steel employed on the Explorer is of the 904L type, not the lesser resilient 316L employed by the majority of watchmakers. 904L is more expensive to produce and harder to work with. The payoff is the watch’s lifetime and scratch resistance. The steel preserves the polished and brushed finishes and the corrosion resistance is higher than with conventional stainless steel. 
Rolex is building watches that last a life time (or two, or three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the case is the Rolex Cal. 3130 chronometer grade movement which beats at 28.800 vibrations per hour. The movement is COSC certified in a two-week evaluation process. This certification tests the movement in different positions and temperatures. Another testament to the quality requirements of Rolex watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than any other aspect of the watch, the dial is what makes the Explorer unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three Arabic numerals at 3, 6, and 9 o’clock combine with a triangular index at 12 and intermediate stick indexes, no date, smooth bezel. Signature “Mercedes” cathedral hands are, like all indexes, rendered in white gold for enduring resistance to corrosion and tarnish. The rich black lacquer dial provides a radiant gloss backdrop to the white gold elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270 is the last of the 36mm Explorers. It represents a time where Rolex built tools rather than jewellery and investment pieces. But make no mistake… the Explorer can be worn with a suite to a evening in the opera. If there is one lesson learned from history, it’s that a Rolex Explorer is your companion anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I bought the 114270 in 2017 and since then it has become my daily companion. It might just be the perfect Rolex. The Explorer is durable, accurate and doesn’t get in your way. The design is timeless and blends in perfectly. People don’t associate the brand Rolex with this inconspicuous watch. This Ref. 114270 is for me the ultimate Oyster Professional model in the history of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>rolex</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Expanse</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;setting&quot;&gt;Setting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Expanse is a science fiction novel by James S. A. Corey, the pseudonym of Daniel Abraham and Ty Franck. It is set in the near future in which humanity has colonized most of the solar system, but does not have faster than light travel. The fractions of the expanse fight for resources and power and the tensions are rising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The series of books provide a realistic outlook into the future of humanity. Gravity is for example not created by a mysterious device as in Star Wars or Star Trek but by acceleration. Spaceships brake by accelerating into the other direction (flip and burn). And there are no pew-pew lasers but bullets, torpedos and railguns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;earth---the-united-nations&quot;&gt;Earth - The United Nations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_un.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the mid and late 21st century, humanity’s national governments are confronted with overpopulation and the resulting difficult state of Earth’s ecosystem. They unite under a global government. The United Nations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The UN begins to establish colonies on other planets and moons in the Sol system, the most notable of these being Luna and Mars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 22nd century the colonial government of Mars demands independence. The United Nations refuses and war is imminent. 
Mars offers to share the revolutionary Epstein drive technology in exchange for independence. The UN agrees in order to avoid Mars having a tactical advantage in spaceship technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now free to expand into the outer Sol system, the UN establishes colonies on several Jovian moons, as well as Titan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mars---martian-congressional-republic&quot;&gt;Mars - Martian Congressional Republic&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_mcrn2.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally a colony of Earth and in the beginning highly depending on the blue planet, three generations after the first settlers landed, Mars became largely self-sustaining. Mars also becomes a leader in environmental technology and research as well as the design and manufacture of advanced spaceships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the colonists on Mars during this period want to secede from Earth, comparing themselves to the American colonies of the 17th century. If not for Solomon Epstein and his accidental invention of what would come to be called the Epstein Drive, war between the planet and its colony may have been inevitable. Mars had a major technological advantage over Earth. The new ships could go further and faster than anything that had been built before, opening up the rest of the solar system for exploration, settlement and resource gathering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Martian government offered the UN access to the Epstein Drive in exchange for granting Mars its sovereignty. The UN accepted and the Martian Congressional Republic was formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-belt---outer-planets-alliance-opa&quot;&gt;The Belt - Outer Planets Alliance (OPA)&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/expanse_opa.jpg&quot; align=&quot;left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Asteroid Belt, often referred to as just The Belt, is a circumstellar disc located in the region of the Sol system between the orbits of the planets Mars and Jupiter. The Belt was colonized by humans in the 21st century. Humans born in the Belt, called Belters, are thinner and taller than humans from the inner planets due to the lower gravity environment. The population of the Belt is estimated at around 50 million according to inner planets censuses. The Outer Planets Alliance (OPA) is a loosely affiliated group uniting under a common ideology that started as a labor union or advocacy group, fighting for the interests of inhabitants of the Belt. Often in direct conflict with the inner planets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;story&quot;&gt;Story&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ice hauling ship Canterbury is traveling back from Saturn to Ceres when it encounters a distress signal. Five members (Jim Holden (Earth), Naomi Nagata (Belt), Alex Kamal (Mars), Amos Burton (Earth) and Shed Garvey(Earth)) of the crew are sent in a shuttle to investigate and discover a transport vessel called Scopuli. There is no trace of the crew but they discover the beacon transmitting the distress signal. They leave the Scopuli with the beacon and head back to the Canterbury in fear of a pirate trap. Before they arrive, a unknown stealth warship decloaks and destroys the Canterbury with a nuclear torpedo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the advanced technology of the warship and the discovery that the beacon from the Scopuli is of Martian origin, the survivors suspect the MCRN of being behind the attack. With the shuttle damaged by the debris field of the explosion the crew decides to send out a message to the entire system implicating Mars in the destruction of the Canterbury.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MCRN battleship Donnager, flagship of the Mars Jupiter fleet responds and the shuttle is ordered to rendezvous with the Donnager. Aboard the battleship the captain denies any knowledge of the MCRN involvment in the attack on the Canterbury. More unknown stealth ships arrive to the site and open fire on the Donnager. Despite the fact that the Donnager is one of the most advanced warships in the Solar System, it is overwhelmed by the mysterious enemy ships and eventually boarded. During the battle a railgun round penetrates the hull and kills Garvey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Realizing that the Canterbury survivors are the target of the attack, a team of MCRN Marines is ordered to evacuate them from the battleship. All Marian Marines are killed in the process and the four surviving crew members are able to escape aboard the light frigate Tachi just before the Donnager is scuttled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other arc of the book tells the story of detective Joe Miller (Belt) who is contracted to locate Julie Mao. The daughter of the wealthy Earth magnate Jules-Pierre Mao. Later the story lines merge and Miller joins the crew of the Tachi (later renamed to Rocinante). They eventually discover the body of Julie Mao on the moon Eros. The corpse is covered in a strange organic material. This material is later unveiled of being of alien origin and named the Protomolecule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Protomolecule is able to transform biomass in order to create a structure of unknown purpose. This is the beginning of the story surrounding the crew of the frigate Rocinante. The members of the crew with their diverse backgrounds and the addition of the Protomolecule to the already critical mixture of fractions, makes The Expanse on of the best Sci-Fi stories of the early 21st century.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/the-expanse/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/the-expanse/</guid>
        
        <category>expanse</category>
        
        <category>scifi</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
