<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>technology, security, privacy and gear</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 09:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 09:05:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Lifecycle Models</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;in-this-article-we-cover-the-lifecycle-models-used-by-project-management-to-direct-the-development-process&quot;&gt;In this article, we cover the lifecycle models used by project management to direct the development process.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Established engineering disciplines (such as electrical or mechanical), often complain that software engineering is not an engineering discipline at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They contend that software engineering is a simple combination of chaotic processes that sometimes manage to create a workable solution. It might not be fair to compare age-old disciplines to those of an industry that’s only a few decades old.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The adoption of formalized lifecycle management processes in software development can help to mature the application engineering discipline. Nowadays, stakeholders often employ project management to keep development projects on target towards the goal of a refined product. The project management is organized around lifecycle models or frameworks to direct this process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/wfh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development frameworks have several activities in common. The names are not necessarily shared but the following core activities are essential to the sound development of secure systems:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conceptual-definition&quot;&gt;Conceptual Definition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This phase of development involves creating the basic concept statement for a system or application. In this very high-level contract that all interested stakeholders agree to the purpose of a project as well as the general requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During all phases of the development process, the concept statement should be referred to in order to avoid getting lost in the details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;functional-requirements&quot;&gt;Functional Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once all stakeholders have agreed on the concept, it’s time to start the functional requirement phase. Specific functionalities are listed and how deliverables from the development phase meet these requirements. The three major characteristics of a functional requirement are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Input&lt;/strong&gt; The data provided to a function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Behavior&lt;/strong&gt; The business logic describing what actions the system should take in response to the input&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Output&lt;/strong&gt; The data provided from a function&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s again very important that all stakeholders agree on the functional requirements document before progressing. The document is used as a checklist to ensure all functional requirements in the testing and evaluation stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;security-requirements&quot;&gt;Security Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations with security in mind ensure that adequate security controls are designed into every system. It’s therefore useful to have the definition of such control specifications in the product development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the conceptual definition and the functional requirements, the security engineers can analyze the system from a security perspectives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Threat modeling on the public entry points and the trust boundaries is a great practice to surface the risks to the system. The product team can then mitigate those threats by implementing appropriate measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All too often, systems are designed without security planning, and then developers try to retrofit the system with security enhancements. These afterthought improvements do often not fully integrate with the system’s design and can leave gaping vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security requirements have to be revisited whenever a significant change is made to the design specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design-review&quot;&gt;Design Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the functional and security specifications, the system designers can start doing their thing. The designers determine exactly how the various parts of the system will interoperate and how the system structure will be laid out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the formal design document is finished, a review meeting will usually be held where all stakeholders ensure that everyone is in agrees with the desired functionality and security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code-review&quot;&gt;Code Review&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the blessing of the stakeholders, the software developers can start writing code. Code reviews at various milestones throughout the coding process will ensure that flaws in the code or problems with the data flow are avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code reviews are an instrumental tool in ensuring that the code produced by development teams perform according to specifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;acceptance-testing&quot;&gt;Acceptance Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the developer puts in the final pieces of code and declares the system as complete (is a system ever complete?), it’s time to begin the acceptance testing phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Initial testing should seek for obvious errors and as the testing progresses more detailed input is provided to simulate predefined scenarios. A copy of the test plan and the results has to be kept for future review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this phase is complete, the application can be deployed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maintenance-and-change-management&quot;&gt;Maintenance and Change Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the system being operational, a range of maintenance tasks is required to ensure stable operation in the face of real user traffic. At this point, the operations team will ensure the observability and reliability of the application and support the developers in opcltimizing the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once in production, any changes to the code are handled by a formalized change management process to ensure availability, confidentiality, and integrity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lifecycle-models-in-detail&quot;&gt;Lifecycle Models in Detail&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following sections, we’ll take a look at several specific software development lifecycles. All these frameworks are meant to improve the resulting products.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Waterfall Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developed in the 1970s this model seeks to view the development lifecycle as a series of sequential activities. Traditionally the framework has six stages of development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;System Requirements &amp;amp; Software Requirements -&amp;gt; Analysis -&amp;gt; Design -&amp;gt; Code &amp;amp; Debug -&amp;gt; Testing -&amp;gt; Operations &amp;amp; Maintenance&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The modern approach of the waterfall model also allows returning to previous phases to correct defects. This framework was one of the first comprehensive attempts to structure the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/de/1970_Royce_Managing_the_Development_of_Large_Software_Systems_Fig10.PNG&quot; alt=&quot;Waterfall Summary&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spiral Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This alternative lifecycle model allows for multiple iterations of the waterfall process. Each loop of the spiral results in the development of a new system prototype. This metamodel provides a solution for the major criticism of the waterfall model - it allows developers to return to the planning stages as requirements change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/ec/Spiral_model_%28Boehm%2C_1988%29.svg/1024px-Spiral_model_%28Boehm%2C_1988%29.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;Spiral Summary&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Agile Software Development&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile software development has seen increasing adoption in the last years. The framework is not built on a rigid model but rather emphasizes certain principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Individuals and interaction&lt;/strong&gt; over processes and tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Working software&lt;/strong&gt; over comprehensive documentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Customer collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; over contract negotiation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responding to change&lt;/strong&gt; over following a plan&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Agile software development was initially seen as best suitable for non-critical product development and excluded from use in domains such as medical devices, financial, nuclear systems, and avionics, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there have been initiatives to adopt agile to match key concerns in the following areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality Assurance&lt;/strong&gt; Systematic and inherent quality management underpinning a controlled professional process and reliability and correctness of product&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety and security&lt;/strong&gt; Formal planning and risk management to mitigate safety risks for users and securely protecting users from unintentional and malicious misuse&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Traceability&lt;/strong&gt; Documentation providing auditable evidence of regulatory compliance and facilitating traceability and investigation of problems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Management models in application development support the software industry to mature and close the gap with established engineering disciplines. It’s important to constantly verify the adequacy of a framework to prevent failure in meeting business requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The involvement of security experts into the development work at certain phases of the lifecycle will support the creation of a product that has security embedded.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-lifecycle/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Basic Principles</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;in-the-first-part-of-this-series-we-have-been-taking-a-look-at-several-types-of-languages-and-the-resulting-security-implications&quot;&gt;In the first part of this series, we have been taking a look at several types of languages and the resulting security implications.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-time-we-focus-on-the-baseline-for-secure-development-we-will-cover-the-most-basic-principles-that-apply-independently-of-the-creation-of-a-more-specific-application&quot;&gt;This time, we focus on the baseline for secure development. We will cover the most basic principles that apply independently of the creation of a more specific application.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secure software is the result of a security-aware software development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/risk_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a mountaineer&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;failure-management&quot;&gt;Failure Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applications will fail at some point in time, no matter how cutting-edge and security-aware programmers, project managers, and product designers are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A sense of how to handle failures is essential to stay in control of unpredictable situations for an application or system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two general practices when planning for failure:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fail-open state&lt;/strong&gt; allows a system to continue operations when failure conditions occur. This approach should only be taken in limited circumstances. It might be appropriate on the lower-layers of multilayered security concepts. A good example is an electronic locking door that unlocks in case of failure to ensure the exit in the event of a natural disaster.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;fail-closed state&lt;/strong&gt; puts a system into a high level of security or even shuts down a failing system. This strategy should be the default where there are security concerns. An example is when a forgotten password results in the denied entry to an account and multiple wrong password entries result in the lock of the account.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;authentication-and-session-management&quot;&gt;Authentication and Session Management&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many applications require that users authenticate before accessing sensitive information or modify the data in an application. One of the most basic security tasks developers are facing is to ensure that those users are properly authenticated, that they perform only authorized activities, and that their sessions are securely tracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is generally more secure to use an existing and hardened authentication system than to try to develop a system for a specific application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, programmers should be encouraged to use established methods for session management. This includes the usage of encrypted channels and that identifiers used in sessions are long and randomly generated. Session tokens have to expire after a specific time and require reauthentication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;input-validation&quot;&gt;Input Validation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many applications receive data from potentially untrusted sources. This includes user input on internet-facing web applications or API communication with suppliers, partners, or other applications in the backend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers often expect these values to fall within certain parameters. For example, if the programmer asks the user to enter a telephone number, the program may expect to see a chain of integer values. If the user enters a value outside the range or character set, a poorly written program may crash or even allow the user to gain control of the underlying system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input validation verifies that the values match the programmer’s expectation before allowing further processing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Input escaping describes a check for unusual characters, such as quotation marks within a text field, which may indicate an attack. Escaping can be performed with a blacklisting or better whitelisting approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All input validation efforts should be performed on the server-side of a transaction and as early as possible in the processing of a request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;error-handling&quot;&gt;Error Handling&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Detailed error messages with in-depth information are crucial to debugging code and make it easier for developers to diagnose a problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, those errors are exposing potentially sensitive information to attackers, including the address of internal servers, database schemas, and other data that may be useful in preparing an attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, developers have to disable detailed error messages on any publicly available application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;logging&quot;&gt;Logging&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While user-facing error messages may present a security threat, the information that those messages contain is quite useful. Not only to developers but also to security analysts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, applications should be sending detailed logging messages to a centralized log repository.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://owasp.org/www-pdf-archive/OWASP_SCP_Quick_Reference_Guide_v2.pdf&quot;&gt;OWASP Secure Coding Guidelines&lt;/a&gt; suggest logging the following events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Input validation failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Authentication events, especially failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Access control failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Apparent tampering events&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attempts to connect with invalid or expired session tokens&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Exceptions by systems and applications&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use of administrative privileges&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;TLS connections failures&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cryptographic errors&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above topics are the most basic principles to guide stakeholders in creating secure software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next article, we’ll take a look at several specific activities of a development process and how security can be applied in each of these.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-baseline/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development-baseline/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Secure Development - Programming Languages</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;software-and-system-development-is-a-complex-and-demanding-activity-undertaken-by-people-with-different-skill-levels-and-varying-security-awareness&quot;&gt;Software and System development is a complex and demanding activity undertaken by people with different skill levels and varying security awareness.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-can-present-a-serious-risk-to-organizations---security-teams-must-understand-these-risks-balance-them-with-business-requirements-and-enforce-appropriate-mitigation-mechanisms&quot;&gt;This can present a serious risk to organizations - security teams must understand these risks, balance them with business requirements and enforce appropriate mitigation mechanisms.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Programming Languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2021/secure-development-baseline/&quot;&gt;Secure Development - Basic Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An in-house development team supports unique objectives in many organizations, tailored software is a competitive advantage and can ultimately decide on the success of a business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Careless or even malicious development on the other hand can introduce vulnerabilities and backdoors to such software and leave the organization open to exploitation by &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/threat-landscape/&quot;&gt;malicious actors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s, therefore, crucial to introduce controls and a structured process to the entire development process to protect against vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is the first in a series about security in software and system development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of an old control pannel&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;programming-languages&quot;&gt;Programming Languages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Software Developers use programming languages to develop software. This chapter takes a look at the different types of languages and the security implications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions that a computer processes are a long series of binary digits in a language known as &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_code&quot;&gt;machine code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;. It’s a language of 0s and 1s and no human can understand anything but the simplest instructions without the assistance of specialized software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language&quot;&gt;Assembler&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a higher-level language to represent the machine code. It’s still a complex and obscure way of programming and requires specific knowledge about the hardware it will interact with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there are some &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Assembly_language#Current_usage&quot;&gt;situations&lt;/a&gt; in which developers might choose to use assembly language, the preference is to use &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/High-level_programming_language&quot;&gt;high-level languages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, such as Java, Ruby, Python, R, and C++.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These languages are feature-rich and provide standards for common tasks, permit debugging, and maintain architectural agnosticism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;compiled-vs-interpreted&quot;&gt;Compiled vs. Interpreted&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When using a &lt;em&gt;compiled language&lt;/em&gt; like C or Java, a tool known as a compiler converts the higher-level language into an executable file that is distributed and designed to be used on a specific operating system. It is not possible to directly view or modify the software instructions in such a compiled executable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconstructing the source code from an executable with a decompiler is described with the term reverse engineering. This is useful for malware analysis or intelligence gathering, where access to the original source code is not available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Languages like Python, R, and JavaScript are &lt;em&gt;interpreted languages&lt;/em&gt;. Developers distribute these programs by sharing the source code with all instructions. End-users use an interpreter to execute the source code on their system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compiled and interpreted languages both have advantages and disadvantages from a security perspective. Compiled code is less likely to be manipulated by a third party, but security flaws or backdoors in the source code are harder to detect since the original instructions can’t be accessed by the end-user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interpreted code on the other hand is very transparent because the end-user can read the code before executing it in an interpreter. The disadvantage is that everyone who touches the software can introduce malicious instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;object-oriented-programming&quot;&gt;Object-Oriented Programming&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OOP is a standard based on the concept of “objects” and focuses on the interaction of such objects rather than on a series of steps as seen in &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Functional_programming&quot;&gt;functional programming&lt;/a&gt;. Many modern programming languages (such as Java, Python, etc.) are multi-paradigm and support OOP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Object-Oriented programming is generally speaking more reliable and reduces the propagation of errors in a system. From a security perspective, OOP is a black-box abstraction because users don’t need to know the inner working of an object but rather the details and abilities of the interface to an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The desired characteristic in OOP is the self-containment of an object or in other works the encapsulation. Below are some core concepts of object-oriented programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Message&lt;/strong&gt; is commonly used in OOP to describe the input of an object.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Method&lt;/strong&gt; this is the name for the instructions (or code) of an object. It specifies the actions in response to a message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class&lt;/strong&gt; is a collection of methods and acts as a template for the creation of objects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delegation&lt;/strong&gt; describes the forwarding of a request an object receives to another object. Objects delegate if they don’t have a method to handle certain requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Polymorphism&lt;/strong&gt; is the characteristic of an object to respond differently to the same message because of changes in external parameters. This can be static polymorphism during compile time or dynamic polymorphism during runtime (JVM).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cohesion&lt;/strong&gt; is the degree of focus of a method (or class). Low cohesion means an unfocused variety of actions and low specialization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coupling&lt;/strong&gt; describes the level of interaction between objects. High coupling of objects means low independence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High cohesion and loose coupling is an important principle in software engineering. It results in strong focus and high independence and is desired for objects (and development teams).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/secure-development/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>devsec</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Tor - 25 Years of Anonymization</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;anonymization-technology-is-at-the-core-of-self-defense-in-the-digital-world-in-this-article-we-take-a-look-at-the-great-anonymization-project&quot;&gt;Anonymization technology is at the core of self-defense in the digital world. In this article, we take a look at the great anonymization project.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The underlying principle of Tor was developed in the mid-1990s by the United States to protect U.S. intelligence communications online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25 years after its inception as a state-funded project, Tor is the most important adversary of state surveillance and the leader in distributed anonymization technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;the logo of the Tor project&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It allows users to protect their privacy and circumvent censorship but also allows selling or buying illicit drugs. The Tor Project has been full of contradictions since the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;onion-routing&quot;&gt;Onion Routing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tor aims to conceal its users’ identities and their online activity from surveillance and traffic analysis by separating identification and routing. It is an implementation of a technique called onion routing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an onion network, messages are encapsulated in layers of encryption, analogous to several peels of an onion. The encrypted data is transmitted through a randomly selected series of network nodes called onion routers, each of which “peels” away a single layer, uncovering the data’s next destination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the final layer is decrypted, the message arrives at its destination. The user remains anonymous to the service provider because each intermediary knows only the location of the immediately preceding and following nodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;deep-and-dark-onion&quot;&gt;Deep and Dark Onion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tor software can be used in two ways: either as an anonymization service to accesses the regular internet or to access services in the virtual top-level domain “.onion”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many misunderstandings and generalizations regarding the “.onion”. Let’s look at some subsets of the web and the naming first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor_users.png&quot; alt=&quot;tor users per day&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;SurfaceWeb&lt;/strong&gt; is everything publicly available and accessible through search engines. This is where we find news sites, blogs like inversegravity, or shopping sites. The &lt;strong&gt;DeepWeb&lt;/strong&gt; describes the parts of the internet that are hidden behind a login and therefore not publicly accessible. Examples are online banking sites or content behind a paywall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term &lt;strong&gt;DarkWeb&lt;/strong&gt; describes services that require specific software to access them. Tor is such software and the TLD “.onion” is a major player in the so-called DarkWeb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hostnames under “.onion” are not actual DNS names, and the TLD is not registered in the root of the regular internet domain services. The purpose of the network is to hide both the identity of the service provider and the person accessing the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mutual anonymity and the emergence of anonymous digital currencies created the possibility to buy and sell services and goods in complete anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;benefits-worth-the-costs&quot;&gt;Benefits worth the costs?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not without reason that stories about the Darkweb are popular in the media. There is everything that makes a good story, anonymous criminals engaging in illegal activities including sex and drugs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tor_users_country.png&quot; alt=&quot;tor users per country&quot; style=&quot;float: left; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outrage from politicians and calls for regulation accompany many of these stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though, a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2020/11/24/2011893117/tab-article-info&quot;&gt;research article&lt;/a&gt; has shown that only ~6.7% of all Tor users are actually accessing Onion services for potentially illegal purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The vast majority uses it as a privacy-enhancing tool to circumvent censorship or stay anonymous on the regular internet. Ultimately Tor is by its very nature dual-use and the question is if the benefits outweigh the costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 25th anniversary of Tor, there is no clear answer. The internet is a very young technology and we are grappling with the implications to personal freedom, censorship, human nature, social evil, and government policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy birthday Tor!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/tor-onion-anniversary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/tor-onion-anniversary/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>CVE - Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures System</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-common-vulnerabilities-and-exposures-system-provides-a-reference-method-for-publicly-known-information-security-vulnerabilities-and-exposures&quot;&gt;The Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures system provides a reference-method for publicly known information-security vulnerabilities and exposures.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system is maintained by the nonprofit organization &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_MITRE_Corporation&quot;&gt;MITRE&lt;/a&gt;, funded by &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/National_Cyber_Security_Division&quot;&gt;NCSD&lt;/a&gt;, and was officially launched in 1999. In this article, we explain what it is all about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before the CVE system, communication about security vulnerabilities was difficult. “The security issue in Windows” could refer to hundreds of individual bugs. Trying to narrow down the exact bug by adding the subsystem was not sufficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/digisign.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a city&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To improve communication and avoid misunderstandings a vendor-neutral and uniform system for the management of vulnerabilities was required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1999, this consistent numbering system for vulnerabilities was introduced: the CVE (Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures) system, which has since become the industry standard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vulnerabilities-and-exposures&quot;&gt;Vulnerabilities and Exposures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities are weaknesses in a software or system that can be used to gain unauthorized access or perform unauthorized actions on a computer system. Exposures are caused by vulnerabilities and misconfiguration and can be actively exploited in cyber attacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;naming-scheme&quot;&gt;Naming Scheme&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IDs in the CVE system follow the format &lt;strong&gt;CVE-YYYY-NNNNN&lt;/strong&gt;. The pattern is familiar to everyone who has dealt with vulnerabilities and describe the specific issue with a software. Software updates refer to the CVE number to explain what is addressed in the update.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial &lt;strong&gt;CVE&lt;/strong&gt; is always followed by the year &lt;strong&gt;YYYY&lt;/strong&gt; in which the number was assigned to the vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last part of the ID was limited to four digits when the system was introduced but the 9999 unique IDs per year were insufficient. Since 2014 there is no limit and the length is defined by the demand of the respective calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;allocation&quot;&gt;Allocation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uniform syntax of the CVE system was the first step to find a common ground for vulnerabilities. But to prevent IDs from being created and assigned in an uncontrolled manner, only certain organizations and persons, so-called CVE Numbering Authorities (CNAs), have the authority to assign an ID to a specific vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are three types of CNA entities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The MITRE itself functions as the primary CNA&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various vendors assign CVE numbers for their products (e.g. Microsoft, Oracle, Google, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Third-party coordinators such as CERT may assign CVE numbers for products not covered by other CNAs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Independent researchers who discover a vulnerability and want to report it will find the relevant contact point in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cve/request_id.html&quot;&gt;CNA overview&lt;/a&gt; on MITRE’s website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cvebanner.png&quot; alt=&quot;a server rack&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once a new vulnerability is reported, the CNA will reserve an ID and enter it into the MITRE maintained &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cve/&quot;&gt;CVE list&lt;/a&gt;. Once the vulnerability is confirmed and a detailed description is provided, the CVE is officially assigned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-information-and-scoring&quot;&gt;Additional Information and Scoring&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The National Vulnerability Database (&lt;a href=&quot;https://nvd.nist.gov/&quot;&gt;NVD&lt;/a&gt;) is an independent project launched in 2005 by the National Institute of Standards and Technology (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nist.gov/&quot;&gt;NIST&lt;/a&gt;) and uses MITRE’s CVE list, but adds additional information to the rather brief descriptions, such as security risks or available updates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the infamous &lt;a href=&quot;https://cve.mitre.org/cgi-bin/cvename.cgi?name=CVE-2014-0160&quot;&gt;Heartbleed CVE&lt;/a&gt; for example, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://nvd.nist.gov/vuln/detail/CVE-2014-0160&quot;&gt;NVD description&lt;/a&gt; provides information on how to fix it and a list of affected software versions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most important data the NVD provides is the so-called Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS). Based on the path of attack and the complexity of the exploit, a scoring level from “Low” to “Critical” is assigned to each CVE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVE is free to use and publicly available to anyone interested in correlating data between different vulnerability or security tools, repositories, and services. Attackers only need to find a single vulnerability to gain unauthorized access to a system. Therefore, organizations need to protect themselves by swiftly addressing known vulnerabilities and exposures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CVE system provides the necessary infrastructure to match any software inventory against known weaknesses and the ID serves as the consistent identification characteristic for such vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/cve-system/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/cve-system/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Zero Trust Security</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;zero-trust-is-a-model-that-is-based-on-the-idea-that-nothing-should-be-trusted-without-verification&quot;&gt;Zero Trust is a model that is based on the idea that nothing should be trusted without verification.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In traditional networks, security is based on perimeter defenses, a concept that can be best described with the metaphor of a medieval castle. It is hard to gain access from the outside, but everyone inside is trusted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/computer.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;old computer&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this perimeter defense approach is that once attackers have overcome the initial boundary of the network, they can freely act on all systems. This is intensified by today’s world of complex interconnected networks, cloud-based environments, working from home (WFH), and bring your own device (BYOD).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, the concept of barricading your castle with a single (fire)wall alone is an inadequate security model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enter zero trust; a new way of thinking, driven by the assumption that threats are everywhere. Let’s take a look at some of the guiding principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;microperimeter&quot;&gt;Microperimeter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The zero trust model extends identity controls to all processes, systems, and people regardless of their group membership or by the location in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Networks are therefore segmented into small zones and a person or program can’t access the resources in such a zone without prior authorization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resulting micro perimeter allows granular authentication that is tailored to an individual user/process/system combination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;principle-of-least-privilege&quot;&gt;Principle Of Least Privilege&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authentication within a zero-trust philosophy is based on the Principle of Least Privilege (PoLP). Meaningi, people and processes receive only the amount of access rights they need to carry out their duty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The framework of policies and technologies for enabling this appropriate access to resources is called Identity and Access Management (IAM) and in conjunction with PoLP, it minimizes the exposure of services to malicious login attempts with valid accounts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;multi-factor-authentication&quot;&gt;Multi-Factor Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In zero-trust security, knowledge of a password is not enough evidence for authentication. Multi-factor authentication is the recommended method in which a user is granted access only after successfully presenting two or more pieces of evidence to an authentication mechanism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/universal-2nd-factor/&quot;&gt;2FA&lt;/a&gt; as a subset of multi-factor authentication confirms identities by combining two different factors: something they know and something they have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utilizing MFA dramatically improves the security of the authentication process and prevents attacks with well-known or easy to brute-force passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tcp_02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a server rack&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;encryption-everywhere&quot;&gt;Encryption Everywhere&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data in public networks is by default encrypted in today’s world. Zero-trust additionally requires the consistent usage of transport layer security (TLS) in internal networks and the cryptographic protection of data in storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Encryption algorithms and secure key sizes have to be assessed regular whether they remain sate of the art. But this effort is quickly compensated by the liberating knowledge that an attacker will have a harder time to move inside the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;observability&quot;&gt;Observability&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Behavioral analytics, efficient incident response, and forensics are important building blocks to support a zero-trust environment. The ability to develop such a cohesive overview requires observability for all services and events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usually, logging and metrics come to mind first, but observability involves other processes like monitoring, tracing, analytics, and alerting. Good observability enables the organization to compile meaningful information from all systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zero Trust can only function within the framework of an overall security concept. It is not an off-the-shelf product or tool but rather a vendor-neutral principle for approaching security in an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It requires a cultural shift and flexible solutions to change the paradigms by which organizations secure their resources.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/zero-trust/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/zero-trust/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Progressive Web Application</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-are-living-in-the-age-of-the-smartphone-and-native-apps-are-often-built-in-a-programming-language-specific-to-the-mobile-operating-system-a-progressive-web-application-pwa-on-the-other-hand-is-delivered-through-the-web-and-based-on-common-web-technologies&quot;&gt;We are living in the age of the smartphone and native apps are often built in a programming language specific to the mobile operating system. A Progressive Web Application (PWA), on the other hand, is delivered through the web and based on common web technologies.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;PWA is intended to work on any platform and with any browser. The functionality includes working offline, push notifications, and even hardware access thus enabling user experiences similar to native applications on desktop and mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no need for developers or users to install a PWA via proprietary distribution systems like Google Play or Apple App Store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why-and-how-to-pwa&quot;&gt;Why And How To PWA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Native apps on Apple iOS use Swift and Android apps are based on Java. Organizations that want to support both platforms are quickly confronted with having to build two expensive teams. Keeping both applications aligned is a neverending endeavor. There is no easy way to build one application and publish it to all the stores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/iphone.png&quot; alt=&quot;screenshot iOS screen&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width:45%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Progressive web applications on the other hand are a great way to have just that, a single app to rule them all and users might not even know that they are using a web-based app instead of a native one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.dev/what-are-pwas/&quot;&gt;web.dev&lt;/a&gt; blog, the characteristics of a PWA are: capable, reliable, installable, and safe. The experience requires speed, network independence, and security from the web-based application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The building blocks are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwabuilder.com/serviceworker&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;service worker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; that handles network requests and the caching of assets to support an offline experience with the web application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://letsencrypt.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transport encryption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for the network connection via TLS/HTTPS for all components of the website, which should be a standard today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwabuilder.com/generate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;manifest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; file in JSON format to control the app appearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any website can become a PWA by satisfying the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pwabuilder.com&quot;&gt;PWA checklist&lt;/a&gt;. Once all the requirements are met, the app can be downloaded to devices and mimics a native application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not having to maintain separate native applications makes PWA especially interesting for small organizations. Major web frameworks like Angular, React or Jekyll enable developers to easily create a PWA, and all major mobile and non-mobile operating systems support the technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inversegravity is now available as a PWA. We support web-applications and like to evade any iOS vs. Android rivalry.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/progressive-web-app/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/progressive-web-app/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Data Anonymization</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;companies-use-data-science-and-analytics-to-improve-their-services-and-products-it-makes-a-lot-of-sense-to-measure-what-users-like-and-only-build-what-people-want-to-use&quot;&gt;Companies use data science and analytics to improve their services and products. It makes a lot of sense to measure what users like and only build what people want to use.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the collected data can be very sensitive and undermine the rights of users if a data loss occurs. Data privacy laws, therefore, &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/art-32-gdpr/&quot;&gt;dictate&lt;/a&gt; appropriate technical and organizational measures to ensure a level of security appropriate to the risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many organizations can’t afford highly restricted environments and are left with either limited data analytics or the risk of a data leak and resulting &lt;a href=&quot;https://gdpr-info.eu/issues/fines-penalties/&quot;&gt;penalties&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to protect data subjects and combine business needs with user rights is anonymization and in this article, we’ll gonna take a look at it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;history&quot;&gt;History&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the oldest methods of anonymization is the removal (suppression) of direct personal identifiers from the data such as names or phone numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/anon_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;anonymization by removing the name&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width:60%; margin: 0px 15px 0px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until 1997, the resulting dataset was considered more or less anonymized and hospitals in the US, for example, released such data to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latanya_Sweeney&quot;&gt;Latanya Sweeney&lt;/a&gt; entered the stage and conducted a re-identification experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataprivacylab.org/projects/identifiability/paper1.pdf&quot;&gt;successfully&lt;/a&gt; re-identified individuals by combining public medical records with other accessible records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The “linkage attack” was born, where adversaries collect information from multiple data sources and then combine that data to re-create personally identifiable information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/anon_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;linkage attack&quot; style=&quot;float: left; width:45%; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latanya Sweeney conducted more research on re-identification and was met with publication challenges. The fear was that she is publicly exposing a serious issue with no known solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, Forbes named Sweeney one of the most influential women in technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of removing names and direct identifiers is considered pseudonymization if at all. Working with this data requires organizations to control the risk of a data breach since disclosure would affect the users rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymization&quot;&gt;Anonymization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, organizations have to provide evidence for anonymization since it exempts the business from strict data-privacy requirements. It has to be clearly documented why data subjects can no longer be identified directly or indirectly from the dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most successful anonymization efforts involve the application of multiple techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;k-anonymity-protection-model&quot;&gt;K-Anonymity protection model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of k-anonymity was first introduced by Latanya Sweeney and Pierangela Samarati in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://dataprivacylab.org/dataprivacy/projects/kanonymity/kanonymity.pdf&quot;&gt;paper&lt;/a&gt; published in 1998.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Data is said to have the k-anonymity property if the information for each person contained in the release cannot be distinguished from at least k - 1 individuals whose information also appear in the release.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more personal attributes in a dataset, the harder it is to accomplish k-anonymity over all the attributes combined. Let’s consider this table of fictitious patient records.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/anon_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;fictitious nonanonymized patient records&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two common methods to support k-anonymity are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suppression&lt;/strong&gt; means that the values of attributes are replaced by a wildcard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Generalization&lt;/strong&gt; describes the replacement of individual values of attributes to a broader category.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following table we accomplished a 2-anonymity with respect to ‘Age’ and “Gender’ since for any combination of these attributes there are always at least 2 rows with the same value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/anon_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;patient records with 2-anonymity&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The attributes ‘Age’ and ‘Gender’ are quasi-identifiers and when combined, can support re-identification to yield personally-identifying information. Each tuple of quasi-identifiers has to occur at least in k records of a dataset to accomplish k-anonymity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;K-anonymity is a promising approach for group-based anonymization given its simplicity, it is however susceptible to attacks. When background knowledge is available an attacker can use it to re-identify people. In the above example, background knowledge about the disease can support an attack on the anonymity of individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the existence of such attacks where sensitive attributes may be inferred from k-anonymity data, the following methods have been created to further k-anonymity by additionally maintaining the diversity and closeness of sensitive fields.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The l-diversity Principle&lt;/strong&gt; An equivalence class is said to have l-diversity if there are at least l “well-represented” values for the sensitive attribute. A table is said to have l-diversity if every equivalence class of the table has l-diversity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The t-closeness Principle&lt;/strong&gt; An equivalence class is said to have t-closeness if the distance between the distribution of a sensitive attribute in this class and the distribution of the attribute in the whole table is no more than a threshold t. A table is said to have t-closeness if all equivalence classes have t-closeness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;differential-privacy&quot;&gt;Differential Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This technique was developed by cryptographers and draws much of its language from cryptography. Simply put differential privacy introduces two methods to balance data usefulness and privacy protection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, an algorithm injects random noise into a data set to protect the privacy of an individual. The noise is small enough to enable analysts and researchers to provide useful insights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secondly, the amount of information revealed is calculated and deducted from a so-called privacy-loss budget. The reference book for differential privacy is “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.de/Algorithmic-Foundations-Differential-Theoretical-Computer/dp/1601988184/ref=sr_1_1?dchild=1&amp;amp;keywords=Algorithmic+Foundations+of+Differential+Privacy%22&amp;amp;qid=1596537123&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot;&gt;The Algorithmic Foundations of Differential Privacy&lt;/a&gt;” by Aaron Roth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple has released a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.apple.com/privacy/docs/Differential_Privacy_Overview.pdf&quot;&gt;whitepaper&lt;/a&gt; describing &lt;em&gt;local differential privacy&lt;/em&gt;. The interesting twist here is that the noise is added on the users’ smartphone even before the data is sent to the Apple backend servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting approach we have been discussing in the posting &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/privacy-client-shift/&quot;&gt;System Architecture - Shift To The Client&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The challenge of privacy-preserving data analysis has a long history. As data about individuals is more detailed than ever, the need for a robust approach to data anonymization is no longer optional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The clever matching of different data collections and resulting de-anonymization threatens any approach. Organizations have to innovate and underline how they handle the obtained user data responsibly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/data-anonymization/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/data-anonymization/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        <category>privacy</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Network Vulnerability Scanner</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;networks-are-the-enabler-of-organizations-in-the-digital-age-the-dynamic-nature-of-on-premises-and-cloud-network-environments-requires-continuous-vulnerability-management-to-defend-against-the-ever-evolving-threat-landscape&quot;&gt;Networks are the enabler of organizations in the digital age. The dynamic nature of on-premises and cloud network environments requires continuous vulnerability management to defend against the ever evolving threat landscape.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we’ll look at network scanning which is the process to identify and classify weaknesses in the network. It is a prerequisite for the successful mitigation of known vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/radar.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;picture of a radar screen&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-a-vulnerability-scanner&quot;&gt;What is a vulnerability scanner?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A vulnerability scanner is an application that detects the hosts in a network and attempts to identify the services that are exposed by those systems. This is often considered the reconnaissance phase of a scan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It then tries to catalog the software version of detected services and checks them against databases of vulnerabilities to identify security weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some scanners will also attempt to exploit services by using default or well-known credentials and or test for other &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/owasp-top-10/&quot;&gt;common security risks&lt;/a&gt;. This step is the vulnerability verification phase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All network hosts and their vulnerabilities are stored in an inventory and once the scan is finished a report is created which can be used to improve the security posture of the organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a large number of commercial and open-source scanners available. Each comes with individual strengths and weaknesses and some companies run multiple scanners to protect their network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;external-and-internal&quot;&gt;External and internal&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A network scan for vulnerabilities can be performed from inside a network or from outside the protected perimeters. Both approaches aim to identify flaws that an attack can exploit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scan from external will document the services and potential vulnerabilities that are accessible directly from the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the common occurrence of insecure cloud-based configurations, the external scans are especially important to gain confidence in the security posture of the setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internal scans, on the other hand, aim to identify weaknesses inside the network and support a defense in depth security approach. These scans protect against threat actors or hackers that have already gained access to the local networki and try to exploit more systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tsunami---a-open-source-network-security-scanner&quot;&gt;Tsunami - a open-source network security scanner&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google has released a general-purpose network security scanner for detecting vulnerabilities. The project is called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner/blob/master/docs/index.md&quot;&gt;Tsunami&lt;/a&gt; and is maintained by the open-source community on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/tsunami.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Tsunami by hokusai 19th century&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It uses &lt;a href=&quot;https://nmap.org/&quot;&gt;nmap&lt;/a&gt; for the reconnaissance phase and tests for known passwords with &lt;a href=&quot;https://nmap.org/ncrack/&quot;&gt;ncrack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner-plugins&quot;&gt;plugins&lt;/a&gt; for the exploitation of vulnerabilities are rather limited but this is expected to change in the coming months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tsunami is a great way to get started with scanning networks for vulnerabilities. The project encourages collaboration and anyone can support it by adding &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/google/tsunami-security-scanner/blob/master/docs/howto.md#create_plugins&quot;&gt;detectors&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;other-network-security-measures&quot;&gt;Other network security measures&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scanning for known vulnerabilities is sometimes confused with other security measures. It is worthwhile to understand the different procedures and their purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;penetration-test&quot;&gt;Penetration Test&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It depends on the scope but in general a penetration test is a simulated cyberattack on computer systems, processes, and employees to evaluate the overall security posture of an organization. The tools and techniques used in such a pentest are the same a hacker would use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penetration tests can surface complex security weaknesses that require coordinated human activities, rather than the execution of automated code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;application-security-test&quot;&gt;Application Security Test&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A specialized vulnerability test for applications that include the analysis of the source code. Application security testing is effective in detecting known security issues with &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/software-supply-chain-security/&quot;&gt;software-components&lt;/a&gt; or hardcoded passwords.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is static security testing (SAST) which aims in testing code before compilation and dynamic security testing (DAST) which examines the application during run-time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;threat-detection&quot;&gt;Threat Detection&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of this activity is the detection of malicious activities in the network. It includes the search for compromised systems, discovering the exfiltration of data, and the unmasking of malicious user behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tools of the trade are a sophisticated &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Security_information_and_event_management&quot;&gt;SIEM&lt;/a&gt; system, the monitoring of indicators and adaptive scanning for changes in the network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Misconfigurations and security vulnerabilities are actively exploited by attackers. Knowledge about the weaknesses in a network is the first step in a successful mitigation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerability scanning is therefore an important activity to improve the security of an organization’s network.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/vulnerability-scanner/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/vulnerability-scanner/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Security Awareness - Security Culture</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;many-organizations-incorrectly-assume-that-a-team-of-security-experts-can-protect-the-other-99-of-the-companys-workforce&quot;&gt;Many organizations incorrectly assume that a team of security experts can protect the other 99% of the company’s workforce.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-dangerous-mindset-persists-in-many-technical-product-and-development-teams-too-and-members-take-it-for-granted-that-the-security-team-will-keep-them-out-of-trouble&quot;&gt;This dangerous mindset persists in many technical product and development teams too, and members take it for granted that the security team will keep them out of trouble.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in reality, it’s the daily informed decision making of all employees that makes the security posture of an enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Awareness as a concept aims at employees knowing about procedures, rules, and touchpoints with the security experts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security culture, however, goes beyond that and emphasizes a healthy mix of knowledge and follow-through by all members of an organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture of a hackers hiding&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we want to take a look at some examples of how to increase awareness and, more specifically, create an impactful cybersecurity culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;leadership---top-down-approach&quot;&gt;Leadership - Top-Down Approach&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Significant shifts in an organization start at the highest level; the support of the executive team is, therefore, essential in building a security culture. The top management has to communicate cybersecurity as an organization-wide priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regular reporting regarding the security situation of the organization and clear communication about the benefits of initiatives will help to build trust between the security team and management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Middle managers work directly with employees and are therefore naturally an essential driver of security culture. By properly explaining requirements to their team and leading by example, team leads will get the security mindset transported to all departments. Getting middle management on board with security has a significant effect on cultural change. They are the multipliers of the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’ve seen a lot of incidents where the management says that cybersecurity is important, but then they turn around and ask for exceptions—and that is the death knell of any cybersecurity program.”
    —Rob Clyde&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An “we are in this together” security mentality is achieved by embedding a vision and mission with leaders. This gives all employees direction on what they need to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;training-and-awareness&quot;&gt;Training and Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security training is labor-intensive but a key effort for growing and maintaining security culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Educating the work-force requires different approaches depending on the specific needs of the target group. For example, it makes sense to run all newcomers through a basic security program with information on common social engineering attacks like phishing or malware, introducing them to secure behavior expectations, and how to report an incident.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More tailored training for development teams can be, for example, introducing them to the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/threat-landscape/&quot;&gt;Threat Landscape&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/owasp-top-10/&quot;&gt;OWASP Top 10 Application Security Risks&lt;/a&gt;, or maybe refresh some &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/crypto-history-basics/&quot;&gt;crypto&lt;/a&gt; knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Departments, like Human Ressources, on the other hand, require awareness of the importance of &lt;a href=&quot;/2019/personnel-security/&quot;&gt;Personnel Security&lt;/a&gt; and how they can help with keeping the workplace safe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge transfer can take place in workshops, via videos or, maybe by introducing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.csoonline.com/article/3444488/equifax-data-breach-faq-what-happened-who-was-affected-what-was-the-impact.html&quot;&gt;famous data-leak case&lt;/a&gt; to a broader group in the organization and how it could have prevented by aligning with the policy framework. Showing that threats are close is an excellent way to encourage employees to follow security policies and best practices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security teams should also consider collecting feedback after a training to ensure the continuous improvement of the education program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture with data privacy message &quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;secure-development-lifecycle&quot;&gt;Secure Development Lifecycle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Secure from the start to the end and repeat. SDL is elemental to a sustainable security culture since it enables security to be integrated from the early stages of the development processes, and not as an afterthought at the very end of the delivery pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running a product through SDL will build trustworthy solutions that have fewer security vulnerabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The origin of most industry SDL implementations is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/securityengineering/sdl/practices&quot;&gt;Microsoft program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SDL is sustainable security culture in action and answers how to embed security culture in development and product teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;rewards&quot;&gt;Rewards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Celebrate success and recognize the people that do the right thing for security. Positive reinforcement is an excellent practice to support the effort to build a community of security-aware employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adding security-related goals to performance reviews will make reasonable security practices mandatory to employees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A positive message to the entire organization is sent by giving employees with good risk awareness more freedom when making decisions. Distributing the responsibility for security is a significant goal of security culture and therefore has to be embedded in the program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/culture_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;artistic picture with data privacy message &quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;automation&quot;&gt;Automation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations can support employees by adding security automation to software development and daily processes. This will not only make the employee’s job more comfortable but can also significantly improve the security posture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examples of good automation are security scanners, static code analysis, or automatically generated governance documents. Providing security plugins for the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_development_environment&quot;&gt;IDE&lt;/a&gt; of developers shifts the feedback to the left, and takes the frustration out of a later deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security culture is an integral part of a corporate culture that encourages people to make decisions in alignment with the organization’s best interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a long-term and never-ending endeavor to break down silo thinking and create a sense of companywide ownership for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employees have to be seen as assets in this approach; they are the first line of defense.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2020/security-culture/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2020/security-culture/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
