<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>personal blog</description>
    <link>https://damaex17.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://damaex17.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:57:02 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 11:57:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Jaeger-LeCoultre Grande Reverso Tribute to 1931 Ref. 2788570</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;modern-vintage&quot;&gt;modern vintage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The history of the reverso starts in the year of 1931. The legends tells that Cesar de Trey, a Swiss businessman and watch aficionado, was attending a polo match of British army officers while travelling India. One of the players had just broken the glass of his watch. De Trey discussed the idea of a watch model robust enough to survive the hard knocks of a polo game with Jacques-David LeCoultre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LeCoultre tasked the firm Jaeger S.A with the creation of a reversible case. The case can be swivelled in its carrier to protect the watch glass. The Reverso was born. The name is inspired by the Latin “I turn around”. The well proportioned rectangular shape with the three grooves at the top and bottom of case is considered a classic of Art Deco design. To this day the Reverso is still produced and is a statement of Jaeger-LeCoultre’s relationship with polo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;reverso-tribute-to-1931&quot;&gt;Reverso Tribute to 1931&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2011, Jaeger-LeCoultre celebrated the 80th anniversary of the Reverso and during SIHH 2011, JCL commorated this anniversary with the Grande Reverso Ultra Thin Tribute to 1931 model. This authentic model comes with the original dial and hands and is presented in an extremely flat and large case, measuring 46.8mm x 27.4mm wide and 7.3 mm thick. There is no brand name on the dial, just the word “Reverso” which is of course well known and closely related to JLC itself. The lugs are thick and downward sloped to make the watch comfortable on the wrist. On the black dial is a rectangular minute with aged hour markers and a double mark at the 12 o’clock position. The watch uses aged baton hands to tell the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the watch ticks the manualy wound Jaeger-LeCoultre Calibre 822 (21 jewels) which beats at 21.600 vibrations per hour. It has a power reserve of 45 hours. Most rectangular and tonneau shaped cases in the industry contain a round movement. But this is a JLC watch, the movement is shaped to the dimensions of the watch itself (true case movement).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/reverso_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the modern watch to the original, it’s clear that Jaeger-LeCoultre was successful in developing a honorable tribute to the 1931 icon. The watch captures the essential elements of the original Reverso. Perhaps the best example of staying true to it’s origin is the the solid caseback. Imposing a sapphire caseback would have damaged the credibility of the watch as a re-edition of an iconic sports watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solid movement, vintage looks, outstanding quality and a significance to history makes this watch a modern classic.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/jlc-reverso-tribute-1931/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>jlc</category>
        
        <category>jaeger-lecoultre</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stealth-rolex&quot;&gt;the stealth rolex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally created to honor the adventures of the Mt. Everest conquerors Tenzing Norgay and Sir Edmund Hillary, the 1953 Rolex Explorer was the first of a long line of Rolex tool watches designed to go anywhere.
The Explorer was developed from the original 1930s-50s Oyster Perpetual “bubblebacks,” the first water-resistant and self-winding wristwatches to achieve technical and commercial success. Norgay and Hillary immortalized the Explorer and the continuous incremental refinement by Rolex led to the Explorer 114270 produced from 2002 until 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the general public may not understand the depth of the Rolex tool heritage, even the averrage “man on the street” understands that the brand stands as a synonym for quality. And in this Explorer, Rolex delivers. The Geneva watchmaker ranks among the exclusive club of true manufactures that produce virtually every part of their watches by themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 36mm stainless steel case itself is a testament to Rolex’s eye for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It all begins with the steel itself; Rolex makes it in its own company foundry. The steel employed on the Explorer is of the 904L type, not the lesser resilient 316L employed by the majority of watchmakers. 904L is more expensive to produce and harder to work with. The payoff is the watch’s lifetime and scratch resistance. The steel preserves the poished and brused finishes and the corrosion resistance is higher than with conventional stainless steel. 
Rolex is building watches that last a life time (or two, or three).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inside the case is the Rolex Cal. 3130 chronometer grade movement which beats at 28.800 vibrations per hour. The movement is COSC certified in a two-week evaluation process. This certification tests the movement in different positions and temperatures. Another testament to the quality requirements of Rolex watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/114270_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than any other aspect of the watch, the dial is what makes the Explorer unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three Arabic numerals at 3, 6, and 9 o’clock combine with a triangular index at 12 and intermediate stick indexes, no date, smooth bezel. Signature “Mercedes” cathedral hands are, like all indexes, rendered in white gold for enduring resistance to corrosion and tarnish. The rich black lacquer dial provides a radiant gloss backdrop to the white gold elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270 is the last of the 36mm Explorers. It represents a time where Rolex built tools rather than jewellery and investment pieces. But make no mistake… the Explorer can be worn with a suite. If there is one leason learned from history, it’s that a Rolex Explorer is your companion anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</guid>
        
        <category>watch</category>
        
        <category>rolex</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
