<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>cyber security and technology blog</description>
    <link>https://inversegravity.net/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://inversegravity.net/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 16:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 16:55:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>CVSS - The Vulnerability Scoring System</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-common-vulnerability-scoring-system-cvss-is-an-industry-standard-for-assessing-the-severity-of-potential-or-actual-vulnerabilities-in-computer-systems-we-explain-how-the-system-works-and-its-limitations&quot;&gt;The Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) is an industry-standard for assessing the severity of potential or actual vulnerabilities in computer systems. We explain how the system works and its limitations.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A scoring system is mainly concerned with assessing the threat posed by a security vulnerability. In some cases, this is easy, but the facts are not always clear and the question is how can the severity of a vulnerability be quantified systematically?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;vulnerability-risk-analysis&quot;&gt;Vulnerability Risk Analysis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities are usually assessed using the method of risk analysis. In this process, the probability of exploits occurring and the possible damage they may cause are estimated. Assessments can, however, always be interpreted in different ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In vulnerability scoring systems, predefined factors are used to help quantify the degree and probability of damage as objectively as possible. The Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) describes vulnerability characteristics and determines the severity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/identity/cvss_4clr.jpg&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; alt=&quot;The CVSS metrics are divided into three groups&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;CVSS logo&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cvss-metrics&quot;&gt;CVSS Metrics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With CVSS, vulnerabilities are assessed based on so-called metrics. There are predefined options for each category and these are used to calculate a severity level from 0.0 to 10.0, with 10.0 corresponding to the highest possible severity level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on these numerical values, qualitative categories are then assigned (None, Low, Medium, High, and Critical), which are also familiar from vulnerability reports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The metrics are divided into three groups: Base Metrics, Temporal Metrics, and Environmental Metrics. Base metrics describe the essential technical and unchanging characteristics of a vulnerability. From these, a so-called “base score” can be calculated, which represents the technical severity of a vulnerability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be readjusted later and adapted to changes over time (temporal metrics) or the environment of the affected system (environmental metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/v3-1/media/MetricGroups.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The CVSS metrics are divided into three groups&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The CVSS metrics are divided into three groups&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For vulnerabilities, a CVE ID is usually assigned as a unique vulnerability identifier in the format CVE-YYYY-NNNN. We have a separate detailed article on the &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/cve-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVE System&lt;/a&gt; if you want to delve deeper into the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CVSS assigns a severity level to vulnerabilities and CVE assigns a unique identifier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;base-score&quot;&gt;Base Score&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic metrics are used to calculate the probability of an attack (exploitability metrics) and the consequences of exploitation (impact metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prerequisites include, among others, if an attack can be carried out via the Internet or whether physical access to a system is required (attack vector).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is also assessed if an attack can be carried out unauthenticated or if an attacker must have a valid user account with certain privileges (privileges required).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most critical determinant of the consequences of a successful attack is whether data can be extracted from the affected system, changed on the system, or if its availability can be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it is determined to what extent the protection goals of confidentiality, integrity, and availability (&lt;a href=&quot;/2019/cia-triad/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CIA&lt;/a&gt;) are compromised by successful exploitation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To calculate the base score, the metrics are offset against each other. Most CVSS assessments on the Internet use this score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;adjustments&quot;&gt;Adjustments&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The base score can later be adapted to temporal changes (Temporal Metrics) or adjusted to the respective environment of the affected system (Environmental Metrics).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, temporal changes occur when there is no longer just a possible description of an abstract vulnerability, but a fully functional exploit appears in the wild (exploit code maturity).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The criticality can also decrease if a workaround or an official manufacturer fix is available for the vulnerability (remediation level).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Environmental metrics allow the score to be adapted to the specific IT environment within an organization. Depending on the importance of a system, the base score is upgraded or downgraded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/v3-1/media/EquationsDiagram.svg&quot; alt=&quot;CVSS Metrics and Equations&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;CVSS Metrics and Equations&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;severity&quot;&gt;Severity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Base Score, Temporal Score, and Environmental Score are added up to a total score in the end. For each individual score as well as for the total score, a numerical value is obtained.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These values are categorized in severity levels from “None” to “Critical”. This qualitative assignment is optional and primarily intended to support companies in prioritization when doing vulnerability management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An overview of the CVSS vector structure is provided by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/calculator/3.1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CVSS Calculator&lt;/a&gt;. Metrics can easily be calculated via a web interface and scores and vectors are automatically calculated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-bias&quot;&gt;Assessment Bias&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vulnerabilities should be assessed as unbiased as possible. The interests of the person doing the assessment are likely to play a role. Manufacturers argue that they have a better basis of information and sometimes talk down vulnerabilities to avoid bad press. Researchers might benefit from a high rating of a finding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, discussions within the security community usually have a correcting effect on such bias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version 4.0 of CVSS is already being actively &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1qmmk9TQulW9d1cuipu_ziXDX0pUswbZ1WSQyynHbvKU/edit&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;discussed&lt;/a&gt;. The Temporale Metrics are to be improved and the introduction of supplemental metrics like “Mitigation Effort” or “Provider-Specific Urgency” is discussed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After almost two decades CVSS has become an indispensable part of vulnerability management and helps organizations to prioritize incidents with software and components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All metrics, options, and formulas of CVSS are described in detail in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/specification-document&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;specifications&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.first.org/cvss/user-guide&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;user guide&lt;/a&gt; provides additional information on the usage of CVSS.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cvss/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cvss/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OWASP Software Assurance Maturity Model</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;security-is-a-major-concern-for-all-software-products-introducing-security-activities-into-the-development-process-can-be-a-challenging-task-to-be-successful-close-integration-with-existing-processes-is-essential-to-embed-the-new-tasks-seamlessly-into-the-tried-and-tested-processes&quot;&gt;Security is a major concern for all software products. Introducing security activities into the development process can be a challenging task. To be successful, close integration with existing processes is essential to embed the new tasks seamlessly into the tried and tested processes.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Open Web Application Security Project (OWASP) has developed a useful framework for this purpose in the form of the Software Assurance Maturity Model &lt;a href=&quot;https://owaspsamm.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;SAMM&lt;/a&gt;. It enables companies not only to measure the maturity of their software development processes in terms of security but also to iteratively improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://owaspsamm.org//img/pages/SAMM_v2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The v2 SAMM&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The v2 SAMM&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;maturity-model&quot;&gt;Maturity Model&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The current version of the model (v2) is based on a set of 15 security practices grouped into five core areas of business functions. Governance, design, implementation, verification, and operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on a detailed catalog of questions, companies can determine their maturity level not only per individual activity but also aggregated to the respective areas and the entire development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the evaluation of the actual situation, an evaluation of the maturity development over time can be presented, which enables the visualization of the project progress and a comparison with the targeted milestones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The maturity model is agnostic in terms of techniques and development methodology, but a certain affinity to agile development methods cannot be denied.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;Initial maturity graph for a startup&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Initial maturity graph for a startup&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;governance&quot;&gt;Governance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The governance chapter aims at key performance indicators (KPIs) which enables teams to see if they have achieved the targeted progress and where intervention is required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, it covers the policy and compliance of projects and the suppliers of third-party components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well-trained and motivated employees are a key factor for a successful security program. These security champions are not only characterized by their interest and knowledge in the security topic but are also communicative and actively contribute to a positively reinforced security culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The security activities in the design phase involve defining security requirements, creating a security architecture, and performing threat modeling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal is to find out what threats are affecting the application being developed and whether they are being handled appropriately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Balanced medium maturity&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Balanced medium maturity&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;implementation&quot;&gt;Implementation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, SAMM focuses on the tools to integrate security into the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Questions address the secure handling of credentials to minimize human involvement during initial setup and the subsequent renewal of secrets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While being important throughout the development lifecycle, the management of defects is also handled in the implementation questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;verification&quot;&gt;Verification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Promoting software into the production environment without prior quality assurance has become unthinkable in many areas. This applies in particular to security checks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chapter recommends security checks that are based on concrete security requirements but generic tests still have their justification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SAMM places a emphasis on denial of service benchmarks, fuzzing, regression testing for fixed vulnerabilities, and test automation in the build and deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is important not to lose sight of the appropriateness of the tests for the specific application criticality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/owasp_4.png&quot; alt=&quot;olid maturity with a opportunity for improvement in the verification section&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Solid maturity with a opportunity for improvement in the verification section&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;operation&quot;&gt;Operation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With DevOps, the boundaries of the software development process are increasingly beginning to blur. The maturity model adds a separate section for operation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specifications tolerate manual log analysis, ad hoc responses to incidents, and best efforts to detect attacks at a low maturity level. Improved maturity requires a dedicated incident response team and defined processes for the detection and remediation of incidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Patch management and configuration hardening have clear recommendations for regular and systematic activities across the entire technology stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highest score points in SAMM require the rapid decommissioning of outdated applications or strategies to monitor such systems until they are replaced with modern successors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OWASP SAMM provides a reliable framework for improving the software development process. Teams should start with an initial maturity assessment to get the status quo. From there, a roadmap can be created that defines the target picture and milestones along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/owasp-samm/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/owasp-samm/</guid>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup April 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month&quot;&gt;Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;spring4shell-the-internet-security-disaster-that-wasnt&quot;&gt;Spring4Shell: The Internet security disaster that wasn’t&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People were naturally concerned when a researcher published a proof-of-concept exploit that could remotely exploit the popular Spring framework. Without much information available and no CVE assigned, people were unable to determine their exposure. Some security companies jumped on the hype train and warned of imminent danger that “could ruin the internet” to sell their snake oil. A great write-up on the worst side of the security industry, selling services through fear, comes from Arstechnica. &lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/04/explaining-spring4shell-the-internet-security-disaster-that-wasnt/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ka-sat-network-cyber-attack-overview&quot;&gt;KA-SAT Network cyber-attack overview&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In our &lt;a href=&quot;/2022/roundup-032022/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;March Roundup&lt;/a&gt; we had an article about thousands of KA-SAT terminals that stopped working for an unknown reason. The provider ViaSat has now released an incident report on the cyber-attack against the network. Spoiler alert, the misconfiguration in a VPN appliance was used to gain the initial foothold into the system. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.viasat.com/about/newsroom/blog/ka-sat-network-cyber-attack-overview/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;graph-based-firewall-analysis&quot;&gt;Graph-based firewall analysis&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is good practice to review firewall rules after changes to identify potential attack paths that have been missed. The use of a graph-based approach can help tremendously to visualize the rules and find gaps in the configuration. &lt;a href=&quot;https://diablohorn.com/2022/04/09/firewall-analysis-a-portable-graph-based-approach/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://diablohorn.files.wordpress.com/2022/04/yed-layout-radial.png?w=628&quot; alt=&quot;Firewall analysis with graphs&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Display of data using yEd&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;distributed-tcpdump-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt;Distributed tcpdump for Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The toolbox of any security professional includes capturing network traffic with tcpdump or Wireshark. Gathering the network traffic of distriubuted workloads in cloud environments has been a challenge for forensic analysis. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/deepfence/PacketStreamer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PacketStreamer (GitHub)&lt;/a&gt; utilizes sensors to collect network packets on remote hosts and enables the collection of traffic activities on a large number of target systems. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/deepfence-cloud-native-security/introducing-packetstreamer-distributed-packet-capture-for-cloud-native-platforms-3e7f9ac57ab1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;authorization-in-a-microservices-world&quot;&gt;Authorization in a microservices world&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alolis&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Alexander Lolis&lt;/a&gt; wrote a great blog post about different authorization approaches and what a flexible mechanism could look like. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.alexanderlolis.com/authorization-in-a-microservices-world#authorization-flow-overview&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.alexanderlolis.com/assets/images/authorization_architecture_overview-a7f2e4f08870034de08c831e81aae323.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Authorization mechanism&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Authorization mechanism&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aws-patch-against-log4j-introduces-new-security-holes&quot;&gt;AWS patch against Log4j introduces new security holes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are still seeing the fallout from the worst Christmas present in years, Log4Shell. A hot patch system introduced to address Log4Shell has been exploited to escape containers and take over the underlying host in AWS. Unit 42 (Paloalto networks) researchers identified the severe security issues within the AWS patching solution. &lt;a href=&quot;https://unit42.paloaltonetworks.com/aws-log4shell-hot-patch-vulnerabilities/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction-to-csrf-how-can-a-cookie-get-you-hacked&quot;&gt;Introduction to CSRF: How can a cookie get you hacked?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cookies serve three purposes: session management, personalization, and tracking. They are assistants to webservers that work in conjunction with the browser to make your life easier. If, however, the web application relies only on cookies to manage sessions, the attacker can perform the infamous CSRF attack. Check out the following article for an introduction to CSRF attacks &lt;a href=&quot;https://systemweakness.com/introduction-to-csrf-how-can-a-cookie-get-you-hacked-1-2-d34e0a0e6319&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-042022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-042022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setting Up the Ledger Nano S Wallet</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;key-management-is-the-most-important-aspect-of-your-crypto-journey-whoever-controls-your-keys-controls-the-assets-there-are-a-variety-of-options-for-key-management-including-online-services-smartphone-apps-or-hardware-devices&quot;&gt;Key management is the most important aspect of your crypto journey. Whoever controls your keys controls the assets. There are a variety of options for key management, including online services, smartphone apps or hardware devices.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-of-these-options-has-its-pros-and-cons-some-are-complicated-to-setup-while-others-leave-your-private-keys-in-the-hands-of-a-service-provider&quot;&gt;Each of these options has its pros and cons. Some are complicated to setup, while others leave your private keys in the hands of a service provider.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recommend a hardware wallet to access the full potential of crypto assets and limiting the exposure of your private keys to others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tutorial explains how to set up the hardware wallet &lt;a href=&quot;https://shop.ledger.com/products/ledger-nano-s&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ledger Nano S&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt; running &lt;a href=&quot;https://ubuntu.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/NanoS_PROD_CAM06.png&quot; height=&quot;500&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Nano S&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ledger Nano S&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;buy-the-hardware-wallet&quot;&gt;Buy The Hardware Wallet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ledger Nano S (or any other hardware wallet) should not be purchased from Amazon, eBay, or other online sellers. There is a risk of receiving a tampered or used device that may result in the loss of your crypto assets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better purchase a legitimate, unopened, and brand new device from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/&quot;&gt;Official Ledger Website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ledger-nano-s---initial-setup&quot;&gt;Ledger Nano S - Initial SetUp&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the included USB cable, connect the Ledger device to your computer and watch it come to life. Navigate with the two buttons on the top of the device and follow the on-screen instructions. Press both buttons simultaneously to accept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing your device’s PIN code is the first step in the setup process. We recommend to use a 6-digit code. The next step is the documentation of the recovery phrase. The 24 random words will appear one by one on the device’s screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is the only backup of the private keys and the words will only be displayed once&lt;/strong&gt;. Write them down on the provided paper recovery sheet or use an even more secure &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.de/-/en/Bitcoin-Cryptocurrency-Hardware-Storage-Compatible/dp/B097CZY65D/ref=pd_lpo_1?pd_rd_i=B097CZY65D&amp;amp;psc=1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;steel recovery sheet&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;virtualbox-and-guest-system-installation&quot;&gt;VirtualBox And Guest System Installation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The virtualization software VirtualBox is open source and can be downloaded &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. We also require the ISO image for &lt;a href=&quot;http://releases.ubuntu.com/20.04/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ubuntu 20.04&lt;/a&gt;. The “Desktop image” is sufficient for our purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Ubuntu20.04.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Nano S&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ubuntu 20.04 in VirtualBox&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A thorough step-by-step guide for the installation of virtual machines on VirtualBox can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://linuxhint.com/install_ubuntu_virtualbox_2004/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;linuxhint blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;setup-the-udev-devices-on-host-and-guest&quot;&gt;Setup the udev devices on host and guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we need to setup the Linux sub-sytem for dynamic device detection and management aka udev. It creates or removes device nodes dynamically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following command will execute the configuration of Ledger devices and has to be executed on both, the host &lt;strong&gt;and&lt;/strong&gt; the guest system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;wget -q -O - https://raw.githubusercontent.com/LedgerHQ/udev-rules/master/add_udev_rules.sh | sudo bash&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the installation of the rules, you must either restart the computer or reload the udev ruleset with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sudo udevadm control --reload-rules &amp;amp;&amp;amp; udevadm trigger&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now connect the Ledger device to the host computer and execute the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command. The device should show up in the list of devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/lsusb.png&quot; alt=&quot;lsusb&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Output of the lsusb command&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take note of the device ID &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;VendorID&amp;gt;:&amp;lt;ProductID&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;configure-the-usb-device-in-the-virtualbox-guest&quot;&gt;Configure the USB device in the VirtualBox guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the USB device is available on the host system, we need to map it to the guest system.
In VirtualBox go to Machine &amp;gt; Settings &amp;gt; USB and add an empty Filter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/VBoxUSBFilter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Create an empty USB Filter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Create an empty USB Filter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Update the entry with the exact data we received from the output of the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command. The &lt;strong&gt;Vendor ID is 2c97&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Product ID is 1011&lt;/strong&gt;. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://devicehunt.com/view/type/usb/vendor/2C97&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Vendor ID&lt;/a&gt; is a fixed value while the Product ID can vary. So make sure you use the correct one for your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/USBFilter.png&quot; alt=&quot;Configure the Filter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Configure the Filter&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are now ready to start the VirtualBox Guest system and check for the availability of the USB device with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; command.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;install-the-ledger-live-software-on-the-guest&quot;&gt;Install the Ledger Live Software on the guest&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the device available on the guest system we can now install the ledger-live software. Download the image from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ledger.com/ledger-live/download&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;official website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make the file executable by issuing the following command in the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;chmod +x ledger-live-*.AppImage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Launch the application with the following command from the terminal:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;./ledger-live-desktop-*.AppImage&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The software will detect your USB hardware wallet and you can now install the desired accounts for the cryptocurrencies you’d like to secure with the wallet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p align=&quot;center&quot;&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/LedgerinVBox.png&quot; alt=&quot;Ledger Software in a VirtualBox&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Ledger Software in a VirtualBox&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations, you are now ready to receive and send crypto assets with your hardware wallet. Please make sure you always confirm the wallet address displayed on your device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No USB Device found in the VirtualBox Software&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.virtualbox.org/wiki/Downloads&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;VirtualBox Extension Pack&lt;/a&gt; installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wallet not detected by Ledger Software when installing Accounts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happened to me when I added the Ethereum account on the wallet. The Bitcoin account worked  without an issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It turns out that the Ledger S changes the Device ID for some accounts. I noticed this by monitoring the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;lsusb&lt;/code&gt; output on the host system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just add a second Filter in VirtualBox for the other Device ID. My wallet has &lt;strong&gt;Device ID 1011 for Bitcoin and 1015 for Ethereum&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;recap&quot;&gt;Recap&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digital crypto assets enable us to have independent ownership without the involvement of any third party. Having assets sitting in an exchange broker or with a wallet service provider puts us at the mercy of said companies’ resilience to outside interference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owning the private key is vital to unleashing the full potential of self-custody. By using a hardware wallet we exercise self-custody. We are responsible for the safety of our keys and in exchange for this effort, we prevent any state, bank, or hacker to take our assets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/ledger-hardware-wallet/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/ledger-hardware-wallet/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup March 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;github-shares-vulnerability-database-with-community&quot;&gt;GitHub shares vulnerability database with community&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GitHub Advisory Database is the world’s largest database for recording security vulnerabilities in open-source software. A team maintains this data full-time. The database is used, among other things, for security checks of the package managers npm and NuGet as well as for GitHub’s Dependabot warnings. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.blog/2022-02-22-github-advisory-database-now-open-to-community-contributions/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;satcom-terminals-under-attack&quot;&gt;SATCOM terminals under attack&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parallel to the Russian invasion of Ukraine, thousands of KA-SAT terminals stopped working in several European countries. Remotely operated wind turbines, connected via SATCOM link, lost contact with their servers as a result. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/rubensantamarta/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Ruben Santamarta&lt;/a&gt; analyses the publicly available information in his interesting article. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reversemode.com/2022/03/satcom-terminals-under-attack-in-europe.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2e/IP-SATCOM.svg/1920px-IP-SATCOM.svg.png&quot; alt=&quot;SATCOM&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;critical-vulnerabilities-in-apc-uninterruptible-power-supply&quot;&gt;Critical vulnerabilities in APC Uninterruptible Power Supply&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armis has discovered three critical vulnerabilities in APC Smart-UPS devices. These are of course controlled through an internet connection nowadays. A malicious actor can use TLS bypass and TLS overflow to gain unauthenticated access to the UPS and use the device for further lateral movement in the network.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.armis.com/research/tlstorm/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;pro-tips-for-burpsuite&quot;&gt;Pro-tips for BurpSuite&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Burp Suite is a network analysis toolbox for testing web applications. It includes a proxy, which intercepts HTTP/HTTPS traffic and modifies the HTTP headers before sending the data to the server. The article by N00PY gives great tips for the powerful software. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.n00py.io/2017/10/how-to-burp-good/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;famous-npm-package-deletes-files-to-protest-ukraine-war&quot;&gt;Famous npm package deletes files to protest Ukraine war&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The importance of supply chain security for open source components in business code has been highlighted once again this month. The developer of the npm module node-ipc.js added malicious code to it that deletes files if the software thinks it is on a Russian or Belarusian system based on a geo-location IP determination. The incident has drawn sharp criticism from the open-source community for actively deploying destructive payloads in a popular library without any warning to honest users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/security/big-sabotage-famous-npm-package-deletes-files-to-protest-ukraine-war/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nsa-hardening-guide-for-kubernetes&quot;&gt;NSA hardening guide for Kubernetes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest sources of compromise in Kubernetes are supply chain risks, malicious
threat actors, and insider threats. The NSA guide describes the security challenges associated with setting up and securing a Kubernetes cluster and provides strategies to avoid common misconfiguration and implement hardening measures. &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.defense.gov/2021/Aug/03/2002820425/-1/-1/0/CTR_Kubernetes_Hardening_Guidance_1.1_20220315.PDF&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;escaping-privileged-containers-for-fun&quot;&gt;Escaping privileged containers for fun&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/pwningsystems&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Jordy&lt;/a&gt; writes on his blog about discovering an escape from a privileged container via the kernel’s coredump handling code. Interesting read and let’s all agree to not run privileged containers, not even for fun! &lt;a href=&quot;https://pwning.systems/posts/escaping-containers-for-fun/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-032022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-032022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        <category>security</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Raspberry PI - 10 Years of hacking</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-raspberry-pi-is-one-of-those-things-that-has-become-so-commonplace-that-you-wonder-how-we-ever-got-along-without-it-before-whenever-a-cheap-small-and-low-power-consuming-computer-is-required-the-pi-is-ready&quot;&gt;The Raspberry Pi is one of those things that has become so commonplace that you wonder how we ever got along without it before. Whenever a cheap, small, and low-power-consuming computer is required, the Pi is ready.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;originally-the-device-was-intended-for-classrooms-since-the-number-of-computer-science-students-in-the-uk-dropped-in-the-2000s-and-british-schoolchildren-were-to-be-inspired-by-the-single-board-computer&quot;&gt;Originally the device was intended for classrooms since the number of computer science students in the UK dropped in the 2000s, and British schoolchildren were to be inspired by the single-board computer.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Raspberry_Pi_4_Model_B_-_Side.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-low-price-and-accessible-os-a-full-fledged-linux-runs-on-the-minicomputer-made-it-attractive-to-hackers-and-tinkerers-worldwide&quot;&gt;The low price and accessible OS, a full-fledged Linux runs on the minicomputer, made it attractive to hackers and tinkerers worldwide.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first model had a CPU with only one core clocked at 700 MHz and 256 MB of RAM, which was completely undersized for a PC or even smartphone of the time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten years and 40 million units sold later, a rich ecosystem has formed around all iterations of the little computer. There is also an active community that has developed open-source software for many applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-and-projects&quot;&gt;Applications And Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is hardly anything that can’t be monitored or controlled with the Raspberry Pi. Home automation is a big field of application: From &lt;a href=&quot;https://iotdesignpro.com/projects/iot-based-solenoid-door-lock-using-raspberry-pi-4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;door locks&lt;/a&gt; over &lt;a href=&quot;https://projects-raspberry.com/home-alarm-system-with-raspberry-pi/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;alarm systems&lt;/a&gt; to &lt;a href=&quot;https://hackaday.com/2020/07/24/a-complete-raspberry-pi-power-monitoring-system/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;solar panels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.magicmirrorcentral.com/complete-raspberry-pi-magic-mirror-tutorial/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;smart mirrors&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://dordnung.de/raspberrypi-ledstrip/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;lighting&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi is also widely used for home entertainment. The microcomputer reliably provides &lt;a href=&quot;https://darko.audio/2020/01/raspberry-pi-audio-streaming-101/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;audio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://pimylifeup.com/raspberry-pi-plex-server/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;video streams&lt;/a&gt; to various devices in a home network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, one of the most frequently used applications is &lt;a href=&quot;https://pi-hole.net/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Pi-Hole&lt;/a&gt;, a network-wide adblocker that uses a DNS filtering to block online advertising for all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mission-accomplished&quot;&gt;Mission Accomplished?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eben_Upton&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Eden Upton&lt;/a&gt; and his team had set out to create a classroom computer that is both inexpensive and very low-threshold to program and use. Even though it is used for teaching purposes in schools and universities, it is mainly utilized by tech-savvy people to automate their homes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As trivial as it may seem to technical users writing a Linux image to an SD card to boot the Raspberry Pi, this hurdle is too high for many people who are otherwise only used to their smartphone. Ultimately, Pi has not quite become what it was supposed to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;against-consumerism&quot;&gt;Against Consumerism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not all is lost as the Pi plays an important role in shaping our consumer culture. The industry has been designing smartphones and tablets so that they can largely only be operated in a consuming manner. Writing code yourself, intervening in the system, exchanging hardware components - has all become increasingly difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, devices and apps are collecting more data than ever and sending them to manufacturers, for mostly no consumer benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Raspberry Pi has formed a countermovement to this development. The operating system and most major software projects are open-source. Not only is it possible to add or swap hardware components but the system has to be assembled in the first place. The device triggers the creativity of users and motivates them to experiment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;outlook&quot;&gt;Outlook&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pi hit a nerve with its features: sufficiently powerful, many connectors, cheap - but not too complicated, especially thanks to good Linux support and an active community. It has spawned a whole ecosystem and we hope the little microcomputer will continue to push the boundaries and provide users with an opportunity to tinker with technology.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/raspberry-pi-anniversary/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/raspberry-pi-anniversary/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup February 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;cybersecurity-has-always-been-about-recognizing-and-responding-to-new-developments-each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Cybersecurity has always been about recognizing and responding to new developments. Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;stop-storing-secrets-in-environment-variables&quot;&gt;Stop Storing Secrets In Environment Variables!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt Hamilton argues that an application is the most trustworthy at initialization before the execution of business logic. He suggests utilizing ephemeral filesystems to provide secrets to an application. A very interesting article that got a lot of attention. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.forcesunseen.com/stop-storing-secrets-in-environment-variables&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-beautiful-complexity-of-the-sha256-algorithm&quot;&gt;The beautiful complexity of the SHA256 Algorithm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/manceraio&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Domingo Martin&lt;/a&gt; presents on his website the inner workings of the SHA256 hashing algorithm. Knowing the theory is one thing but having such an engaging graphical representation is quite a treat!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://sha256algorithm.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;how-i-hacked-a-hardware-crypto-wallet-and-recovered-2-million&quot;&gt;How I hacked a hardware crypto wallet and recovered $2 million&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A very entertaining video reached us from &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/joegrand&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Joe Grand&lt;/a&gt; aka Kingpin. The video is running us through the hack of a Trezor One hardware wallet to recover $2 million in cryptocurrency (THETA). Joe uses a technique called fault-injection - also known as glitching — to undermine the security protection of the wallet. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dT9y-KQbqi4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;watch&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theverge.com/2022/1/24/22898712/crypto-hardware-wallet-hacking-lost-bitcoin-ethereum-nft&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cdn.vox-cdn.com/thumbor/vQqFr3C363AsxquC-9oLwOdpNDU=/0x0:3360x1632/1920x0/filters:focal(0x0:3360x1632):format(webp):no_upscale()/cdn.vox-cdn.com/uploads/chorus_asset/file/23191888/Screen_Shot_2022_01_24_at_2.53.21_PM.png&quot; alt=&quot;hack&quot; class=&quot;center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;father-accidentally-knocks-out-mobile-network&quot;&gt;Father accidentally knocks out mobile network&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Between midnight and 3 AM every day of the week, the mobile network in the French municipality of Messanges did not work. Turns out a father wanted to prevent his children from surfing the Internet with a jammer - and as a side effect shut down the mobile network of a municipality in France. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bleepingcomputer.com/news/technology/dad-takes-down-towns-internet-by-mistake-to-get-his-kids-offline/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;open-source-tool-unredacter-makes-pixelated-text-readable-again&quot;&gt;Open-source tool Unredacter makes pixelated text readable again&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixelation is not a secure way to make text passages unreadable. The software “Unredacter”, developed by Dan Petro, a senior researcher at security provider Bishop Fox, takes redacted pixelized text and reverses it back into its readable form. We recommend a black bar to securely redact text. &lt;a href=&quot;https://bishopfox.com/blog/unredacter-tool-never-pixelation&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;little-improvements-in-vulnerability-management&quot;&gt;Little improvements in vulnerability management&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most organizations appear to be making little progress in addressing application security issues despite all of the heightened concerns around the topic. A study, by researchers at NTT Application Security, shows that organizations left more than half (53%) of known critical flaws nonremediated. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/key-application-security-metrics-show-little-sign-of-improvement&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;advisory-western-digital-my-cloud-pro-series&quot;&gt;Advisory: Western Digital My Cloud Pro Series&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wonderful world of IOT provides us with a dead simple command injection and execution for the WD PR4100. Turns out the device sends a HTTP (not HTTPS) based healthcheck to the WD remote cloud service every 300 seconds. This can be hijacked and untrusted data can be injected. The lack of input validation leads to the execution of said untrusted data.&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.iot-inspector.com/blog/advisory-western-digital-my-cloud-pro-series-pr4100-rce/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-022022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-022022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cloud &amp; Schrems II: What now?</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;cloud-computing-has-been-one-of-the-most-disruptive-technologies-in-the-last-decade-unprecedented-flexibility-scalability-and-cost-effectiveness-seduced-organizations-to-equate-digital-transformation-with-cloud-migration&quot;&gt;Cloud computing has been one of the most disruptive technologies in the last decade. Unprecedented flexibility, scalability, and cost-effectiveness seduced organizations to equate digital transformation with cloud migration.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;but-in-2020-the-bright-future-of-cloud-computing-darkened-when-the-eu-court-of-justice-cjeu-invalidated-the-transfer-deal-privacy-shield-the-legal-foundation-on-which-eu-companies-outsourced-to-us-cloud-providers&quot;&gt;But in 2020, the bright future of cloud computing darkened when the EU Court of Justice (CJEU) invalidated the transfer deal “Privacy Shield”, the legal foundation on which EU companies outsourced to US cloud providers.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/schrems2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-so-called-schrems-ii-ruling-leaves-many-companies-in-an-awkward-situation-us-cloud-providers-are-mostly-no-help-and-retreat-to-mere-lip-services&quot;&gt;This so-called Schrems II ruling leaves many companies in an awkward situation. US cloud providers are mostly no help and retreat to mere lip services.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No false conclusions should be drawn from the supposed inaction of the data protection authorities. In the case of the USA in particular, the CJEU’s ruling has given the supervisory authorities clear guidelines that leave little room for discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this article, we describe technical measures that organizations can take to continue the use of US cloud providers post-Schrems II.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tldr-schrems-ii--us-cloud-act&quot;&gt;TL;DR Schrems II &amp;amp; US Cloud Act&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Large US companies, such as Microsoft, Amazon, or Google, advertise that they have an EU subsidiary with server locations in Europe, which means that no transfer to the USA would take place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the Schrems II ruling states that a server located in the EU does not protect against US laws: The &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CLOUD_Act&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;CLOUD Act&lt;/a&gt; authorizes US authorities to access data stored by US service providers and their subsidiaries outside the USA - even if this represents a conflict with local national law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The CJEU notes that data protection standards, in general, cannot be guaranteed when outsourcing to US providers. US law is incompatible with the requirements of EU consumer rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under the GDPR, EU businesses have to prevent unauthorized access to personal data. What’s new about Schrems II, however, is that this time we do not have to fear hackers or human error, but American law enforcement. The cloud environment has become hostile territory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s look at some technical safeguards for the post Schrems II era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;assessment-and-classification&quot;&gt;Assessment And Classification&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first task, in any case, is an honest evaluation of the situation to plan for supplementary measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What cloud providers are used?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What processes are outsourced to the provider?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Which laws apply to the service provider?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is the privacy and security policy appropriate?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What type of data is transferred?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do we need a data processing agreement?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations are well-advised to maintain a detailed list of suppliers and sub-suppliers. The full outsourcing chain has to be considered. For example, an EU-based HR software provider can potentially run on a US infrastructure service (IaaS).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;anonymization&quot;&gt;Anonymization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Completely anonymized data is not protected by the GDPR and can consequently be transferred to US cloud providers. The challenge is to preserve the usability of such anonymized data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;OpenSource tools such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://arx.deidentifier.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ARX&lt;/a&gt; are very helpful in building proper documentation and help businesses to strike the right balance between anonymization and data usability. Proof for the anonymization must be defendable against objections from data authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;smart-clients&quot;&gt;Smart Clients&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have written a whole article on this topic here: &lt;a href=&quot;/2020/privacy-client-shift/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Shift To The Client&lt;/a&gt;. Smart Client architecture emphasizes the client over the backend when it comes to the processing and storage of personal data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This approach has, for example, been chosen for the official German &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Corona-Warn-App&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;COVID-19 contact tracing app&lt;/a&gt;. The app is not supported by a centralized storage system and anonymized data is only shared when a warning to other users is initiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decentralized architecture and smart clients are a much too rarely considered possibility when planning for a business case. With Schrems II, however, the traditional client-server architecture will be a challenge in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;provider-independent-encryption&quot;&gt;Provider Independent Encryption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cloud providers make key management easy to use with integrated services. But this doesn’t address the underlying issue of Schrems II since the key ownership stays with the cloud provider and therefore enables the provider to decrypt any sensitive data in transit or storage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provider independent encryption (or key management) on the other hand is a suitable approach to prevent unauthorized access. Organizations with such a system can effectively block cloud providers from reading sensitive data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A great solution for cloud storage solutions like Google Drive or Dropbox is the usage of key management services like &lt;a href=&quot;https://cryptomator.org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Cryptomator&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.boxcryptor.com/en/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Boxcryptor&lt;/a&gt;. These tools hide the content of files from the storage provider by implementing full end-to-end encryption (e2ee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cryptomator.org/img/home/split-screenshots.png&quot; alt=&quot;workplace&quot; style=&quot;left; margin: 5px 0px 5px 0px;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have highlighted some technical ideas that can serve as a starting point for a cloud outsourcing approach in line with the GDPR. However, the most important question is if every single outsourcing project needs to be done with a US provider or whether there is not a suitable EU solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choose your battles carefully. The days of pragmatically transferring data to vendors and configuring something that somehow worked are over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of outsourcing to the cloud lies in the deliberate planning of processing activities and supplementary measures to secure a run-of-the-mill cloud service.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-post-schrems2/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/cloud-post-schrems2/</guid>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup January 2022</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;each-month-we-gather-our-favorite-finds-from-around-the-internet-and-we-recommend-them-to-you-right-here-so-go-ahead-pour-yourself-a-cup-of-coffee-or-tea-and-settle-in&quot;&gt;Each month we gather our favorite finds from around the internet and we recommend them to you right here. So go ahead, pour yourself a cup of coffee, or tea, and settle in.&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;log4j-newest-vulnerability-in-log4j-2170-more-hype-than-substance&quot;&gt;Log4j: Newest Vulnerability in Log4j 2.17.0 more hype than substance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/breadchris&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Chris Thompson&lt;/a&gt; has an insightful article about the current hype on log4j. With as much attention as there is now on the Log4j project, it can be difficult to truly understand the impact of the recently disclosed vulnerabilities when they are being compared against the original Log4Shell vulnerability, a perfect 10/10 severity. The latest vulnerabilities found in log4j 2.17.0 are much less serious. 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lunasec.io/docs/blog/log4j-hype-train/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;vulcano-breaks-communication-with-the-archipelago-tonga&quot;&gt;Vulcano breaks communication with the archipelago Tonga&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The massive eruption of the Hunga Tonga-Hunga Haʻapai volcano in Tonga in the Pacific damaged several submarine cables. This is reported by New Zealand media referencing to various operators of submarine cables in the South Pacific. It is feared that the island state of Tonga will remain largely cut off from the Internet for at least several weeks.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stuff.co.nz/world/south-pacific/127517682/cable-repair-ship-to-set-sail-from-png-to-restore-communications-to-tonga&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;never-before-seen-cross-platform-rat-discovered&quot;&gt;Never-before-seen cross-platform RAT discovered&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers have uncovered a remote access trojan (RAT) written from scratch for systems running Windows, macOS, or Linux that remained undetected by virtually all malware scanning engines. The discovery is significant for several reasons and is described in detail in the following article.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2022/01/backdoor-for-windows-macos-and-linux-went-undetected-until-now/1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;10-real-world-stories-of-compromised-cicd-pipelines&quot;&gt;10 real-world stories of compromised CI/CD pipelines&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build pipelines are highly-privileged targets with a substantial attack surface. Not only does this article by nccgroup detail the exploits and deficiencies, but lays out clear actionable steps to remedy them. &lt;a href=&quot;https://research.nccgroup.com/2022/01/13/10-real-world-stories-of-how-weve-compromised-ci-cd-pipelines/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;patchmanagement---a-comprehensive-series&quot;&gt;Patchmanagement - a comprehensive series&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unpatched known vulnerabilities remain one of the most common attack vectors in today’s cyberattacks. The insightful series of articles on darkreading covers the evolution of patchmanagement, the risk-based approach we are all used to today, and an outlook to the future development of keeping systems updated. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/the-evolution-of-patch-management-how-and-when-it-got-so-complicated&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;threat-intelligence---free-and-open-source&quot;&gt;Threat intelligence - free and open-source&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matthew Sullivan has created a community-driven alerting system for high-impact vulnerabilities. We think this is an amazing alternative to commercial threat intelligence systems and worth supporting. &lt;a href=&quot;https://mattslifebytes.com/2022/01/04/bugalert-org/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-purchased-a-machine-from-china-and-it-came-with-malware-preinstalled&quot;&gt;We purchased a machine from China and it came with malware preinstalled&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We want to end this roundup with a hilarious and informative story from the folks at rmcybernetics. They ordered a small Pick and Place machine from AliExpress and found malware preinstalled. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rmcybernetics.com/general/zhengbang-zb3245tss-pick-place-machine&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-012022/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2022/roundup-012022/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roundup December 2021</title>
        <description>&lt;h5 id=&quot;another-year-is-coming-to-an-end-and-we-start-a-new-format-here-on-inversegravity-kick-back-with-us-and-dig-into-a-selection-of-the-best-articles-code-and-projects-we-found-this-past-month-we-wish-you-all-the-best-for-2022&quot;&gt;Another year is coming to an end and we start a new format here on inversegravity. Kick back with us and dig into a selection of the best articles, code, and projects we found this past month. We wish you all the best for 2022!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;a-cisos-practical-advice-on-log4j&quot;&gt;A CISO’s Practical Advice on log4j&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/lamont-orange-99540a/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Lamont Orange&lt;/a&gt; gives some great advice on darkreading.com. He writes: “it’s easy to get weighed down in hype, marketing, and speculation and forget that there are important things we need to do, right now, to improve our posture, strengthen our team, and put us in a better position for the next Log4j.” Well-spoken, sir!
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/log4j-a-ciso-s-practical-advice&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ms-teams-1-feature-4-vulnerabilities&quot;&gt;MS Teams: 1 feature, 4 vulnerabilities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fabian Bräunlein and his team from &lt;a href=&quot;https://positive.security/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Positive Security&lt;/a&gt; stumbled upon 4 vulnerabilities in Microsoft Team’s link preview feature. The vulnerabilities allow accessing internal Microsoft services, spoofing the link preview, and, for Android users, leaking their IP address and running a DoS attack.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://positive.security/blog/ms-teams-1-feature-4-vulns&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cloud-security-breaches-and-vulnerabilities-2021-in-review&quot;&gt;Cloud Security Breaches and Vulnerabilities: 2021 in Review&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Christophe Tafani-Dereeper has written a great summary of common cloud security incidents. We especially appreciate his insight into the prevention and detection of these common misconfigurations.
&lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.christophetd.fr/cloud-security-breaches-and-vulnerabilities-2021-in-review/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;ccc-rc3-nowhere-2021&quot;&gt;CCC rc3 Nowhere 2021&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chaos Communication Congress is the largest gathering of the hacker community in Europe. For the second time, the annual event was replaced by a virtual one due to COVID-19 restrictions. You can find the videos of the 2021 talks &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3-2021&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. All the German language presentations are translated and some are held in English. We hope for the CCC folks (and us) that everything will be back to normal in 2022. &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.ccc.de/c/rc3-2021&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;streaming link&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;fun-with-speckle-patterns-and-lasers&quot;&gt;Fun with speckle patterns (and lasers)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anfractuosity has an exciting project with lasers, a calculator, and a vice. He writes “The approach takes advantage of the fact that tiny surface deformations cause phase changes in reflected coherent light which alter the speckle pattern visible under laser illumination.” &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.anfractuosity.com/projects/fun-with-speckle-patterns/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;that-toy-you-got-for-christmas-could-be-spying-on-you&quot;&gt;That Toy You Got for Christmas Could Be Spying on You&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Montalbano has written an interesting article about security flaws in the recently released Fisher-Price Chatter Bluetooth telephone. Keeping those kids protected! &lt;a href=&quot;https://threatpost.com/toy-christmas-spying/177288/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;make-your-pc-notify-your-phone-whenever-there-is-movement-around-it&quot;&gt;Make Your PC Notify Your Phone Whenever There is Movement Around it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another great holiday project comes from c0d3x27. In the article, he/she describes how to use the camera of a computer with OpenCV to capture images and detect motion. &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.devgenius.io/make-your-pc-notify-your-phone-whenever-there-is-movement-around-it-c6c4ccd734b7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;read&amp;lt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://inversegravity.net/2021/roundup-122021/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://inversegravity.net/2021/roundup-122021/</guid>
        
        <category>roundup</category>
        
        <category>technology</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
