<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>personal blog</description>
    <link>https://damaex17.github.io/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://damaex17.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 13:54:27 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 13:54:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rolex Explorer Ref. 114270</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-stealth-rolex&quot;&gt;the stealth rolex&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally created to honor the exploits of Mt. Everest conquerors Tenzing Norgay – who wore his Rolex to the summit – and Sir Edmund Hillary, the 1953 Rolex Explorer was the first of a long line of Rolex utility watches designed to go into harm’s way.
Rolex’s Explorer grew out of the original 1930s-50s Oyster Perpetual “bubblebacks,” the first water-resistant and self-winding wristwatches to achieve technical and commercial success. Norgay and Hillary immortalized the “Explorer” name, and Rolex’s modus operandi of incremental refinement led to the Explorer 114270 of 2002-2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/IMG_0603.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the general public may not grasp the depth of Rolex’s hardcore heritage, even the proverbial “man on the street” understands that the brand stands with Rolls-Royce as a synonym for quality. And in this Explorer, Rolex delivers. The Geneva watchmaker ranks among the exclusive club of true manufactures that fabricate virtually every part of their watches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 36mm stainless steel case itself is a testament to Rolex’s eye for detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The difference starts with the steel itself; Rolex makes its own at the company’s in-house foundry. But the stainless employed on the Explorer is of the 904L variety, not the 316L employed by the majority of Swiss watchmakers. 904L is more expensive to produce, harder to work, and requires a greater up-front investment, but the payoff continues for the watch’s lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2019/rolex-explorer-114270/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Download or Use This Theme</title>
        <description>&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-this-theme-as-you-main-site&quot;&gt;Use this theme as you main site&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download or fork the master branch of this theme repo into your GitHub account.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rename the repo into something like &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;your_username.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file to your preferences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Edit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;about.md&lt;/code&gt; file for your About page.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inside &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; folder, there are sample of blog entries. Learn from it and start yours.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now, visit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;http://your_username.github.io&lt;/code&gt; and you should see your blog running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;use-this-theme-as-a-project-page&quot;&gt;Use this theme as a project page&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to use this theme as a project page blog, you don’t need to rename the theme repo into &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;your_username.github.io&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All you need to do, open &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; file, change &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baseurl&lt;/code&gt; to your project name which contains this theme, e.g. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;baseurl: &quot;/myproject&quot;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;cheers&quot;&gt;Cheers!&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2016/how-to-download-or-use-this-theme/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2016/how-to-download-or-use-this-theme/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>If you have a Guest post..</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you think that you’re going to have a guest post… take a look on this post sample. Just add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;author: GuestName&lt;/code&gt; to the YAML front matter. Then, the &lt;strong&gt;GuestName&lt;/strong&gt; will be appear on the next of post date. Oh, the guest name will be automatically uppercase.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://damaex17.github.io/2016/if-you-have-a-guest-post/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://damaex17.github.io/2016/if-you-have-a-guest-post/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
